<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name311">
        <b>3101    BUSINESS AND SOCIETY</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>1. The interface of Business and Society : </b> \n
        Business is a Social world, argument for and against social responsibility for business, social power and social 
        responsibility, A pluralistic Society, business role and social issues, managerial role and social issues, technology 
        and social changes.
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. Business Ideology : </b> \n
        The development of business as a social institution, Heritage of Business Ideology, Business values and codes for conduct. 
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Business and Its Public :</b> \n
        Business Interface with Government, Issues of Government Regulation and influence, Ownership Climes and business, 
        business employees and organized labor, the individual and business.
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. Business and Community : </b> \n
        Business involvement in community activities, business and the urban community, business, minorities and less advantaged 
        person, interface between business and higher education, business involvement with cultural affairs and 
        communication media, ecology and business responsibility, controlling pollutions.
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. Business in an International World :</b> \n
        Social response of multinational business, business encouragement on international development, looking towers the 
        future.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommend Books :</b>
        \n\n
        
        1. Keith davis and Robert L Blomstrom, Business and Society: Environment and Responsibility.
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name312">
        <b>3102    AUDITING </b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>1. Auditing and the Public Accounting Profession : </b> \n
        Definition of Audit, types of auditors, attest and non-attest services, AICPA, ICAB.
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. Financial Statements Audit and Auditor\'s Responsibilities: </b> \n
        Accounting and Auditing, need for financial statement audit, economics benefits of an audit, limitations of financial
         statement audit, independent auditors relationship – management, board, audit committee, internal auditor, and 
         shareholders- SAS, GAAS. Auditors report, auditors responsibility and expectation gap, narrowing the expectation gap, 
         errors and irregularities, reporting doubts as to an entity ability to continue as a going concern.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Professional Ethics: </b> \n
        General ethics, professional ethics, AICPA code of professional conduct, principals, rules - independence, integrity 
        and objectivity, confidential client information, contingent fees, Acts discreditable, advertising and other forms of 
        solicitation, commissions and referral fees.
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. Audit Objectives, Evidence and working Papers: </b> \n
         management financial statement association, specific audit objectives, audit evidence, audit procedures, 
         working papers.
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. Accepting the Engagement and Planning the audit: </b> \n
        overview of a financial statement audit, accepting the engagement, planning the audit. 
        \n\n
        
        <b>6. Materiality, Risk and Preliminary audit Strategies: </b> \n
        concepts of materiality , preliminary judgment, materiality at financial statement and account balance level, audit 
        risk components, relationship among the components, audit risk  at financial statement and account balance level, 
        interrelationship  among materiality , audit risk and audit evidence, audit risk alerts, preliminary audit strategies.
        \n\n
        
        <b>7. Understanding the Internal control Structure: </b> \n
        introduction to internal control, components of an internal control structure, obtaining understanding of components of 
        an internal control structure, documenting the understanding.
        \n\n
        
        <b>8. Assessing Control Risk and Test of Control: </b> \n
        assessing control risk, test of control, additional consideration.
        \n\n
        
        <b>9. Detection Risk and Design of Substantive Test : </b> \n
        determining detection risk , designing substantive tests, developing audit programs for substantiating tests, 
        special consideration in designing substantive tests.
        \n\n
        
        <b>10. Completing the Audit and Post Audit Responsibilities: </b> \n
        completing field work, evaluating the finding, communication with the client , post audit responsibility.
        \n\n
        
        <b>11. Reporting on Audited Financial Statement: </b> \n
        standards of reporting, auditors report, other reporting consideration.
        \n\n
        
        <b>12. Accounting Profession in Bangladesh:</b> \n
        Bangladesh Chartered accountants bye law 1973 – certification of practice – admissions – practice- fees – standing 
        committees – examination and training – cost audit in Bangladesh – institution of cost and management- Accountant of 
        Bangladesh – objective of cost audit – advantage and disadvantage of cost audit – commencement of cost audit – 
        programming of cost audit – cost audit report.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommend Books: </b>
        \n\n
        
        1. W C Boynton and W G Kell, Modern Auditing, John Wiley &amp; Sons Inc.
        \n\n
        
        2. B.N. Tandon, A Handbook of Practical Auditing, S. Chand &amp; Co.
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name313">
        <b>3103    TAXATION IN BANGLADESH</b>
        \n\n
        
        
        <b>1. Introduction: </b> \n
        meaning of income and characteristics of income – nature and importance of income tax – income tax ordinance 1984 – 
        statutory definitions and important concepts.
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. Income Tax Authority: </b> \n
        organization structure – administrative and judicial authorities – powers, functions , duties and responsibility of 
        administrative and judicial authorities – taxes appellate tribunal.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Charge of income Tax: </b> \n
        basic principals – exceptions – rate of tax – surcharge on net wealth – scope of total income – assessable and 
        non-assessable income – exemptions – residential status.
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. Computation of Total Income: </b> \n
        salaries – perquisites – provident and other funds – interest on securities – grossing up – income from house 
        property – agricultural income – income from business or profession – share of income from partnership firm – income 
        of spouse or minor child – capital gains – income from other source – unexplained investment as income – statutory 
        deductions from all heads of income – set-off and carry forward of losses.
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. Procedures of Assessment : </b> \n
        filing of return and other statements – types of statements – types of assessment – limitation for assessment – persons 
        liable to file a return.
        \n\n
        
        <b>6. Investment Tax Credit and Tax Rebate: </b> \n
        Investment Allowances – tax holiday for specific industries – tax rebate and exemptions in special cases.
        \n\n
        
        <b>7. Payments, Refund and Recovery: </b> \n
        Tax deductions at source – Advances tax – recovery of tax from assesse-in-default – tax refund.
        \n\n
        
        <b>8. Assessment of Individuals, Partnership and Public Limited Company. </b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>9. Value Addition Tax (VAT) : </b> \n
        Important terms, taxable goods and Services, VAT  authorities, Determination of VAT, method and time for VAT payments, 
        turnover tax and supplementary duty, registrations under VAT and VAT return.
        \n\n
        
        <b>10. Customer Act : </b> \n
        brief introduction to Customer act 1969, statutory definitions, customs procedure, customs authorities, prohibited 
        goods, goods dutiable , exemptions from customs duty , valuation procedure, date for determination of value and rate 
        of duty, determination of customs duty.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommend Books : </b>
        \n\n
        
        1. Income Tax Ordinance 1984 and Income Tax Rules 1984. \n\n
        
        2. Value Added Tax 1991 and Value Added Tax Rules 1991.
        \n\n
        
        3. Customer Act 1969.
        \n\n
        
        4. Finance Ordinance/Acts
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name314">
        <b>3104    INDUSTRIAL LAW</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>1. Factories Act : </b> \n
        Health – Welfare – hygiene – safety – working hours – employment of young persons – leave and holidays.
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. Employment of Labour (Standing order) Act 1965 : </b> \n
        Conditions of employment – classification of workers – leaves and holidays – stoppage of work – calculation for period 
        of continuous services – layoff – retrenchment, dismissal and punishment – termination and penalties – provident fund.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Industrial Relations Ordinance 1969 : </b> \n
        Trade unions and freedom of association, application for registrations, requirements for application, requirements for 
        registrations, appeal against cancellation, and cancellation of  registrations, appeal against cancellation, 
        incorporation of registered trade union , unfair labour practice on the part of employees and workman , collective 
        bargaining agent , CBA for institution with more than one establishment , negotiation relating to industrial disputes, 
        conciliator, arbitration, strikes and lock-out.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Payment of Wages Act 1936. </b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Workmen\'s Compensation Act 1923.</b>
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommend Books : </b>
        \n\n
        
        1. Sen, A.K., and Mitra, J.K., Commercial Law including Company Law and Industrial Law.
        \n\n
        
        2. Ahmed, Iqbal (Ed.), Basic Labour Laws of Bangladesh, 2nd Edition.
        \n\n
        
        3. Factories Act.
        \n\n
        
        4. Labor Ordinance. 
        \n\n
        
        5. A A Khan, Industrial Law.
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name315">
        <b>3105    BANGLADESH STUDIES </b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>1. Origin of the name “Bangladesh”, the people and language. </b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. Geographical features of Bangladesh. </b> 
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Roots of Bangladesh: </b> \n
        Political Development of Bangladesh , specially of the eastern Bangladesh during (a) Ancient Period, (b) Medieval 
        Period (1204-1765), (c) British Rule(1765-1947).
        \n\n
        
        <b>4.Emergence of Bangladesh : </b> \n
        cultural, politics and economic background – towards independence(1970-1971) – liberation war , role of India , China , 
        USA and USSR.
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. Constitution of Bangladesh and Major Amendments.</b> 
        \n\n
        
        <b>6. Politics and Government : </b> \n
        Party system of Bangladesh and its characteristics – the executive, the legislature and judiciary branch of the 
        government – local government and agencies.
        \n\n
                               
        <b>7. Foreign policy :</b> \n
        Goals , Objective, SAARC and Bangladesh.
        \n\n
        
        <b>8. Society and Social Structure : </b> \n
        culture and religion education.
        \n\n
        
        <b>9. Tribal people , insurgency in Chittagong Hill Treats, Peace Accord.(Dec 1997) </b>
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommend Books : </b>
        \n\n
        
        1. A F Salahuddin Ahmed and Bazlul Mobin Chowdhury (edited), Bangladesh : National Culture and Heritage , 
        Independent University Pablication.
        \n\n
        
        2. Haroun or Rashid, Geography of Bangladesh, UniversityPress Limited.1991.
        \n\n
        
        3. Talukdar Maniruzaman, Bangladesh Revolution and its Aftermath. 
        \n\n
        
        4. A M A Muhith, Bangladesh of a Nation.
        \n\n
        
        5. Syed Anwer Hussain, Bangladesh : National Scenario, Foreign Policy and SAARC.
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
    </string>
    
    
</resources>