<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name_acc421">
        <b>MAJOR - ACCOUNTING</b>
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>ACC-4201    ACCOUNTING THEORY</b> \n\n
        
        <b>1. Introduction:</b> \n
        Accounting and its Changing Role, Users of Accounting Information, Users Information Needs, Accounting Theory and. 
        its Needs, Research Methodology for the Formulation of Accounting Theory. Nature, Classification and Foundations of 
        Accounting Theory.
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. Approaches to the Formulations of Accounting Theory: </b> \n
        Traditional Approaches, New Approaches, Efficient Market Hypothesis, Capital Market Research and relevance of 
        Accounting Information.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. History of Accounting Thought: </b> \n
        Early History, Age of Stagnation, Growth of Accounting Knowledge, development of Accounting Practice and theory in 
        European countries, Basic Accounting Equation, Development of Accounting Practice and Theory in USA, Development of 
        Accounting Principles, Standards versus Principles, GAAP, Alternatives in Accounting Standards, Comparability of 
        Financial Statements, Structure for Establishment of Accounting Standards.
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. Structure of Accounting Theory: </b> \n
        Elements of the structure, Accounting Postulates, Theatrical Concepts of Accounting, Basic Accounting Principles, 
        Exception or Modifying Principles.
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. Conceptual Framework for Accounting and Reporting: </b> \n
        Elements and Meaning. Objectives, APB, Trucblood Report, Corporate Report, Stamp Report, IASC, ASB, Conceptual 
        Framework by IASC.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Book</b>
        \n\n
        
        1.	L S Porwal, Accounting Theory, Tata McGraw-Hill Publishing Company Ltd.
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name_acc422">
        <b>ACC-4202    FINANCIAL STATEMENT ANALYSIS</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>1.	Financial Statements: </b> \n
        Overview.
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. Balance Sheet: </b> \n
        Financial Condition, Analysis of Assets, Analysis of Liabilities, Stockholders Equity.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Income Statement and Statement of Stockholders Equity: </b> \n
        Analysis of the Income Statement, Statement of Stockholder\'s Equity, Earnings Quality, Inflation, Cash Flow. Segmental 
        accounting.
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. Statement of Cash Flows: </b> \n
        Preparing a Statement of Cash Flows, Calculating Cash Flow from Operating Activities, Cash Flow from Investing 
        Activities, Cash Flow from Financing Activities, Change in Cash, Analyzing the Statements of Cash Flows.
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. Analysis of Financial Statements: </b> \n
        Objective of Financial Statement Analysis, Sources of Information - Auditor\’s Report, Management Discussion, 
        Supplementary Schedules, other sources - Tools and Techniques - Common Size Financial Statements, Key Financial 
        Ratios, Liquidity Ratios, short-term Solvency, Activity Ratios, Asset Liquidity, Asset Management Efficiency, 
        Leverage Ratios, Debt Financing and Coverage, Profitability Ratios, Overall Efficiency and Performance - 
        Analyzing Data - Background, Economy, Industry and firm, Short-term Liquidity, Nef Trade Cycle, Capital Structure 
        and Long-term Solvency, Financial Leverage, Operating Efficiency and Profitability, Relating the Ratios, Du Pont 
        System, Projections, Pro Forma statements, Market Rations.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Books</b>
        \n\n
        
        1.	 L. M Fraser and A Ormiston, Understanding Financial Statements, (6th edition). Prentice-Hall Inc, 2002
        \n\n\n\n\n

        
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name_acc423">
        <b>ACC-4203    SPECIALIZED ACCOUNTING</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>1. Final Accounts: </b> \n
        Trading and Profit and Loss Account, Balance Sheet.
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. Partnership Accounts: </b> \n
        Essential Features of Partnership. Capital Accounts. Usual Adjustments in Partnership Accounts, Admission of a 
        Partner, Goodwill, Retirement, Death, Dissolution.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Company Accounts: </b> \n
        share Capital, Stock, Types of Shares, share Issues, Application, Allotment, Calls, Calls in Arrears and in 
        Advance, Forfeiture, Surrender, Reissue of Forfeited Shares. Forfeiture of Shares when there is an over 
        subscription and prc rata allotment. Rights Issue. Bonus Share. Redeemable Preference Shares, Debentures, Final 
        Accounts of Companies.
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. Accounts for Non-Trading Concerns: </b> \n
        Receipts and Payments Accounts, Income Tax and Expenditure Accounts, Balance Sheet.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Book</b>
        \n\n
        
        1. S P Jain and K L Narang, Advanced Accountancy, Kalyani Publishers.
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name_acc424">
        <b>ACC-4204    CORPORATE REPORTING AND DISCLOSURE</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>1. Introduction to International Accounting Standards:</b> \n
        Development of Accounting and Financial Reporting, Accounting and Reporting Models, Need for International Accounting 
        Standards, International Accounting Standard Committee, Stages of Development in the International Accounting 
        Standards, Setting Process, International Accounting Standards Board, Benefits from Convergence of National and 
        International Accounting Standards.
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. Balance Sheet: </b> \n
        Perspectives and Issues, Definition of Terms, Concepts, Rules and Examples.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Income Statement, Statement of changes in Equity and Statement of Recognized Gains and Losses: </b> \n
        Perspectives and Issues, Definition of Terms, Concepts, Rules and Examples.
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. Cash Flow Statements: </b> \n
        Perspectives and Issues, Definition of Terms, Concepts, Rules and Examples.
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. Accounting and Its Global Context: </b> \n
        Cultural Environment, Legal and Political Environment, Business Environment, Selected Financial Reporting 
        Practices and Illustrations.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Books</b>
        \n\n
        
        1.	 B J Episten and A A Mirza, Interpretation and Application of International Accounting Standards, John Wiley &amp;
         Sons, Inc.
         \n\n
         
        2.	M E Haskins, K R Ferris and T I Selling, International Financial Reporting and Analysis: A 
        Contextual Emphasis, 1996, Irwin, Inc
        \n\n\n\n\n
       
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name_acc425">
        <b>ACC-4205    VIVA AND PROJECT PAPER DEFENSE</b>
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name_mgt421">
        <b>MAJOR - MANAGEMENT</b>
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>MGT-4201    MANAGEMENT THOUGHT</b> \n\n
        
        <b>1. Management Thought prior to Industrial Revolution:</b> \n
        Early Management Practices - Management Writers — Factors Leading to Development of Management Theories.
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. The Classical Theories of Management: </b> \n
        Direction of Classical Management Theories - Development of Scientific Management and Management Principles - 
        Max Weber\’s Theory of Bureaucratic Organization - Systematization of the Classical Management Theories.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Neo-Classical Theories of Management: </b> \n
        Emergence of the Human Relations Concepts - Basic Notions of - the Human Relation. Approach - Emergence of 
        Social System Approach - General Theory of Management.
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. Contemporary Management: </b> \n
        The Quantitative School — Decision Theory - Experimental Design - Game Theory - Socialist Management and Socialist 
        Principles of Management: - Apologetic in the Theory of Management.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Books</b>
        \n\n
        
        
        1.	 Claude S George, Jr., The History of Management Thought. Prentice-Hall
        \n\n
        
        2.	Herbett G. Micks, Organization: Theory and Behavior, McGraw Hills Books Ltd.
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
        
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name_mgt422">
        <b>MGT-4202    INDUSTRIAL RELATIONS AND CONFLICT MANAGEMENT</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>1. An Overview of Industrial Relations:</b> \n
        Definition - Objectives - Models - Factors affecting the Pattern of Industrial Relations - Actors in Industrial Relations.
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. Workers and Unions: </b> \n
        Workers Typology - A Profile of the Bangladeshi Workers. Union Typology - Evolution — Growth  - Characteristics 
        and Problems of the Trade Unions in Bangladesh.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Employers and Their Organizations: </b> \n
        Employers  Styles in dealing with workers- Profile of Bangladeshi Employer - Objectives and Functions of the 
        Chamber of Commerce and Industries and Bangladesh Employers Association.
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. Role of Government : </b> \n
        Government Role in Different Areas of Industrial Relations - Formulation	of Labor Policies — Labor Legislations - 
        Intervention in Wage Issues - Service Regulations - Dispute Resolution.
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. Conflict : </b> \n
        Definition — Levels of Conflict - Functions and dysfunctions of Conflict - Sources of Conflict - Classification of 
        Conflict - Effects of Conflict — Factors that make Conflict Difficult to Manage - Approaches to Managing Conflict.
        \n\n
        
        <b>6. Conflict Resolution:</b> Negotiation	Planning	and Strategy — Negotiation Breakdown - Causes and 
        Cures - Communication in Negotiation - Persuasion Process - Social Structure of Negotiation - Power in Negotiation — 
        Third Party Intervention.
        \n\n
        
        <b>7. Industrial Conflict: </b> Nature — Process — Theories — Institutional Methods of resolution — Factors 
        Affecting Resolution. Collective Bargaining - Concept - Process - Scope — Prerequisites - Operation in Bangladesh 
        Context.
        \n\n
        
        <b>8. Adjudication Machinery: </b> \n
        Organization and Operation of Labor Court - Problems Encountered.
        \n\n
        
        <b>9. Employee Discipline and Grievance Handling Procedure:</b> \n
        Concept — Steps in Disciplinary Action — Domestic Enquiry - Charge Sheet — Cause of Grievances Grievance Handling 
        Procedure — the Employment of Labor (Standing Order) Act.
        \n\n
        
        <b>10. Participative Management and Industrial Democracy:  </b> \n
        Determinants — Country Experience - Experience in Bangladesh.
        \n\n
        
        <b>11. Ethics in Conflict Management: </b> \n
        Reasons for Ethics - Causes of Unethical Behavior — Model of Ethical Decision Making - factors Creating Unethical 
        Tactics.
        \n\n
        
        <b>12. Bangladesh and ILO: </b> \n
        Objectives - Structure and Finance of ILO - Impact of ILO on the labor in Bangladesh.
        \n\n\n
        
        
        <b>Recommended Books</b>
        \n\n
        
        1.	 Arun Monappa, Industrial Relations. Tata McGraw Hill.
        \n\n
        
        2.	 Dale Yoder, Personnel. Management and Industrial Relations, Prcnticc-Hall, Inc.
        \n\n
        
        3.	Relevant Laws \n
        •	Industrial Relations Ordnance 1969 \n
        •	Industrial Relations Rules 1977 \n
        •	Employment of Labor (Standing Order) Act 1965 \n
        •	Employment of Labor (Standing Order) Act 1968 \n
        •	Documents of ILO \n
        •	Annual Report of DCCI and FDCCI
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name_mgt423">
        <b>MGT-4203    COMPARATIVE MANAGEMENT</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>1. Introduction:	</b> \n
        Concepts of Comparative Management and International Management - Comparing Culture - Organizational versus 
        National Culture — Defining Culture — Managing Cultural Diversity — Why are Cultural Management Skills Important.
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. Culture and Comparative Management: </b> \n
        The need for Comparative Management — Management Culture Bound — Cultural and National Perspectives - Convergence 
        and Divergence Forces — Cross-Cultural Management - Models for Analyzing and Universality and Transferability of 
        Management.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Management Behavior and Leadership Style:</b> \n
        Comparative Management Models - Leadership Styles - Decision Making Styles.
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. An Overview:</b> \n
        Management systems in USA, UK and Japan - Main strengths and weaknesses.
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. Management Scenario of Developing Countries:</b> \n
        Characteristics of Developing Countries - Features of Management Practices — Success Story of the third world MNCs.
        \n\n
        
        <b>6. Management Style in Bangladesh: </b> \n
        Brief History — Culture — Economy - Features - Comparison with Management Systems of- other Countries.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Books</b>
        \n\n
        
        1.	S. Ronen. Comparative and Multinational Management, John Wiicy and Sons.
        \n\n
        
        2.	Richard Mead, International Management:	Cross Cultural Dimensions, Blackwell.
        \n\n
        
        3.	K B  Hoque, Management System m Bangladesh and Japan: A Comparative Study, Institute of Development Economics, Tokyo.
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
        
        
    </string>
        
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name_mgt424">
        <b>MGT-4204    INDUSTRIAL PSYCHOLOGY</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Prefatory: </b> \n
        Concept - Scope - Objective - Importance. Industry a place to study human behavior. Psychology applied in industry.
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. Attitude: </b> \n
        Formation and Change - Opinion — Attitude and Productivity - relevant Experiment.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Causation in Behavior: </b> \n
        Understanding versus Evaluating Behavior - Causal Sequence in Behavior - Application of the Causation  
        Formula to the Job - Same Behavior due to different Causes Different Behavior due to same Causes - Personality.
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. Learning: </b> \n
        Learning under Classical Conditions - Instrumental Condition — Avoidance Learning - Pavlov\’s and Skinner\’s 
        Experiment.
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. Personnel Selection and Evaluation: </b> \n
        Jobs and their Requirements - Job related Terms — Human Ability and their Measurement - Use of Psychological Tests 
        in Selection and Placement - Training - Evaluation of Training Methods - Employee Turnover - Absenteeism.
        \n\n
        
        <b>6. Job Satisfaction: </b> \n
        Job satisfaction in Organization - Job Satisfaction and Productivity - Job Related Variables.
        \n\n
        
        <b>7. Development of Participation: </b> \n
        Nature of Employee Participation - Prerequisites for Effective Participation - Organizational Programs to Build 
        Participation — Labor Union\’s Role in Participation - Limitations of Participation.
        \n\n
        
        <b>8. Employee Counseling: </b> \n
        Role of Counseling - Causes of Counseling Needs - What Counseling can do - Manager\'s Counseling Role - 
        Directive and Non-directive Counseling.
        \n\n
        
        <b>9. Frustration: </b> \n
        The Nature of-Problem Situation - Variability in Behavior - Symptoms of Frustration - Characteristics of 
        Motivated and Frustrated behavior — Frustration and Social Movements - Dealing with Frustration.
        \n\n
        
        <b>10. Motivation: </b> \n
        Human Needs - Maslow\’s Priority Model - Wants and Needs - Motivational and Maintenance Factors - Comparison of 
        Herzberg and Maslow Models - Motivation and Productivity - nature and Study of Motivation at Work Place.
        \n\n
        
        <b>11. Leadership: </b> \n
        Concept — Manager and Leader - Early Concepts of Leadership — Role Behavior as an evidence of Leadership - 
        Skills used in Role Behavior - Factors Affecting Leadership - Leadership Styles - Applications of Styles.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommend Books</b>
        \n\n
        
        1.	Norman R. F. Maier, Psychology in Industry.
        \n\n
        2.	Keith Davis, Human Behavior at Work, McGraw Hills Irwin
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
        
     </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name_mgt425">
        <b>MGT-4205    VIVA AND PROJECT PAPER DEFENSE</b>
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name_fin421">
        <b>MAJOR-FINANCE</b>
        \n\n\n
        
        <b> FIN-4201    FINANCIAL ANALYSIS</b> 
        \n\n
        
        1.	Objectives of Financial Statement Analysis \n\n
        
        2.	Financial Statement Analysis and Accounting \n\n
        
        3.	Accounting Objectives, Conventions, and Standards - Their Implications for Analysis \n\n
        
        4.	Tools and Techniques of Financial Statement Analysis - An Overview \n\n
        
        5.	Analysis of Current Assets \n\n
        
        6.	Analysis of Noncurrent Assets \n\n
        
        7.	Analysis of Liabilities \n\n
        
        8.	Analysis of Stockholders Equity \n\n
        
        9.	Inter corporate Investments, Business Combinations, and Foreign Operations \n\n
        
        10.	Analysis of the Income Statement \n\n
        
        11.	Earnings Per Share - Computation and Evaluation \n\n
        
        12.	Statements of Cash Flows \n\n
        
        13.	Effects of Price Changes on Financial Statements \n\n
        
        14.	The Auditor\'s Opinion - Meaning and Significance \n\n
        
        15.	Analysis of Short-Term Liquidity \n\n
        
        16.	Funds Flow Analysis and Financial Forecasts \n\n
        
        17.	Analysis of Capital Structure and Long-Term Solvency \n\n
        
        18.	Analysis of Return on Investment and of Asset Utilization \n\n
        
        19.	Analysis of Results of Operations \n\n
        
        20.	The Evaluation and Protection of Earnings \n\n
        
        21.	Comprehensive Analysis of Financial Statements \n\n\n
        
        
        <b>Recommended Rooks</b>
        \n\n
        
        1.	 Leopold A. Bernstein, Financial Statement Analysis - Theory, Application, and Interpretation, 
        (5th edition, 1993) Irwin, USA.
        \n\n
        
        2.	George Foster. Financial Statement Analysis.
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
        
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name_fin422">
        <b>FIN-4202    SECURITY ANALYSIS AND PORTFOLIO MANAGEMENT</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>1. Introduction to Investment: </b> \n
        Introduction to Investment; Securities; Securities Market.
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. Investment Setting: </b> \n
        Definition of Investment, Measures of Returns and Risks, Determinants of Required Rate of Returns, Relationship 
        between Risk and Return.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Introduction to Portfolio Management: </b>
        \n
        
        Background Assumptions, Markowitz Portfolio Theory, Combining Individual Assets into Portfolio.
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. Introduction to Asset Pricing Model: </b> \n
        Capital Market Theory, Capital Asset Pricing Model, Expected Return and risk, Arbitrage Pricing Theory.
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. Introduction to Security Valuation: </b> \n
         Overview of Valuation Process, Why a Three Step Valuation Process? Theory of Valuation, Valuation of Alternative 
         Investments, Relative Valuation Techniques, Required rate of return and Expected Growth Rate of Valuation Variables.
        \n\n
        
        <b>6. Bond Fundamentals:</b> \n
        Basic Features of a Bond, Global Bond Market Structure. Alternative Bond Issues, Obtaining Information on Bond Prices.
        \n\n
        
        <b>7. Analysis and Valuation of Bonds: </b> \n
        Fundamentals of Bond Valuation, Computing Bond Yields, Calculating future Bond Prices, Bond Valuation using Spot
         Rates, What determines Interest Rate? What determines Price Volatility for Bonds?
        \n\n
        
        <b>8. Bond Portfolio Management Strategies:	</b> \n
        Alternative Bond Portfolio Strategies, Implications of capital Market Theory and the EMH on Bond Portfolio Management.
        \n\n
        
        <b>9. Stock Market Analysis: </b> \n
        Applying the DDM Valuation Model to the Market, Estimating the Growth Rate of Dividends, Valuation using the relative
         Valuation Approach, Estimating expected EPS, Estimating the Earning Multiplier for a Stock Series, Calculating 
         Expected Rate of Return on Common Stocks.
        \n\n
        
        <b>10. Industry Analysis: </b> \n
        Why do Industry Analysis? Business Cycle and Industry Sectors, Structural Economic Changes and Alternative 
        Industries, Estimating Industry Rates of return, Industry Analysis using Relative Valuation Approach. Other Relative 
        Valuation Rations, Global Industry Analysis.
        \n\n
        
        <b>11. Company Analysis and stock Selection: </b> \n
        Company Analysis versus Selection of Stock. Economic, Industry and structural Links to Company Analysis, Company 
        Analysis. Estimating Intrinsic Value. Estimating Company Earning per Share.
        \n\n
        
        <b>12. Equity Portfolio Management Strategies: </b> \n
        Passive versus Active Management, Overview of Passive Equity Portfolio Management Strategies, Overview of Active 
        Portfolio Management Strategies. Value versus Growth Investment.
        \n\n
        
        <b>13.	Evaluation of Portfolio Performance</b> \n
        What is required of a Portfolio Manager? Composite Portfolio Performance Measures. Evaluation of Bond Portfolio 
        Performance. Reporting Investment Performance.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Books</b>
        \n\n
        
        
        1.	 Reilly and Brown, Investment Analysis and Portfolio Management. 
        \n\n

        2.	Elton and Gruber. Modern Portfolio Theory.
        \n\n\n\n\n
       
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name_fin423">
        <b>FIN-4203    FINANCIAL MARKET AND INSTITUTIONS</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>1. Introduction: </b> \n
        Financial Assets with classifications. Financial Markets with Classifications, Globalization of Financial Market 
        and Derivative Markets.
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. Financial Intermediaries and Financial Innovation: </b> \n
        Financial Institutions, Role of financial Intermediaries. Overview of Asset and Liability Management in Financial 
        Institutions, Financial Innovation and Asset Securitization.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Depository Institutions: </b> \n
        Asset and Liability problem of Depository Institutions, Commercial Banks, Savings Banks and Credit Unions.
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. Insurance Companies: </b> \n
        Characteristics, Life Insurance Companies. Property and Casualty Insurance Companies, Finance in the International 
        Insurance Industry.
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. Investment Companies: </b> \n
        Types of Investment Companies. Structure and expenses of a Fund, Economic Motivation for Funds, Regulation of Funds, 
        Commercial Banks and Mutual  Funds.
        \n\n
        
        <b>6. Pension Funds: </b> \n
        Introduction to Pension Plans, Types of Pension plans, Investments, Regulation and Managers of Pension Funds.
        \n\n
        
        <b>7. Properties and Pricing of Financial Assets: </b> \n
        Properties of Financial Assets, Principles of Pricing Financial Assets and Price Volatility of Financial Assets.
        \n\n
        
        <b>8. Level and Structure of Interest Rates:</b> \n
        Theory of Interest Rates, Determinants of the Structure of Interest Rate.
        \n\n
        
        <b>9. Risk/Return and Asset Pricing Model: </b> \n
        Portfolio Theory, Capital Asset Pricing Model and Arbitrage Pricing theory.
        \n\n
        
        <b>10. Primary Markets and the Underwriting of Securities: </b> \n
        Process of Issuing New Securities, Investment Bankers, regulation of Primary Market, Variation in Underwriting 
        Process and Private Placement of Securities.
        \n\n
        
        <b>11. Secondary Markets: </b> \n
        Definition, Functions, trading Locations, Market Structures, Perfect Markets, Role of Brokers and Dealers.
        \n\n
        
        <b>12. Markets for Corporate Senior Instruments: </b> \n
        Credit Risk and the Role of rating Companies, Commercial Papers, Medium Term Notes, Euronotes and Bank Loans, 
        Corporate Bonds, Preferred Stocks, Bankruptcy Creditor Rights.
        \n\n
        
        <b>13. Mortgage Market: </b> \n
        Definition and Origin, Types of Mortgage Design and Investment Risks.
        \n\n
        
        <b>14. Financial Future Markets: </b> \n
        Futures Contracts/Futures versus Forward Contracts, Role of Futures in Financial Markets.
        \n\n
        
        <b>15. Options Markets: </b> \n
        Options Contract, Difference between Options and future Contracts, Risk and Return Characteristics of Options.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Books</b>
        \n\n
        
        1.	Frank J Fabozzi,. Franco Modigliani and Michael G Ferri, foundations of Financial Markets and Institutions.
        \n\n
        
        2.	 Anthony M Santomero and David F Babbel, Financial Markets  Instruments and Institutions.
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
        
        
        
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name_fin424">
        <b>FIN-4204    PUBLIC FINANCE</b>
        \n\n
        
        1.	Introduction \n\n
        
        2.	Efficiency, optimality and allocation of resources \n\n
        
        3.	Pure public goods \n\n
        
        4.	Normative and Subjective Approach \n\n
        
        5.	Principles and Canons of Taxation \n\n
        
        6.	Externality and the role of government \n\n
        
        7.	Government and the income distribution \n\n
         
        8.	Budget system and cost benefit analysis \n\n
        
        9.	Revenue structure decision making \n\n
        
        10.	Economic effects of income and consumption taxes, the expenditure tax \n\n
        
        11.	The incidence of commodity taxes, excise taxes \n\n
        
        12.	Public finance and the developing economies.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Books</b>
        \n\n
        1.	 Due and Friedlauder, Government Finance
        \n\n
        
        2.	 Rosne, Public-Finance
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
   
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name_fin425">
        <b>FIN-4205    VIVA AND PROJECT PAPER DEFENSE</b>
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name_mkt421">
        <b>MAJOR – MARKETING</b>
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>MKT-4201    CONSUMER BEHAVIOUR</b>
        \n\n
        
        
        <b>1. Introduction to Consumer Behavior: </b> \n
        
        An Overview of Consumer Behavior - Consumer Decision Making Process — Scope of Consumer Behavior Field- Theory 
        Building - Role of Theory - Criteria of a Sound Theory - How Models are Constructed - Different Models of Consumer 
        - Application of Consumer Behavior Theories.	
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. Environmental Influences:</b> \n
        Culture — Defining Culture — Components of Culture — Concepts of Cultural Analysis — Cross Cultural Research — 
        Multinational Marketing — Subculture.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Social Organization and Reference Groups: </b> \n
        Socialization — Primary and Secondary Reference Groups — Reference Group Norms and Conformity - Social Change — 
        Social Change and its affect on Consumption. Social Class - Social Stratification - Research Models for Social 
        Class - Social Class and Buying Behavior. Family - Influence on Family Decision Making - Using family Concepts in 
        Marketing.
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. Individual Influences: </b> \n
        Learning - Learning Theory - Behavior Modification in Psychology and Marketing - Retention and Advertising Massages - 
        Habit Formation and Brand Loyalty. Perception — Theories of Perception Affecting Consumer Behavior. Motivation and 
        Personality - Motivation Theory - Motivation Research Methods - Concept of Personality. Attitude - Influence of 
        Attitude — Component of Attitude Model - Functions of Attitude - Measurement of Attitudes - Attitude Change - 
        Cognitive Dissonance Theory – Multi attitude Theory.
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. Purchasing and Post Purchasing Behavior: </b> \n
        Purchasing Process - Planned Purchases - Intention and Probability - Unplanned Purchases - Impulse Buying - Post 
        Purchase Behavior.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Books </b>
         \n\n
         
         1.	 Harold W Berkman and Christopher C Gibson, Consumer Behavior: Concepts and Strategies, Kent Publishing Company
         \n\n
         
         2.	 Loon G Schiffman and Leslie Lazar Kanuk, Consumer Behavior, (6th Edition), Prcnticc-hall Inc.
         \n\n\n\n\n
         
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name_mkt422">
        <b>MKT-4202	   MARKETLNG RESEARCH</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>1. Introduction: </b> \n
        Definition - Importance — Classification - Role in MIS and DSS — Marketing Research suppliers and Services — 
        Marketing Research Process - Ethics in Marketing Research.
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. Defining Marketing Research Problem and Developing an Approach: </b> \n
        Nature and Importance of Marketing Research Problem - Process of Defining the Problem - Process of Developing an 
        Approach - Management Decision Problem and Marketing Research Problem.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Research Design: </b> \n
        Definition — Classification -Sources of Error — Budgeting and Scheduling the Project — Marketing Research Proposal.
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. Exploratory Research Design: </b> \n
        Primary versus Secondary Data - Criteria for Evaluating secondary Data - Classification of Secondary Data — 
        Qualitative versus Quantitative Research — Classification of Qualitative Research Procedures.
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. Descriptive Research Design: </b> \n
        Survey Methods — Survey Methods Classified by Mode of Administration - A Comparative Evaluation of survey Methods. 
        Observation Methods - Observation Methods Classified by Mode of Administration.
        \n\n
        
        <b>6. Causal Research Design: </b> \n
        Concept of Causality - Conditions for Causality - Validity in Experimentation - Extraneous Variables - A 
        Classification of Experimental Design Laboratory versus Field Experimentation.
        \n\n
        
        <b>7. Measurement and Scaling: </b> \n
        Primary Scales of Measurement - Comparative and Non-comparative Scaling techniques — Non comparative Itemized 
        rating Scale Decisions—Scale Evaluation.
        \n\n
        
        <b>8. Questionnaire and Form Design:</b> \n
        Questionnaire definition — Characteristics - Considerations for Drafting a Questionnaire — Questionnaire Design 
        Process — Observational Forms.
        \n\n
        
        <b>9. Sampling Design and Procedures: </b> \n
        Sample versus Census — Sampling Design Process - Non-probability and Probability Sampling Techniques.
        \n\n
        
        <b>10. Data Collection, Preparation and Analysis: </b> \n
        Nature of field Work - Field Work and Data Collection Process - Data Preparation Process - Classification of Statistical 
        Techniques.
        \n\n
        
        <b>11. Frequency Distribution, Cross-Tabulation and hypothesis Testing: </b> \n
        Statistics Associated with Frequency Distribution  — Cross Tabulation — Statistics associated with Cross Tabulation — 
        Hypothesis Testing - Parametric Tests - Non parametric Testing.
        \n\n
        
        <b>12. Report Preparation and Presentation: </b> \n
        Nature and Importance of Report and Presentation - Report Preparation and Presenting Process.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Book</b>
        \n\n
        
        1.	 Narcsh K Malhotra, Marketing Research: An Applied Orientation, Prcnticc-Hall, 2000
        \n\n
        
        2.	David A Aakcr, V Kumar and George S Day, , Marketing Research, (5lh Edition), John Wiley and Sons
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name_mkt423">
        <b>MKT-4203    MARKETING PROMOTION</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>1. Introduction: </b> \n
        Meaning - Scope — Importance and Role - Different Types of Marketing Promotion — Promotion Planning Process.
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. Analyzing Communication Process: </b> \n
        Nature — Basic Model of Communication — developing Effective Communication.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Advertising: </b> \n
        Meaning - Importance - Classification - Creative Strategies - Planning and development - Creating Strategy - 
        Implementation and Evaluation - Media Planning and Strategy - The Media Plan - Developing the Media Plan - Market 
        Analysis - Establishment of Media Objectives - Media Strategy development and implementation and Evaluation and 
        Follow-up - Types of Media - Effectiveness of Advertising - Corporate Advertising - Objectives - Types - Advantages 
        and Disadvantages.
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. Personnel Selling: </b> \n
        Meaning — Role — Objective - Prospecting — The Selling Process - Opening and Securing Interview - Delivering the 
        Presentation - Demonstration - Answering - Objections and Closing the Sales. Designing the Salesforce - Objectives - 
        Strategies - Structure - Size and Compensation. Managing the Salesforce - recruitment and Selection - Training - 
        Motivation - Evaluation.
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. Public Relations, Publicity and Corporate Advertising: </b> \n
        Public Relations - Meaning - Role - Marketing Public Relation Function - Process of Public Relations. Publicity — 
        Powers of Publicity - Control and Dissemination of Publicity. Corporate Advertising - Objectives - Types - 
        Advantages and Disadvantages - Measuring the Effectiveness of Corporate Advertising.
        \n\n
        
        <b>6. Sales Promotion: </b> \n
        Meaning - Role - Growth - Major Decisions in Sales Promotion.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Book</b>
        \n\n
        
        1.	 George E Belch and Micheal E Belch, Advertising and Promotion — An Integrated Marketing Communications 
        Perspective.
        \n\n
        
        2.	C A Carpatric and F A Russ, Effective Selling.
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name_mkt424">
        <b>MKT-4204    BRAND MARKETING</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>1. Brands and Brand Management: </b> \n
        What is Brand? Why do Brands Matter? Can anything be Branded? Branding Challenges and Opportunities, Brand Equity 
        Concept, Strategic Brand Management Process.
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. Customer Based Brand Equity: </b> \n
        Customer based Brand Equity,Brand Knowledge, Sources of Brand Equity. Building a Strong Brand.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Choosing Brand Elements, to Build Brand Equity: </b> \n
        Criteria for Choosing Brand Elements, Options and Tactics for Brand Elements.
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. Designing Marketing Programs to build Brand Equity:</b>
        \n
        New Perspectives on Marketing. Product	Strategy. Pricing Strategy,
        Channel Strategy .
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. Integrating Marketing Communication to Build Brand Equity: </b> \n
        Information Processing Model of Communication. Marketing Communication Options, Developing Integrated Marketing 
        Communication Programs.
        \n\n
        
        <b>6. Developing a Brand Equity Measurement and Management System: </b>
        \n
        
        Brand Value Chain, Designing Brand Tracking Studies, Brand Equity Management System.
        \n\n
        
        <b>7. Designing and Implementing Branding Strategies: </b> \n
        Brand - Product Matrix, Brand Hierarchy, Designing Branding Strategy.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Book</b>
        \n\n
        
        1.	 Kevin Lane K alter, Strategic Brand Management - Building, Measuring and Managing Brand Equity, 
        (Second Edition), Pearson Education.
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name_mkt425">
        <b>MKT-4205    VIVA AND PROJECT PAPER DEFENSE</b>
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
        
    </string>
    
</resources>