<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name321">
        <b>3201    FINANCIAL MANAGEMENT</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>1. Itroduction to financial management : </b> \n
        Definition of financial management , goals of the firm, agency relationship, the efficient market hypotheses, discounted
         cash flow analysis, the risk return trade offs.
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. Risk and Return : </b> \n
        Probability distribution , total risk analysis, portfolio risk analysis, CAPM, APT, and other model.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Valuation Concepts and models : </b> \n
        General valuation model, bond valuation, preferred stock, cost of common equity , cost of retained earning , the CAPM 
        approach , the DCF and risk premium methods, cost of newly issued common stock, WACC, Other issues in the cost of 
        capital.
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. Cost Capital : </b> \n
        Capital components and cost , cost of debt , cost of preferred stock, cost of common equity, cost of return earning, 
        the CAPM approach, the DCF approach, bond yield plus risk premium approach, comparison of the CAPM, DCF and risk 
        premium method; cost of newly issued common stock , WACC, other issues in the cost of capital.
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. Overview of Capital Budgeting and Risk Analysis in Capital Budgeting : </b> \n
        Capital budgeting decision rules, comparison of NPV and IRR, risk adjustment, introduction to risk assessment, 
        techniques for measuring corporate risk, market risk, relationship among firm beta, asset beta, and capital structure, 
        techniques of measuring beta risk, portfolio effect within firm, problems with project risk assessment, 
        incorporation project risk in the capital budgeting decisions.
        \n\n
        
        <b>6. Working Capital Policy and Financing : </b> \n
        Working capital terminology , the requirements for external working capital financing , the working capital cash flow 
        cycle, working capital investment and financing policies, advances and disadvantage of short term credit, sources of 
        short term financing, accruals, accounts payable or trade credit, short term loans, account receivable financing, 
        inventory financing.
        \n\n
        
        <b>7. Capital Structure Theories : </b> \n
        Early theories of capital structure, the MM model, Financial distress and agency costs, review of the tradeoff model.
        \n\n
        
        <b>8. Dividend Policy : </b> \n
        Dividend policy theories, dividend policies issues, dividend policies in practice , summery of factors that influence 
        the dividend policies.
        \n\n
        
        <b>9. Mergers and Corporate Restructuring : </b> \n
        A perspective on Corporate restructuring, Forms of Business Combination, mergers, merger mechanics, payment methods, 
        tax consideration, reasons for business combination, evaluating proposed business combination by the seller and the 
        buyers, are mergers profitable? Corporate takeover fights.
        \n\n
       
        <b>10. Cash and marketable Securities management : </b> \n
        Cash management, the cash budget, setting the target cash balance , cash management techniques, matching the cost and 
        benefits of cash management, marketable securities management.
        \n\n
        
        <b>11. Receivable Management and Credit Policy : </b> \n
        receivable management, credit policy, cash discount, other factors influencing credit policy. 
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommend Books : </b>
        \n\n
        
        1. Charles P Jones, Introduction to Financial Management. \n\n
        
        2. Brigham and Gapenski, Intermediate Financial Management. \n\n
        
        3. Ross and Westerfield, Corporate Finance.
        
        \n\n\n\n\n
       
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name322">
        <b>3202    ENTREPRENEURAL DEVELOPMENT </b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>1. Entrepreneur : </b> \n
        Evolution of the concepts of entrepreneur, characteristics of an entrepreneur, function of entrepreneur, types of 
        entrepreneur.
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. Entrepreneurship : </b> \n
        Concepts of entrepreneurship, growth of entrepreneurship in Bangladesh, Role of entrepreneurship in economic 
        development.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Factors affecting entrepreneurial growth : </b> \n
        Environment for entrepreneurship, environmental factors , economic factors , non-economic factors , government actions.
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. Entrepreneurial motivation : </b> \n
        Motivation theories, motivating factors , achievement motivation.
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. Entrepreneurial competencies : </b> \n
        Meaning of entrepreneurial competence or trait, major entrepreneurial competence, developing competencies.
        \n\n
        
        <b>6. Entrepreneurial mobility : </b> \n
        Factors influencing mobility, occupational mobility, locational mobility.
        \n\n
        
        <b>7. Small enterprises : </b> \n
        characteristics, rational, scope, opportunities for an entrepreneurial career, role of small enterprises in economic 
        development.
        \n\n
        
        <b>8. Project Identification and Selection :</b> \n
        Meaning of project , project identification , project selection,formulation of a project report, concepts of project 
        appraisal, metods of project appraisal, business plan.
        \n\n
        
        <b>9. Finance of enterprises : </b> \n
        Finance planning, source of finance, capital structure.
        \n\n
        
        <b>10. Industrial Support to Entrepreneurs of Bangladesh :</b> \n
        Need for institutional support , financial institution of government and non-government of Bangladesh, supply and demand side analysis of support and 
        assistance of Bangladesh, Government policy and progams for small scale Enterprises.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommend Books : </b>
        \n\n
        
        1. S S Khanka , Entrepreneurial development , S Chanda and company ltd.
        \n\n
        
        2. Hisrich and Petter, Entrepreneurship, Tata McGraw-Hill.
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name323">
        <b>3203    INTERNATIONAL BUSINESS </b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>1. Introduction : </b> \n
        Definition – characteristics – scope – importance in the world economy – trend with special reference to Bangladesh.
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. International trade theories : </b> \n
        Overview of trade theory – source of international trade – absolute advances – comparative advantages – economic 
        gains – huckster – ohlin theory.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Protectionism and Free Trade : </b> \n
        Arguments for and against protectionism – economic of protectionism – instruments of protectionism – multilateral 
        Tread Negotiation – removing barriers to free trade.
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. Foreign Exchange Rate : </b> \n
        Nature and Importance of foreign exchange rate – equilibrium exchange rates – determination of foreign exchange rate 
        – nominal and exchange rates – appreciation and depreciation of currencies.
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. Balance of Payment : </b> \n
        Concepts of balance of payments and balance of trade – adjustment mechanism of balance payments – disequilibrium – 
        causes of disequilibrium – removal of disequilibrium.
        \n\n
        
        <b>6. Issues of International trade : </b> \n
        The Bertton woods system – the international monetary fund (IMF) – The World Bank – world trade organization(WTO).
        \n\n
        
        <b>7. Bangladesh and International Trade : </b> \n
        Bangladesh position in the developing countries – trade intensity and terms of tread of Bangladesh with the SAARC 
        countries – quota free export market – trends and composition of export and import Bangladesh.
        \n\n
        
        <b>8. Institutions Assisting International Trade of Bangladesh : </b> \n
        Export promotion bureau (EPB) – Export Processing zone (EPZ) – Trading corporation of Bangladesh(TCB) – Bangladesh 
        Standard and Testing Institution(BSTI).
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Books : </b>
        \n\n
        
        1. Charles W L Hills, Institutional Business, McGraw-Hill.
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name324">
        <b>3204    MARKEING MANAGEMENT</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>1. Understanding Marketing Management : </b> \n
        Define marketing management – importance of marketing management – core marketing management concepts – scope of 
        marketing management – demand management – marketing management philosophies – the marketing management process.
        \n\n
        
        
        <b>2. Managing Marketing Information and Measuring Market Demand : </b> \n
        Define marketing information system – marketing intelligence and research system – marketing decision support system – 
        An overview of forecasting and demand measurement.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Market Targeting and Market Positioning : </b> \n
        Define market targeting and positioning – importance and evaluation of market segments for market targeting – tools 
        for competitive differentiation – developing target positioning strategies – communication the company\'s positioning 
        – consumer values – SWOT analysis for the positioning strategies.
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. Competitive Strategies : </b> \n
        Identifying competitors – market leader strategies – market challenger strategies – market follower strategies – 
        market niche Strategies.    
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. Managing Product Life-cycle Strategies : </b> \n
        Products life-cycle – marketing strategies throughout the product life cycle – stages in market evolution and analysis.
        \n\n
        
        <b>6. Developing new products : </b> \n
        Define new product – stages of new product development – manging new products development process – Strategies for new 
        product development – the consumer adoption process.
        \n\n
        
        <b>7. Managing Products, Services and Brand : </b> \n
        Dynamics of attribute competition – product hierarchy – product mix decision – product line decisions – Brand decision 
        – categoric of services – characteristics of services and marketing implications – marketing strategies for firms – 
        managing product support services.
        \n\n
        
        <b>8. Designing pricing strategies : </b> \n
        Setting the price – new product pricing strategies – adapting the pricing – initiating and responding to the price 
        changes.
        \n\n
        
        <b>9. Managing Marketing Channel : </b> \n
        Channel Functions and flows – Channel Levels – channels in the services sector – channels design decision – 
        channels dynamics – channel cooperation – conflict and competition – managing retailing – wholesaling and market 
        logistics.
        \n\n
        
        <b>10. Managing Direct and on- line Marketing : </b> \n
        Benefits of direct marketing – major channels for direct marketing – advances and disadvantage of on-line marketing – 
        challenges ODF electronic commerce.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommend Books : </b>
        \n\n
        
        1. Philip kotler, Marketing Management , prentice-Hall inc.
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
         
        
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name325">
        <b>3205    PRODUTION AND OPERATIONS MANAGEMENT</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>1. Induction to operational management : </b>
        \n
        
        Meaning of process, meaning of operational management, difference and similarities of manufacturing and services, 
        trends in operations management, operations management across the organization.
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. Operational strategies : </b> \n
        Corporate strategies, market analysis, competitive priorities, services strategies, manufacturing strategies, mass 
        customization.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Process management : </b> \n
        Meaning of process management, major process decisions, relationship between decision in manufacturing and services, 
        job design consideration, economics of scope, designing process.
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. Total Quality Management : </b> \n
        Meaning of process management, major process decisions, relationship between decisions in manufacturing and services, 
        job design consideration, economics of scope, designing processes.
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. Capacity Decisions : </b> \n
        Capacity planning, systematic approach to capacity decisions – estimating capacity requirements, identify gaps, develop 
        alternative, evaluate alternative, tools of capacity planning.
        \n\n
        
        <b>6. Location Analysis : </b> \n
        Factors Affecting Locations Decisions, locating a single facility, comparing several sites , applying load – distance 
        methods, using break-even analysis.
        \n\n
        
        <b>7. Layout Analysis : </b> \n
        Meaning of layout planning, layout types, creating hybrid layouts, designing process layout, warehouse layout, office 
        layouts, designing products layout – line balancing, other considerations. 
        \n\n
        
        <b>8. Inventory Management : </b> \n
        Inventory concepts – pressures for low inventories, pressures for high inventories, types of inventories, inventory 
        reduction tactics, placement of manufacturing inventories, economic oder quantity – cancellation EOQ, non instantaneous 
        replacement , quantity discounts, one period decision.
        \n\n
        
        <b>9. Aggregate Planning and Scheduling : </b> \n
        Purpose of aggregates plans , managerial importance of aggregates plans, planning processes, identifying alternatives, 
        preparing an acceptable plans, scheduling in manufacturing – Gantt charts, Performance Measures, job shop dispatching, 
        sequencing operations for single and multi machines, scheduling in services – scheduling customer demand, scheduling 
        workforce, characteristics of just-in-time operations – pull method of material flow, small lot sizes, uniform 
        workstations loads, standardized components and work methods, close supplier ties, flexible workforce, line flows, 
        Kanban  system – general operating rules, determination number of containers, JIT II.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommend Books : </b> \n\n
        
        1. Lee J Krajewski and Larry P. Ritzman, Operations Management: Strategy and Analysis, Addition-Wesley Publishing 
        Company.
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
        
        <b></b>
        
    </string>
    
</resources>