<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name211">
        <b>2101    PRINCIPLES OF FINANCE </b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>1. Introduction : </b> \n
        Definition, Business Finance, Functions of Financial Manager, Goals of the Firm, Social Responsibilities of the Firm.
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. Concepts of Risk and Return : </b> \n
        Definition of Risk, Difference between Risk and Uncertainty, Relation between Risk and Return, Measurement of Risk, 
        Portfolio Risk, Corporate risk, Market Risk, Significance of Risk in the field of  Financial Environment.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Time value of money and It\'s Applications :  </b> \n
        Time value definitions, present value, future values, concepts of annuity, compounding, effective rate of return.
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. Short term Financing :  </b> \n
        Potentiating Source  of Short term financing, Trade credit, Accruals, Negotiated short, Term Financing, Short term 
        Bank loans, Open market loans, Secured loans, Others source of short term financing.
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. Common and Preferred Stock Financing : </b> \n
        Market for common stock, Decision to go public, Decision to list, Procedures for selling new common stock, advantages 
        and disadvantages of common stock financing, preferred stock financing,  Investment banking process.
        \n\n
        
        <b>6. Bonds and Convertible securities: </b> \n
        Bonds, Types of loan term debt, Important bond features, Bond refunding junk bonds, Advantages and disadvantage of 
        financing with debt, convertible securities, conversion terms, valuation of convertibles, bond ratings, provisions in 
        bond indenture.
        \n\n
        
        <b>7. Lease Financing: </b> \n
        Types of leases, Tax effects, financial statement effects, evaluation by the lessee, evaluation by the lessor, other 
        issues in lease analysis.
        \n\n
        
        <b>8. Concepts of Cost of Capital and Valuation of Securities: </b> \n
        Capital components and cost, cost of preferred stock, cost of common equity cost of retained earning, WACC, general 
        valuation model, bond valuation, preferred stock valuation, common stock valuation.
        \n\n
        
        <b>9. Introduction to Capital Budgeting: </b> \n
        Concepts of capital budgeting, capital budgeting decision rules, Evaluation of the decision rules, comparison of NPV 
        and IRR methods, comparison of the NPV and PI methods, Multiple IRR.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Books: </b> \n\n
        
        1.	Charles P Jones, Introduction to Financial Management, Homewood.
        \n\n
        
        2.	Santley B Block and Geoffrey A Hirt, Principles of Finance , Richard D Irwin.
        \n\n
        
        
        3.	Brigham and Gapenski, Principles of Finance, The Dryden Press .
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name212">
        <b>2102    PRINCIPLES OF MARKEING  </b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>1. Foundation of Marketing : </b> \n
        Definition of marketing - Scope of marketing – modern function of marketing – core concepts of marketing - marketing 
        system and goals –  market – market and marketing mix – marketing process.
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. Marketing Environment : </b> \n
        The macro and micro marketing environment – environmental factors affecting consumer decision - making process.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Consumer Markets and Consumer Buying Behavior: </b> \n
        Definition of consumer market and consumer buying behavior - Models of consumer behavior - factors affecting consumer 
        behavior - cultural, social and psychological factors – the buying decision process - the buyers decision process for 
        new products/service.
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. Marketing Segmentation: </b> \n
        Levels of market segmentation – bases and causes of segmenting consumer and business market - requirements of 
        effecting segmentation – evaluating market segments – selecting market segments.
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. Product and Service Classification : </b> \n
        Define product – Classification of products – Individual product decision – Product Attributes – branding – packaging 
        – labeling – products decisions – products line and product mix decision – product life cycle – nature and 
        characteristics of service – marketing strategies for service firms.
        \n\n
        
        <b>6. Pricing the Products : </b> \n
        General Pricing Approaches – Factors affecting pricing decision – product line pricing strategies – product mix 
        pricing strategies – price adjustment strategies.        
        \n\n
        
        <b>7. Distributing the products : </b> \n
        Nature of distribution channel channel design decision – channel management decisions – channel behavior and 
        organizations.
        \n\n
        
        <b>8. Marketing Promotion and Communication : </b> \n
        Steps in developing effective Communication- tools of marketing promotion – advertising – personal selling – sales 
        promotion – publicity and public relation – factors in setting the marketing communication mix.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Books : </b>
        \n\n
        
        1.	Philip kotler and Gray Armstrong, Principles of Marketing, (9th edition), Prentics Hall.
        \n\n\n\n\n 
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name213">
        <b>2103     ORGANIZAIONAL BEHAVIOUR : </b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>1. Introduction : </b> \n
        What is organization behavior? Contributing disciplines to the organizational behavior field, Challenges and 
        opportunities for organizational behavior.
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. Foundation of Individual Behavior : </b> \n
        Ability – learning – values – attitudes – job satisfaction – personality – Perception.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Motivation : </b> \n
        Form concepts to application – recognition program – involvement programs - Involvement programs – variable pay programs.
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. Foundation of Group Behavior : </b> \n
        Classifying groups – stages of group development – group structure.
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. Understanding Work Team : </b> \n
        Types of teams, Creating effective Teams.
        \n\n
        
        <b>6. Leadership : </b> \n Theories of leadership – power and politics.
        \n\n
        
        <b>7. Inter-group Behavior : </b> \n Conflict types and processor of Negotiation.
        \n\n
        
        <b>8. Organizational Culture : </b> \n
        Meaning and Characteristics.
        \n\n\n
        
        
        <b>Recommended Books : </b>
        \n\n
        
        1.	S P Robbins, Organizational Behavior, Prentice-Hall
        \n\n
        
        2.	Keith Davis, Human Behavior at Work, McGraw-Hill
        \n\n
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name214">
        <b>2104   MACRO ECONOMIC</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>1. Introduction : </b> \n
        Meaning of macroeconomics, Macroeconomics transaction, Macroeconomics markets – commodity market, labor market, money 
        market, bond market, foreign exchange market, Walras law, macroeconomics issues and trade offs – gross domestic 
        products, unemployment, Inflation, foreign debt, exchange rates, interest rates government budgets deficit, 
        macroeconomics policies – fiscal policy monetary policy.
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. Concepts and Measurement of Macroeconomics Aggregates : </b> \n
        Circular flow of income and expenditure, measurement of macroeconomics aggregates, Price Index, real versus nominal 
        GDP/GNP and GNP deflector.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Theory of Income and Determination (Fixed Price) : </b> \n
        Autarky Economy without government, variable Consumption, Multiplier, Autarky Economy with Government.
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. Money, Interest and Income : </b> \n
        Investment and Interest rate, Equilibrium in the Commodity Market – IS Curve, Interest Rate and Money, Equilibrium 
        in the money market – LM curve and velocity of money.
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. Commodity and Money Market Interactions : </b> \n
        Commodity and money market interactions, Monetary policy, Interest rate and output, Effectiveness of monetary policy, 
        Effectiveness of fiscal policy, Targets and policy mix.
        \n\n
        
        <b>6. Price Level and Aggregate Demand : </b> \n
        Slope of the AD Curve, Position of AD curve.
        \n\n
        
        <b>7. Aggregate Supply : </b> \n
        Aggregates supply (AS) – Classical model, aggregates supply – imperfect foresight models, perfectly elastic 
        aggregates supply.
        \n\n
        
        <b>8. Consumption and Investment.</b>
        \n\n\n
        
        
        <b>Recommended Books:</b> \n\n
        
        1.	Pual A Samuelson, Macroeconomics, McGraw-Hill, India.
        \n\n
        
        2.	Rudiger Drnbush, Stanley Fischer and Richard Startz, Macroeconomics, McGraw-Hill Irwin, Singapore.
        \n\n
         
        3.	M.C. Vaish, Macroeconomics, Allied Publishers Pvt Limited.
        \n\n\n\n\n

              
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name215">
        <b>2105   BUSINESS STATISTICS-2</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>1. Probability : </b> \n
        Meaning of Probability, Experiment, Events – Simple and Compound, Simple Space, Probability of events, Event 
        Relations, Independent and Dependent events, Probability laws, Bayes Theorem.
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. Random Variable : </b> \n
        Random variable, Discrete Random Variable, Continuous random variable, Probability distribution of discrete random 
        variable, Mathematical Expectations and variance of a discrete random variable.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Discrete Probability Distributions: </b> \n
        Binomial Probability Distribution and Poisson Probability Distribution. 
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. Continuous Probability Distributions:  </b> \n
        Normal Distribution, tabulated Area of the Normal Distribution, Normal Approximation to the Binomial Distribution.
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. Sampling and Sampling Distribution : </b> \n
        Sampling, Statistic and Parameters, types of Sampling, Sampling Distribution, Central limit Thermos, Sampling 
        distribution of the sample mean and proportion, sampling distribution of the difference between two sample means and 
        proportion.
        \n\n
        
        <b>6. Large Sample Estimation : </b> \n
        Point and Interval Estimation, reliability of point and Interval Estimation, point and Interval Estimation  of a 
        population mean and difference between two means, point and interval estimation of a binomial proportion and 
        difference between two proportions.
        \n\n
        
        <b>7. Large Sample Tests of Hypotheses : </b> \n
        Basic terminology, types 1 and type 2 errors, one tail and two tailed tests, testing hypotheses about population 
        mean and population, testing hypotheses about difference between two population means and proportion, use of p-values.
        \n\n
        
        <b>8. Small Sample : </b> \n
        Student\'s Distributions, small sample inference about population mean and the difference between two means, 
        paired difference tests, inferences about population variance (chi-square test), comparing two population 
        variance (F-distribution).
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Books : </b>
        \n\n
        
        1.	Richard I Levin and David S Rubin, Statistics for Management, Prentice-Hall.
        \n\n
        
        2.	S.P. Gupta &amp; M.P. Gupta, Business Statistic, Sultan Chand and Sons.
        \n\n\n\n\n

        
    </string>
</resources>