<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name411">
        <b>4101   HUMAN RESOURCE MANAGEMENT</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>1. Introduction: </b>\n
        Definition - Nature - Components - Functions - Reasons for Growing Importance of Human Resource Management — 
        Principles — Philosophies - Challenges.
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. Organizational Performance: </b> \n
        Factors - Organization Performance Models — Internal and External Environment.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Human Resource Planning: </b> \n
        Concepts — Purposes — Processes - Description of the Factors of the Process.
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. Job Analysis and Work Study: </b> \n
        Concepts - Definition - Terminologies — Importance Information required - Steps – Methods Writing Job 
        Descriptions and Specifications - Types - Contents - Drafts - Guidelines - Job Analysis in a Jobless World and 
        Reasons thereof - Techniques used to foster change.
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. Recruitment and Selection of Human Resources: </b> \n
        Concepts - Factors - Sources and their merits and demerits - Innovative sources of Recruitment - Recruitment Process 
        - Selection Process - Standard Selection Conditions. Reliability and Validity - Concepts - Steps to validate a test - 
        Guidelines to set a test program - sources of unreliability. Interview - Concept - Purpose - Process - Techniques 
        - Administrative Mechanism - Problems of Interviewing - Detection of dishonesty - Techniques to Avoid Interview 
        Mistakes.
        \n\n
        
        <b>6. Career Transition: </b> \n
        Orientation - Concepts - Reasons - Programs - Problems; Transfer - Concepts - Reasons - Types - Impacts; 
        Promotion - Concepts - Rationale - Types - Basis - Objectives - Devises of Promotion; Demotion - Definition - 
        Reasons - Impact - Techniques; Separation - Layoff - Concepts - Purpose - Problems.
        \n\n
        
        <b>7. Skill Training: </b> \n
        Concepts - Steps - Methods - Effectiveness Evaluation — Principles of Learning Theory.
        \n\n
        
        <b>8. Performance Evaluation</b> \n
        Concepts — Importance - Purposes — Process - Methods — Distortion Factors - Overcoming Pitfalls.
        \n\n
        
        <b>9. Wage and salary Administration:</b> \n
        Concepts — Goals — Considerations - Process; Job Evaluation - Concept - Steps - Methods - Current Issues.
        \n\n
        
        <b>10. Employee Benefits:</b> \n
         Concepts - Process - Goals - Importance - Benefits to Management.	
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Books</b>
        \n\n
        
        1.	 William. B Werther and Keith Davis, Human Resources and Personnel Management, Invin-McGraw Hill Co.
        \n\n
        
        2.	 Wendell L French, Human Resources Management, Houghton Mifflin Company.
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name412">
        <b>4102    MANAGEMENT ACCOUNTING </b> 
        \n\n
        
        <b>1. Introduction to Management Accounting: </b> \n
        Concepts of Management (Accounting, Role of Management Accountant in Organizations, Relations and Differences between 
        Financial Accounting. Management Accounting and Cost Accounting. Techniques of Management Accounting.
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. Cost Behavior: </b> \n
        Concepts Related to Costs, Separation of Fixed Cost and Variable Cost Elements of a Mixed Cost.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Costing Methods: </b> \n
        Income Measurement under variable and Absorption Costing, Uses of Variable Costing in Planning, Controlling and 
        Decision Making.
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. C-V-P and Break-even Analysis: </b> \n
        Computation of Break-even Point, Construction of Break-even Chart, Techniques used in C-V-P Analysis - 
        Break-even Analysis for Decision Making under changes in fixed cost, volume, price, sales mix and margin of safety.
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. Income Measurement under Direct Costing and Absorption Costing: </b> \n
        Uses of Direct Costing in Planning, Controlling and Decision Making.
        \n\n
        
        <b>6. Budget: </b> \n
        Different types of Budgets and their preparation, Sales Budget, Production Budget, Production Cost Budget, Cash 
        Budget, Master Budget.
        \n\n
        
        <b>7. Budgetary Control</b> \n
        1.	Meaning, Objectives, Essential Conditions, Benefits and Limitations, - Difference between Forecasting and Budget.
        \n\n
        
        <b>8. Segment Reporting, Profitability Analysis and Decentralization: </b> \n
        Segment Reporting, Level of Segment Statement, Costs and Revenues of Segments, Segment Margin, Customer Profitability 
        Analysis, Responsibility Accounting, Decentralization and Segment Reporting, Cost, Profit and Investment Centers, 
        Rate of Return for Measuring Managerial Performance, controlling the Rate of Return, Residual Income, Divisional 
        Comparison.
        \n\n
        
        <b>9. Relevant Information and Decision Making: </b> \n
        Qualitative Characteristics of Accounting Information, Meaning of Relevance, Special Sales Order, make or buy, 
        Deletion or Addition of Products in Product Line. Joint Product Cost, Irrelevance of Future costs.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Books</b> 
        \n\n
        
        1.	T. Horngren, G. Foster, and S. M. Datar, “Introduction To Management Accounting” (10th edition), Prentice Hall, 
        Inc.
        \n\n
        
        2.	 Pierre L Titard, Managerial Accounting.
        \n\n\n\n\n

        
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name413">
        <b>4103    PROJECT MANAGEMENT</b> 
        \n\n
        
        <b>1. Introduction: </b> \n
        Meaning and types of projects - Forces fostering project management — objectives of projects - project development 
        lifecycle.
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. Project Appraisal: </b> \n
        Market Appraisal - information required for market and demand analysis - demand forecasting. Technical appraisal — 
        material and inputs — machinery and equipment — structures and civil works - work schedules. Financial appraisal - 
        cost of project and means of financing - profitability - assessing tax burden - financial projections. Economic 
        appraisal - measuring cost and benefits- appraisal criteria - social cost benefit analysis.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Project Organization: </b> \n
        Project as par: of Organization - Pure Project Organization - Matrix Organization - Mixed Organizational system - 
        Human Factor and Project Team.
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. Project Planning: </b> \n
        Project Coordination - Systems Integration, Sorting out the Project - Work Breakdown structure.
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. Project Scheduling: </b>	\n
        Network techniques - PERT and CPM - Gantt Charts - Resource Allocation.
        \n\n
        
        <b>6. Project Control: </b> \n
        Fundamental purpose of control - Types of Control Processes - Control as Function of Management - Balance in a 
        Control System.
        \n\n
        
        <b>7. Project Termination: </b> \n
        Varieties of Termination process - when to terminate a project - Final report.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommended books</b>
        \n\n
        
        1. Jack R Meredith and Samuel J Mantel. Project Management — A Managerial Approach, John Wiley and sons.
        \n\n
        
        2. P Chandra, Projects: Preparation Appraisal Budgeting and implementing, Tata-McGraw-Hill
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
        
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name414">
        <b>4104    STRATEGIC MANAGEMENT</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>1. Introduction: </b> \n
        Evolution of the Concept of Strategy and Strategic Management - Definitions of Strategic Management - Relationship 
        between Strategy, Strategic Plan, and Strategic Management.
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. Strategic Management Process: </b> \n
        Establishing an Organization\’s Mission and Vision - Internal and External Environment Analysis (SWOT Analysis) - 
        Strategy Formulation — Strategy Implementation — Strategy Control.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Establishing Company Direction: </b> \n
        Relationship between Vision, Mission, Goals, and Objectives - Preparing Mission Statements — Establishing Objectives.
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. Strategic Analysis: </b> \n
        External — Industry and Competitive Analysis. Internal — Evaluating Company Resources and Competitive Capabilities.
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. Strategy Formulation: </b> \n
        Different Levels of Strategy - Operational Level - Business Level - Corporate Level - Global Level. Linking Strategies 
        with Ethical and Social Responsibilities.
        \n\n
        
        <b>6. Strategy Implementation: </b> \n
        Hardware and Software of Strategies - Building the Organization — Strengths and Capabilities - the Framework for 
        Implementing Strategies. - the Major Tasks - Implementation Process. Managing the Internal Organization to 
        Promote better Implementation - Linking Budget to Strategy - Creating Strategy supportive Policies and Procedures - 
        Installing Support Systems.
        \n\n
        
        <b>7. Strategic Control: </b> \n
        Different Tools and techniques of Control.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Books</b>
        \n\n
        
        1.	 Arthur Thomas and A J. Stickland, Strategic Management: Concepts , and Cases/McGraw Hills.
        \n\n
        
        
        2.	Alex Miller, Strategic Management, McGraw Hills.
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name415">
        <b>4105   MANAGEMENT INFORMATION SYSTEM</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>1. Foundation Concepts: </b> \n
        Basic information systems concepts and the operations, decision-making, and strategic roles of information systems. 
        Other behavioral, managerial, and technical concepts are presented where appropriate in other chapters.
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. Technology: </b> \n
        Major concepts, developments, and managerial implications involved in computer hardware, software, database 
        management, and telecommunications technologies. Other technologies used in computer-based information systems are 
        discussed where appropriate in selected chapters.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Applications: </b> \n
        How information technology is used in modem information systems to support end user collaboration, enterprise 
        operations, managerial decision-making, and strategic advantage, and artificial intelligence and expert systems.
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. Development: </b> \n
        Developing information system solutions to business problems using a systems approach to problem solving and 
        application development.
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. Management: </b> \n
        The challenges and methods of managing information systems technologies, activities, and resources, including 
        information resource management, global IT management, issues in planning and implementing change with IT, and 
        security and ethical challenges.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Books</b> \n
        \n
        
        1.	 James A O\’Brien, Management Information Systems - Managing IT in the Internetworked Enterprise, Fourth-edition, 
        McGraw-Hill.
        \n\n
        
        2.	Kenneth C Laudon and Jane P Laudon, Essentials of Management Information Systems, 5th edition, Prentice Hall.
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
</resources>