<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources> 
<string name="bba_subject_code_and_name111">
    <b>1101 INTRODUCTION TO BUSINESS</b>
    \n\n
    
    <b>1. Business Concepts: </b>
    \n
    
    Meaning of business – Basic Elements of Business – Basic Features of Business – Branches and their place in the Ecology 
    of Bangladesh – Business Environment – Business Size – Location of Business – Efficiency of Business – Social responsibility 
    of Business and its Implications.
    \n\n
    
    <b>2. Business Organizations: </b>
    \n
    
    Forms of business ownership in Bangladesh – Relative position of each form of ownership sole proprietorship, 
    partnership joint-stock company, Co- operatives and state ownership – Considerations in the choice of specific form of 
    ownership. 
    \n\n
    
    <b>3. Development of Joint-Stock Companies in Bangladesh: </b>
    \n
    
    Phases of development, Types Domain of operations of each type – Formation of Memorandum of Association and Article of 
    Association, prospectus – Rights and obligation of share holders, directors, and government – Liquidation of a company.
    \n\n
    
    <b>4. State Enterprises: </b>
    \n
    
    Historical background – Fields of state enterprise – Importance – Successes and Failures – Proposals for improvement.
    \n\n
    
    <b>5. Co-operative Societies in Bangladesh: </b>
    \n
    
    Their development – Types(industrial, commercial and service sector societies) – the role of each type – Formation - 
    problems and approaches to solve problems.
    
    \n\n
    
    <b>6. Institutions for Promotion of Business: </b>
    \n
    
    Support services of government institutions – Chamber of Commerce and Industry – Federation of Chambers of Commerce and 
    Industry – Trade Associations – The Dhaka Stock Exchange – Chittagong Stock Exchange – Board of Investment – 
    Privatization Board – Export Promotion Bureau – Bangladesh Small and Cottage Industries Corporation – Shilpa Bank – 
    Shilpa rin Sangstha – Export Processing Zone. 
    \n\n
    
    <b>7. Trade Practices in Bangladesh: </b>
    \n
    
    Commercial policy – Import procedure – Export procedure – Formalities – Problems and measures to overcome the problems – 
    Documents used in trade – LC Shipping Documents – Commercial Advice.
    \n\n\n
    
    <b>Recommended Books: </b>
    \n\n
    
    1. John M Ivancevich and Steven J Skinner, Business for the 21st Century, Irwin.
    \n\n
    
    2.A guide to Opportunity – Investment guide of Bangladesh, Board of Investment, Bangladesh.   
     \n\n\n\n\n
    
</string>    




<string name="bba_subject_code_and_name112">
    <b>1102 PRINCIPLE OF ACCOUNTING </b>
    \n\n
    
    <b>1. Introduction: </b> \n
    What is Accounting? Building Blocks of  Accounting – Ethics, Assumptions, Equations, Transaction Analysis, Financial 
    Statements.
    \n\n
    
    <b>2. Recording Process: </b>
    \n
    
    The Accounts, Steps in the recording Process, Journal, Ledger, Trial Balance.
    \n\n
    
    <b>3. Adjustment Process: </b>
    \n
    
    Timing Issues, Basics of Adjusting Entries, Adjusted Trial Balance and Financial Statement, Alternative Treatment of 
    prepaid Expenses and Unearned Revenues.
    \n\n
    
    <b>4. Completion of Accounting Cycle: </b> \n
    Using a Work sheet, Closing the Books, Reversing Entries and Correcting Entries, Classified Balance Sheet.
    \n\n
    
    
    <b>5. Accounting for Merchandising Operations: </b> \n
    Merchandising Operations, Recording Purchases of Merchandise, Recording sales of Merchandise, Completing Accounting Cycle, 
    Forms of Financial Statements – Multiple and Single Step Income Statement – Classified Balance Sheet, Work Sheet of a 
    Merchandiser.
    \n\n
    
    <b>6. Inventories: </b>
    Inventory Basics, Periodic Inventories System, Inventory Costing Under a Periodic Inventory System, LCM, Inventory Errors, 
    Statement Presentation and Analysis, LIFO, FIFO, Average cost Method.
    \n\n
    
    
    <b>7. Accounting Information System:  </b> \n
    Basic Concepts of Accounting Information Systems, Subsidiary Ledgers, Special Journals.
    \n\n
    
    <b>8. Internal Control and Cash: </b> \n
    Internal Control, Cash Control, Use of a Bank, Reporting Cash.
    \n\n\n
    
    
    <b>Book Recommended</b>
    1. Weygandt, D E Keiso, and P D Kimmel, Accounting Principles, 8th Edition, John Wiley and Sons, Inc.
    
    </string>
    


    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name113">
        <b>1103 INTRODUCTION TO COMPUTER</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>1. Historical Evaluations of Computer</b> \n
        An Overview of the Computer System – Relationship between system and technology – Components of computer systems – 
        Difference between hardware and software – Major types of software – Operating System Basics and Shapes of Computers 
        Today.
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. Processing and Representing Data: </b> \n
        Transforming data into information, text codes, conversion of text codes – Binary to decimal and decimal to binary, 
        logical diagram of CPUs and its components and functions.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Computer Hardware: </b> \n
        Types of computer hardware, types of  input devices, standard methods of input through keyboard, types of output 
        Devices, Monitors and sound systems, selection criteria of monitors, printers – types, functions of laser printers and 
        selection criteria of printer.
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. Storage Devices: </b> \n
        Types of storage devices, formatting a floppy, CDROM and hard disk, technologies of reading and writing data on and 
        from floppy disk and reading data from CD Rom, measuring drive performance.
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. Networks and Data Communications: </b> \n
        Uses of  networks, structure of network, Data transferring mechanism: Packet, Header, Payloads, Control Elements, 
        definition of protocol, layers of OSI model, topologies, networking media and hardware.
        \n\n
        
        <b>6. Internet and Online Resources: </b> \n
        History of  internet, how internet works, features of internet, accessing internet. 
        \n\n
        
        <b>7. Living with computers: </b> \n
        Computers and the individual – Ergonomics, piracy, virus – origin, prevention, hardware and data theft and other 
        ethical issues that affect us all. 
        \n\n
        
        <b>8. Word processing using MS word: </b> \n
        Creating and saving documents, editing, coping pasting, spelling and grammar checking, creating and manipulating table, 
        creating and footer, creating auto table of index and printing documents.
        \n\n
        
        <b>9. Spreadsheet using MS Excel: </b> \n
        Creating and saving worksheets, editing, coping, pasting, creating, formula, MS Excel functions, linking among sheets, 
        creating header and footer, creating charts and printing documents.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Books</b>
        \n\n
        
        1. Peter Norton, Introduction to Computers, Fourth Edition, Glencoe/McGraw-Hill.
        \n\n

        2. Lutfar Rahman, Alamgir, ComputerFundamentals, Systech Publications, Dhaka.
        \n\n
        
        3. Microsoft Office Professional, Microsoft Publications.
        \n\n\n\n\n 
        
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name114">
        
        
        <b>1104   BUSINESS MATHEMATICS </b>
        \n\n
        
        
        <b>1. Basic Concepts of Number: </b> \n
        
         Introduction, Prime, Rational and irrational numbers, even and odd numbers, imaginary and complex number.
         \n\n
         
         
         <b>2. Indices, Exponents and Logarithmic Functions: </b> \n
         Indices, laws of indices, positive and fractional indices with operations, logarithmic and natural logarithm. 
         \n\n
         
         <b>3. Theory of Sets: </b> \n
         Definition of set, different types of set, Union, different, intersection, Cartesian product, Venn diagram, 
         Application to business problems.
         \n\n
         
         <b>4. Linear and Quadratic Functions: </b> \n
         Solution of linear and simultaneous linear equations, Relationship between roots and co-efficient of a quadratic 
         equations, formation of quadratic equation with given roots, Sketching of different linear and non-linear equations.
         \n\n
         
         <b>5. Mathematics of Finance:  </b> \n
         Annuities, Sinking fund, discount, simple and compound interest, amortization, calculation of present and future 
         value of annuities.
         \n\n
         
         <b>6. Co-ordinate Geometry: </b> \n
         Cartesian co-ordinate system, distance between points, straight line, slopes, intercepts, Equation of cost line, 
         business applications.
         \n\n
         
         <b>7. Differential Calculus:  </b> \n
         Concepts, derivatives and differentiation of non-trigonometric functions – derivative of a function of one variable, 
         power  function, sum functions, product of two functions, quotient of two functions, functions of a function and 
         rate, measurement; Successive differentiation; Maxima and Minima; Business Applications.
         \n\n
         
         <b>8. Integral Calculus: </b> \n
         Meaning of integration, Rules of integration, Indefinite and definite integration, area determination, business 
         applications.
         \n\n\n
         
         <b>Recommended Books </b>
         \n\n
         
         1. D.C. Sancheti &amp; V.K. Kapoor. Business Mathematics, Sultan Chand and Sons.
         \n\n

         2. Gordon D Prichett and John C Saber, Mathematics with Application in Management &amp; Economics, Irwin Inc.
         \n\n\n\n\n
         
         
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name115">
        <b>1105  ENGLISH</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>1. Reading and Understanding:</b> \n
        Students are expected to read passages that they might come across in their everyday life to create understanding 
        about the different uses of language so that they can understand different purposes and types of reading, guess mean of 
        the words in context, understand long sentences, recognize main ideas and supporting ideas, answer comprehension 
        answers, and write summaries.
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. Writing: </b> \n
        To write correct sentences, complete sentences and combining sentences; Be able to write situational sentences for 
        posters, notices, slogans, memos, advertisements; Be able to right paragraph, understand structure of a paragraph, 
        topics of a sentence, develop ideas, write conclusions; Explain the types of paragraphs like narrative, descriptive, 
        expository, persuasive; explain the techniques of paragraph development; Newspaper writing like reports and press 
        release; Write resumes; Write letter both formal and informal; Request letters, job letters, complaint letters, etc; 
        Generate ideas for essay, outlines, introduction, main essay, conclusion.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Grammar: </b> \n
        Word order of Sentences, Framing Questions, Tense, Articles, Subject – Verb, Agreement, Noun – Pronoun Agreement, 
        Verbs, Phrases, Infinitives, Participles, Gerunds, Punctuation.
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. Developing Vocabulary: </b> \n
        Use of Dictionary, Suffixes, Prefixes, Synonyms, Antonyms, changing word forms and using them  in sentences. 
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. Translation from Bengali to English.</b>
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Books</b>
        \n\n
        
        1. P C Wrin and H Martin, HighSchool English Grammar and Composition, Sultan Chand and Company.
        \n\n

        2. A J Thomson and A V Martinet, A Practical English Grammar, Delhi Oxford University Press.
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
        
        

        
        
    </string>
    

</resources>






