<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name221">
        <b>2201    INSURANCE AND RISK MANAGEMENT </b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>1. Insurance : </b> \n
        The scope of insurance, origin, history and development of insurance, nature and function of insurance. 
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. Risk : </b> \n
        Types of risk, insurable risk, identification and management of risk. 
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Difference insurance policies : </b> \n
        Life, Fire, marine, liability .
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. Principles of Insurance : </b> \n
        Insurable interest, Indemnity, subrogation, contribution, Utmost good faith, Proximate cause.
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. Reinsurance.</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>6. Insurance market.</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>7. Insurance pricing.</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>8. Insurance Practices in Bangladesh.</b>
        \n\n\n
        
        
        
        
        <b>Recommend Books :</b>
        \n\n
        
        1.	Williams, Risk and Insurance. McGraw-Hill, India.
        \n\n
        
        2.	Azizul Huq Chaudhari, Elements of Insurance.
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name222">
        <b>2202    COST ACCOUNTING </b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>1. Nature of Cost Accounting : </b> \n
        Meaning, Objects, Importance and advantages of cost of accounting – essential of a cost accounting system- Relationship 
        between cost accounting and financial accounting- methods of costing – limitation of cost accounting.
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. Cost Concepts : </b> \n
        Cost terms – Expense – Classification of cost – preparation of cost sheet.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Materials : </b> \n
        Direct and indirect materials – Procurements of materials – Storage of materials – Materials record -  
        methods of valuing material issues – planning material requirements – stock levels – EOQ – Safety stock – 
        material control – ABC plan -  VED analysis – stock valuation – stock verification and adjustment.
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. Labour : </b> \n
        Labour cost control, recording of time -  methods of remuneration – incentive plans – wages calculation – 
        payments of wages – wages abstract.
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. Overhead : </b> \n
        Planning and control of overhead – predetermined factory overhead – methods of determining allocation ratios – 
        applied factory overhead – departmental allocation of factory overhead – actual factory overhead – over and under 
        applied factory overhead – analysis of variance – administrative, selling and distribution overheads – 
        applied and actual overhead – accounting for overheads – departmental rate – plan wise rate.
        \n\n
        
        <b>6. Job and Batch Costing : </b> \n
        nature and procedure of job and batch costing – determination of economics batch quantity.
        \n\n
        
        <b>7. Contract Costing : </b> \n
        Nature and procedure – contract account – notional profit – determination of profits and incomplete contract.
        \n\n
        
        <b>8. Process Costing : </b> \n
        Nature and application – physical flow – loss, spoilage, defective, scrap – equivalent procedure unit. 
        \n\n
        
        <b>9. Standard Costing Concepts : </b> \n
        Objective – setting of standards – analysis of material and labour variance and overhead variance, 
        significance of variance.
        \n\n
        
        <b>10. Cost Accounting Records : </b> \n
        Non Integral accounting system, journal entries, cost accounting ledger and control accounts, integral 
        accounting system, advantages, disadvantage  journal entries and ledger accounts.
        \n\n
        
        <b>11. Reconciliation of Cost Accounting Profit and Financial accounting Profit : </b> \n
        Reason for variations, treatment of items, need for Reconciliation, Reconciliation statement, Memorandum 
        Reconciliation Account.
        \n\n
        
        <b>12. Operational Costing  : </b> \n
        Basic principals, conditions necessary for it\'s success, accounting records, Transport costing, Staff, Canteen 
        costing, hotel costing, powerhouse costing, hospital costing.
        \n\n\n
        
        
        <b>Recommend Books :</b>  
        \n\n
        
        1.	Polimemeni, Cost Accounting, The World Press Private Ltd.
        \n\n
        
        2.	Matz and Usry , Cost Accounting, The World Press Private Ltd.
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name223">
        <b>2203    COMPUTER PROGRAMMING </b>
        \n\n
        
       <b>1. Evaluation of Programming :</b> \n
       History and evolution of computer language and difference types of program.
       \n\n
       
       <b>2. Fundamental Concepts of Computer Programming and terminology : </b> \n
       Algorithms and its notations, Flow charts, Functions, constant, variables and data types. Expressions, selections 
       statements, arrays, records and pointers, general sub procedure, lists, stacks, queues and recursions, loop 
       structure, trees, sorting and searching and data files.
       \n\n
       
       <b>3. Designing and Creating a Relation database with MS Access 2000 or above : </b> \n
       Tables – Attributes, keys, Indexes, Relationship, Queries – select, insert, delete, append, parameter, Wizards;  
       Forms- Wizards, controls, sub forms; reports – wizards, custom macros - actions, conditions, function; code behind 
       forms and expressions.
       \n\n\n
       
       <b>Recommend Books :</b>
       \n\n
       
       1.	Seymour Lipschutz, Data Structure. Schaum\'s outline series, McGraw-Hill.
       \n\n
       
       2.	Andersen, Peter Norton, Guide to Access 2000 Programming, Sams Publishers.
       \n\n\n\n\n
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name224">
        <b>2204    COMMERCIAL LAW</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>1. Law of Contract : </b> \n
        Definition of a Contract- essential elements of a contract – offer – acceptance – considerations – void and 
        voidable agreements – capacity of parties – free consent – Legality of object and consideration – contingent 
        contract – performance of contracts  - terminology and discharge of Contracts – indemnity &amp; guarantee – 
        Bailsment and pledge.
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. Law of Relating to Negotiable Instruments : </b> \n
        Definition- acceptance and negotiation – rights and Liabilities of Parties – Dishonor of Negotiable instruments.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Laws Related to Sales of Goods : </b> \n
        Definitions, Transfer of Ownership, Performance of the contract of sales. 
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. The Company Act 1994 : </b> \n
        Definition, Characteristics, types Memorandum – Contents and clauses, alteration, ultra vires, article of 
        association – purpose, content, alteration; formations of company – steps, procedure of registrations and 
        incorporation, Certification of incorporation, promoters; prospectus : contents, misrepresentation, omission, 
        statement in lieu of prospectus; directors – appointment, Qualification, powers and duties, removal, vacation of 
        office, Remuneration, managing director; Meetings – Statutory Meetings, Statutory report, annual meeting, extraordinary 
        general meeting, resolutions, minutes of proceeding; winding up – winding up by the court, 
        voluntary winding up, winding up subject to the supervision of the court, appointment of official liqueidators.
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. Partnership Act : </b> \n
        Nature of partnership, Rights and liberalities of Prtners and Dissolution of Firms.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommend Books : </b>
        \n\n
        
        1.	Sen, A.K. and Mitra, J.K., Commercial Law including Company Law and Industrial Law, The World Press 
        Limited, Calcutta.
        \n\n
        
        2.	The Company Act, 1994.
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name225">
        <b>2205    THEORY AND PRACTICE OF BANKING</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>1. Banker : </b> \n
        Customer Relationship.
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. </b>	Banker as agent; trustee; executor and administrator.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. </b>	Negotiable Instrument Act; Payments and Collections of promissory notes, bills and cheques.
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. </b>	Investment in securities; Loans and Advances.
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. </b>	Loans and advances; Cash credit; overdrafts; Different forms of loans with and without collateral, securities 
        and guarantees. Securities and conditions for acceptable securities.
        \n\n
        
        <b>6. Lending Policy : </b> \n
        Sound Lending policy, Factors to be considered at the time of Sanctioning Loans, which type of loan will be 
        considered as good loan and which type of loan will be considered as bad loan, Areas for using bank\'s funds.
        \n\n
        
        <b>7. Payments Instruments : </b> \n
        Details about different types of payment instruments, cheques, types of crossing, cancellation of crossing.
        \n\n
        
        <b>8. Crossing of cheques :  </b> \n
        Significance of crossing, importance and application of crossing, types of crossing, cancellation of crossing.
        \n\n
        
        <b>9. </b>Banking company Act, Money Laundering Act, Artho-Rin Adalat Act.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommend Books :</b>
        \n\n
        
        1.	A R Khan, Fundamentals of Banking, S S Publishers.
        \n\n
        
        2.	 M I Tanan, Banking Law and Practices.
        \n\n
        
        3.	Mentioned Act.
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
    </string>
</resources>