<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name121">
        <b>1201   BUSINESS COMMUNICATION</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>1. Introduction to Communication : </b> \n
        Meaning – Importance – Uses, Factors affecting Communication, Cultural Orientation in Communication. 
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. Types of Communication: </b> \n
        Written, Oral and Non-verbal Communication. 
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Written Communication: </b> \n
        Purpose, Content and Structure.
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. Major Media of Written Communication: </b> \n
        Letters, Memos, Reports – How to write good business letters, memos, report, style and structure – Advantages and 
        disadvantages of different media.
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. Oral Communication: </b> \n
        Importance, use, preparation, delivery, style of delivery.
        \n\n
        
        <b>6. Major media of Oral Communication: </b> \n
        Speech, face-to-face conversation, interviews, meetings, telephonic conversation – Advantages and Disadvantages of 
        Differential Media-Dos and Don\’t in Oral Communication.
        \n\n
        
        <b>7. Non- verbal Communication: </b> \n
        Symbols, Gestures, Nods, Body Language, etc. Visual Aids in Communication.
        \n\n
        
        <b>8. Internal Communication: </b> \n
        Upward Communication, Downward Communication and Lateral Communication Media used in Internal Communicational. 
        \n\n
        
        <b>9. Effective Meeting: </b> \n
        Preparation, Conduction, Strategy and Follow- up- Agenda and Minutes-Effective versus Ineffective groups, Small Group 
        Communication.
        \n\n
        
        <b>10. Business Reports: </b> \n
        Characteristics, Importance and types of report; Structure of reports – Front Matters, Main Body and Back Matters; 
        preparatory steps to writing reports – purpose and scope, determining the audience – Collecting data – Organizing 
        materials – Elements of Style – Writing the report – Oral presentation.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Books</b>
        \n\n
        
        1. Betty and Kay, Business Communication System &amp; Application.
        \n\n
        
        2. Raymond V. Lesiker, Basic Business Communication, McGraw Hills.
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name122">
        <b>1202   INTERMEADIATE ACCOUNTING </b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>1. Conceptual Framework Underlying Financial Accounting: </b> \n
        Conceptual Framework, Basic Objectives, Fundamental Concepts, Recognition and Measurement Concepts. 
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. Receivables: </b> \n
        Recognition and Valuation of Accounts Receivables, Recognition and Valuation of Notes Receivables, Disposition of 
        Accounts and Notes Receivables, Presentation and Analysis.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Acquisition and Disposition of Property, Plant and Equipment: </b> \n
        Acquisition of property, Plant and Equipments, Valuation, Costs Subsequent to Acquisition, Disposition of Plant 
        and analysis.
        
        <b>4. Depreciation, Impairments and Disposition: </b> \n
        Depreciation, Impairments, Depletion, Presentation and analysis.
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. Intangible Assets:  </b> \n
        Intangible Assets Issues, Specifically Identifiable Intangibles, Goodwill, Impairment of Intangible Assets, R &amp; 
        D Costs, Presentation of Intangibles and Related costs.
        \n\n
        
        <b>6. Current Liabilities and Contingencies:  </b> \n
        Liability, Current Liability, Gain Contingencies, Loss Contingencies, Presentation and Analysis.
        \n\n
        
        <b>7. Revenue Recognition: </b> \n
        Guidelines, Revenue Recognition at Point of Sales, Before Delivery and After Delivery.
        \n\n
        
        <b>8. Accounting for Leases: </b> \n
        Basics of Leases, Accounting by Leesee and Lessor, Special Accounting Problems.
        \n\n\n
        
        
        <b>Recommended Book </b>
        \n\n
        
        1. D E Keiso and J J Weygandt, Intermediate Accounting, John Wiley and sons, Inc.
        \n\n\n\n\n
       
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name123">
        <b>1203   PRINCIPLE  OF MANAGEMENT</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>1. Introduction: </b> \n
        Definition – Functions – Principles of Management – Levels of Management – Skills Required – Managerial Responsibilities 
        and Roles – Effective Management – Balancing Effectiveness and Efficiency.
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. Approaches to the Study of Management: </b> \n
        Pre-classical contributors – Classical Viewpoint – Contemporary Viewpoint – Management Theory Jungle.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Planning: </b> \n
        Design for Tomorrow\’s Action – Types of Planning – Steps of Planning Process – Forecasting – Planning and Time – 
        Pervasiveness of Planning – Flexibility – of Plans – Planning Premises.
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. Decision Making: </b> \n
        Decision Making Premise – Approaches to Decision Making – Steps in Decision Making Process – Decision Making under 
        Conditions of Certainty, Risk, and Uncertainty.
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. Organizing:  </b> \n
        Orderly Arrangement  of Group Effort – Departmentation  - Staffing – Delegation of Authority – Decentralization and 
        Centralization – Organization. Structure – Span of Management – Use of Committee.
        \n\n
        
        <b>6. Leading : </b> \n
        Influencing People – Direction – Participation – Motivation – Leadership – Manager and Leader.
        \n\n
        
        <b>7. Controlling: </b> \n
        The Steering Function – Steps in the Control Process – Control Methods – Control Tolerance Limit – Link between 
        Planning and Controlling. 
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Books</b>
        \n\n
        
        1. Ricky W Griffin, Management, Houghton Mifflin Company.
        \n\n
        

        2. Heinz Weihrich and Harold Koontz, Management, Mcgraw-Hill, Inc.
        \n\n\n\n\n
       
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name124">
        <b>1204    MICRO ECONOMICS  </b> 
        \n\n
        
        <b>1. Introduction: </b> \n
        Definition, Microeconomics vs. Macroeconomics, scope of economics, meaning of economics theory, some basic concepts 
        – product, commodity, want, utility, consumption, factors of production.
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. Demand: </b> \n
        Law of demand, factors determining demand, shifts in demand functions, deriving demand curves, substitution and 
        income effects, deriving aggregate demands, various concepts of demand elasticity and measurements, discussion on 
        the methods of estimating demand functions and demand forecasting.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Supply: </b> \n
        Law of supply and supply function, determinants of supply, shifts in supply, elasticity of supply, market equilibrium. 
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. Economic Theory of Consumer Behavior: </b> \n
        Reasons for Consumption, Principles of Diminishing Marginal Utility, Indifference Curves, Budget Constraint, Utility 
        Maximization and Consumer Equilibrium.
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. Consumer Demand:  </b> \n
        Changes in Budget Constraints, Price Consumption Curve, Income Consumption Curve, Consumer Demand, Market Demand, 
        Engel Curve.
        \n\n
        
        <b>6. Production: </b> \n
        Production functions, total, average and marginal products, law of diminishing marginal physical products, 
        production isoquants, marginal rate of technical substitution (MRTS), optimal combination of inputs, expansion path, 
        returns to scale, estimation of production function and efficiency criterion.
        \n\n
        
        <b>7. Cost: </b> \n
        Concepts of cost, short- run costs, relation between short- run costs and production, long-run costs, economics and 
        diseconomies of scale, relation between short- run and long-run costs, cost function and estimation of cost function.
        \n\n
        
        <b>8. Markets and Revenue: </b> \n
        Meaning of market, different forms of market, concepts of total, average and marginal revenge, relation between 
        average revenue and marginal revenue curves, relation between different revenues and elasticity\’s of demand, 
        equilibrium of the firm.
        \n\n
        
        <b>9. Price and Output: </b> \n
        Price and output determination under perfect competition, monopoly, monopolistic competition and oligopoly, 
        profit maximization, price discrimination, plant shut down decision, barriers to entry.
        \n\n\n
        
        
        <b>Recommended Books</b>
        \n\n
        
        1. Paul A Samuelson and Willaim D Naurdhus, “Economics”. McGraw Hill Book Co., New York,(USA).
        \n\n
        

        2. Farguson and Gould, Micro Economics.
        \n\n
        

        3. K.K Dewett,  Modern Economics Theory,  S. Lac Charitable Trust, New Delhi.
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
       
    </string>
    
    
    
    <string name="bba_subject_code_and_name125">
        <b>1205     BUSINESS STATICTICS - I </b> 
        \n\n
        
        <b>1. Introduction:</b> \n
        Definition, nature and Scope of Statistics, Functions &amp; limitation, Use of Statistics in business.
        \n\n
        
        <b>2. Collection, Procession and Presentation of Business Data: </b>
        \n
        
        Collection of primary and secondary data, Classification, types of classification, frequency distribution, 
        cumulative frequency distribution, diagrammatic and graphical representation of data.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. Measures of Central Tendency:  </b> \n
        Mean, Median, Mode, Geometric  Mean and Harmonic Mean – their computation and properties.
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. Measures of Dispersion:  </b> \n
        Absolute and Relative Measures of Dispersion, their computation &amp; properties.
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. Moments, Skewness and Kurtosis: </b> \n
        Definitions, their computations and uses in business.
        \n\n
        
        <b>6. Correlation and Regression: </b> \n
        Concept of correlation and regression, their computation, fitting of regression lines. 
        \n\n
        
        <b>7. Time Series Analysis: </b> \n
        Concepts, Components of time series. The trend, Fitting of trend by least square method and moving average method, 
        uses of time series in business.
        \n\n
        
        <b>8. Index Number : </b> \n
        Definition – Problems for construction, Construction of price, quantity, value and cost of living index numbers, 
        ideal index, tests and uses of index numbers.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Books</b>
        \n\n
        
        1. Richard I Levin and David S Rubin. Statistics for Management, Prentice- Hall India.
        \n\n
        
        2. S.P. Gupta &amp; M.P. Gupta, Business Statistics,  Sultan Chand and Sons.
        \n\n\n\n\n
       
    </string>
    
    
    
</resources>