<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<resources>
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name121">
        <b>CSE-121  Data Structure</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Introduction:</b> \n Basic Terminology; Elementary Data Organization; Data Structures; Data Structure Operations; 
        Control Structures; Algorithms: Complexity, Time-Space Tradeoff, Mathematical Notation and function, String Processing: 
        String Operations, word processing, and Pattern Matching Algorithms.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Arrays, Records and Pointers:</b> \n Linear Arrays; Representation of linear array in memory; Traversing linear arrays, 
        Inserting and Deleting; Sorting; (Bubble sort), Searching (linear, binary), Multidimensional Arrays; Pointer Arrays; 
        Record Structures;  Matrices.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Linked lists:</b> \n Representation of Linked lists in memory, Traversing a linked list, Searching a linked list, 
        insertion, deletion; Header and two-way lists. 
        \n\n
        
        <b>Stacks, Queues, Recursion:</b> \n Array Representation of Stacks, Polish Notation; Quicksort, Recursive definition; 
        Towers of Hanoi, Implementation of Recursive procedures, Queue Dequeue, Priority Queues.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Trees:</b> \n Binary Trees; Representing Binary Trees in memory, traversing binary tree, Header Nodes; Threads , 
        binary search trees, Heap tree, heap sort, Huffman\’s Algorithm.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Graphs:</b> \n Sequential Representation of Graph; Adjacency Matrix; Path Matrix; Warshall\’s Algorithm; 
        Linked representation of Graphs.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Reference book:</b>
        \n\n
        
        
        1.	Seymour Lipschutz ( Schaum\’s  outline series), Data Structure (International Edition)
        \n\n
        
        2.	Ellis Horowitz &amp; Sartaj Sahni, Data Structure and Algorthm.
        \n\n
        
        3.	Robers L Kruse, Data Structure &amp; Programming Design, 2nd Ed.
        \n\n\n\n\n
    
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name122">
        <b>CSE-122 Data Structure Practical</b>
        \n\n
        
        Laboratory works based on CSE-121
        \n\n
        
        Operation on array of character (Single character, substring insertion, deletion, counting, find, etc), Usage of 
        built-in string function declared in STRING.H file, Declaration and use of single/ multiple structure/ record type 
        variables, Searching algorithms (Linear, Binary), Sorting Algorithms (Bubble, insertion, merge, Quick), Usage of 
        pointer variable and memory allocation, Usage of address arithmetic, Usage of call by reference variable, Usage of 
        pointer in structure variables and implementation as link list, Operation on one-way link list (Creation, display, 
        insertion, deletion, append etc.), Declaration and operation on stack (Push, Pop) and queue (Dequeue), Recursive 
        function (Towers Hanoi), Binary tree implementation, Infix, prefix, postfix transformation using array, Traversing 
        techniques (In-order, preorder, post-order), Calculation of paths and nodes as well as height of a graph and tree,
         Advanced sorting technique (Heap sort).
        \n\n\n\n\n        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name123">
        <b>CSE-123   Introduction to Electrical Engineering</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Ohm\’s law, Power and Energy:</b> \n Conductance and conductivity, Ohm\’s Law, Power, Wattmeter, Efficiency, Energy, 
        Circuit Breaker\’s, GFCIS and Fuses, Effect of Temperature on resistance
        \n\n
        
        <b>Series Circuits:</b> \n Introduction, Voltage Sources in Series, Kirchoff\’s Voltage Law, Resistances is Series, 
        Voltage Divider rule, Voltage regulation.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Parallel circuits:</b> \n Introduction, kirchoff\’s current law, Current divider rule, Voltage source in parallel, 
        Open and short circuits, Voltmeter.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Method of analysis:</b> \n Source conversion, Maxwell\’s loop Current method, Mesh Analysis with matrix form, 
        Nodal analysis with voltage source, Nodal analysis with current source.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Network theorem:</b> \n Delta star conversion, Superposition theorem, Thevenin\’s theorem, Norton\’s theorem, Maximum 
        power transfer theorem.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Laws:</b> \n Ampere\’s law, Biot-Savart law, Induction and Inductance, Magnetic properties of matter, 
        Inductors and transformers, AC and DC networks, DC and AC powers, instantaneous and r.m.s value: Current, 
        voltage and power, average power for various combinations of R, L and C circuits, phasor representation.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Reference Books:</b>
        \n\n
        
        
        1. Boylested, Introductory Circuit and Analysis.
        \n\n
        
        2. B.L.Theraja,AText book of Electrical Technology
        \n\n
        
        3. David Halliday and Robert Resin, Physics Part-II
        \n\n\n\n\n

    </string>
    
    
    
    
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name124">
        <b>CSE-124 Introduction to Electrical Engineering Practical</b>
        \n\n
        
        Laboratory works based on CSE-123.
        \n\n
        
        Verification of ohm\’s law and measurement of Resistivity of a Metallic wire, To verify Kirchhoff\’s Current law and 
        kirchhoff\’s Voltage law, To verify Thevenen\’s theorem, To verify Norton\’s theorem, To verify Superposition 
        theorem, To study R-C circuit and to find out the time constant, To study the R-L-C series Resonance circuit.
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name125">
        <b>CSE-125 Integral Calculus and Differential Equation</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Indefinite Integrals as Inverse of Derivatives:</b> \n Techniques of integration; Definite integral as limit of a 
        sum; Interpretation as area; Fundamental theorem of integral calculus (for continuous functions); Determination of 
        length and area of plain curve; Volume and surface area of revolution.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Introduction to linear, Nonlinear and Inhomogeneous Differential Equations:</b> \n Solutions of ordinary differential 
        equations; Solutions by the method of variation of parameters and indetermined coefficients.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Differential Equations:</b> \n Power series solutions about singular points; Solutions of partial differential 
        equations by the method of separation of variables.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Reference Books:</b>
        \n\n
        
        
        1.	Dr. Abdul Matin, Integral Calculus.
        \n\n
        
        2.	B.C Das &amp; B.N Mukherjee, Integral Calculus.
        \n\n
        
        3.	Abu Yusuf, Differential Equations.
        \n\n
         
        4.	Dr. Abdul Matin, Differential Equations.
        \n\n\n\n\n
              
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name126">
        <b>CSE-126 Statistics and Probability </b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Elements of Statistics:</b> \n Nature and scope of statistics, Nature &amp; representation of statistical data; 
        Attributes and variables; discrete and continuous variables; Method of data collection.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Measures of location:</b> \n Characteristics of an ideal measure; Arithmetic mean; Geometric mean; Harmonic mean; 
        Median; Mode; Quartiles; Deciles; Percentiles.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Measure of dispersion:</b> \n Characteristics of an ideal measure: Absolute &amp; Relative measures; Range; Standard 
        deviation; Mean deviation; Quartile deviation; Coefficient of dispersion; Coefficient of variation; Skew ness and 
        kurtosis.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Elements of Probability:</b> \n Meaning and definition of probability; A priori and a posteriori probability; Basic 
        terminology of probability; Random variables; Probability function; Expectation of sum and products.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Regression and correlation:</b> \n Relationship between variables; Fitting of regression lines; Simple correlation; 
        Multiple correlation and regression. 
        \n\n
        
        <b>Sampling:</b> \n Sampling Techniques &amp; its role, different types of sampling &amp; its merits &amp; Demerits.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Tests of Significance:</b> \n Tests of means, Variance, Correlation coefficient and regression coefficient.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Probability Distribution:</b> \n Binomial Distribution, its uses and properties, Poisson Distribution, its uses and 
        properties, Normal Distribution, its uses and properties.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Reference Books:</b> 
        \n\n
        
        
        1. M. Nurul Islam, An introduction to Statistics.
        \n\n
         
        2. M.G. Mostafa, Methods of statistics.
        \n\n
        
        3. Md Abdul Aziz, Business Statistics.
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name127">
        <b>CSE-127 Discrete Mathematics</b>
        \n\n
        
        Set Theory, Relations, Functions, Graph Theory, Planer Graph and Trees, Direct graphs and Binary Trees, Algebraic 
        Systems, Ordered sets and lattices, Propositional Calculus, Boolean Algebra, Lattices, group theory, cyclic groups, 
        permutation groups, symmetry groups, quotient, homomorphism, Basic structure theory, Prepositional and Predicate logic, 
        Mathematical reasoning and program techniques. Theories with induction. Counting and countability. Graph and trees. 
        Morphisms, Algebraic structures.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Reference Books :</b>
        \n\n
        
        
       1.	K.H. Rosen, Discrete Mathematics and Its Applications, McGraw Hill,4th ED 2000. 
       \n\n
       	
       2.	O. Nicodemi, Discrete Mathematics CBS, 1989. 
       \n\n
       
       3.	J. C. Molluzzo and F.Buckley( Waveland Press, reprinted 1997) ISBN 0-8833-9407
       \n\n\n\n\n
      
    </string>
    
    
    
    
</resources>