<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<resources>
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name211">
        <b>CSE-211  Object Oriented Programming</b>
        \n\n
        
        Principles of Object-Oriented Programming; Beginning with C++; Tokens, Expressions and Control Structure; Functions 
        in C++; Classes and objects; Constructors and Destructors; Operator Overloading and Type conversions; Inheritance: 
        Extending classes; Pointers, Virtual Functions and Polymorphism; Managing console I/O operations; Working with Files; 
        Exception Handling; Template functions and classes; Multi-threaded Programming. Introduction to java, comparison 
        between java and c++.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Reference Books:</b>
        \n\n
        
        1. E Balagurusamy  “Object- oriented programming with C++”.
        \n\n
         
        2. Robert Lafore “Turbo C++”.
        \n\n
        
        3. Herbert Schildt “Turbo C++, The complete Reference”.
        \n\n
        
        4. Herbert Schildt “ Teach Yourself C++ “.
        \n\n\n\n\n
    
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name212">
        <b>CSE-212 Object Oriented Programming Language Practical</b>
        \n\n
        
        Laboratory works based on CSE-211
        \n\n
        
        Review of C Programming; Use of C++ Editors/ compilers; Basic C++ input and output statements; Functions 
        (Call by Reference, Function Overloading Friend and virtual function, inline function, default arguments etc); 
        Classes and Objects (Built-in and user-defined) (private, Public, Protected members); Constructor and Destructor 
        (With multiple constructor); Arrays of objects and within class; Static data members and member functions; Dynamic 
        and copy constructor; Operator overloading (Unary, binary, string); Different types of inheritance(with access 
        specifiers); Virtual base class; Pointers (this, reference,…), Polymorphism, Dynamic binding; File 
        processing(Create, read, write and update files sequential access and random access file processing); 
        Development of Integrated software using multiple C++ feature; Some problems on Numerical Analysis 
        (Solution of Linear equation, Iterative method of root finding, Least-square curve fitting, etc.).
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name213">
        <b>CSE-213 Operating System</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Introduction:</b> Definition OS, Mainframe, desktop systems, multiprocessor Systems, distributed systems, 
        clustered systems, real-time systems, handheld systems, computing environments.
        \n\n
        
        <b>OS Structures:</b> System components, OS services, system calls, system programs, system structure, virtual 
        machines, system design and implementation.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Processes:</b> Process concept, Process state, Process control block, threads, Process scheduling, operation on 
        processes, cooperating Processes, interprocesses communication, Communication in client-server system.
        \n\n
        
        <b>CPU scheduling:</b> Basic concepts, CPU-I/O bust cycle, CPU scheduler, preemptive scheduling, dispatcher, 
        scheduling criteria, Scheduling algorithms, multiple-processor scheduling, real-time scheduling ,algorithm evaluation, 
        process scheduling models: ex-windows 2000, Linux.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Process Synchronization:</b> Background Process Synchronization ,critical section problem, semaphore, 
        classical problems of synchronization, critical regions, OS Synchronization ,Atomic transaction.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Deadlocks:</b> System model, Dead Lock characterization, Methods for handling Deadlock, Deadlock Avoidance, Dead 
        Lock Detection, Recovery from Dead lock.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Memory management:</b> Background: Address binding, Logical vs Physical Address Space, Dynamic Loading, Dynamic 
        Linking and Shared Libraries, Overlays, Swapping, Contiguous Memory Allocation, Paging, Segmentation, Segmentation with 
        paging.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Virtual Memory:</b> Background of Virtually Memory (VM). Demand Paging, Process Creation, Page Replacement, 
        Different Page, Replacement Algorithms, Thrashing: Working Set Model, Page-Fault Frequency
        \n\n
        
        <b>File Concept:</b> File Attributes, File Operations, File Types, File Structure, File Access Methods, Directory 
        Structure, file System Mounting, File Sharing, File Protection.
        \n\n
        
        <b>File System Implementation:</b> File System Structure, File System Implementation, Overview, Partitions and 
        Mounting Virtual File Systems, Directory Implementation, Allocation Methods, Free-Space Management, Recovery: 
        Consistency Checking, Backup and Restore Log-Structure File System.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Reference Book:</b>
        \n\n
        
        
        1. Silberschatz, Galvin, Peterson, Operating system Concepts, sixth Edition.
        \n\n
        
        2.A.S.Tanenbaum,OS,Prentice Hall
        \n\n
        
        3. P.B. Hausen,OS Concepts, Prentice Hall.
        \n\n
        
        4. S. Madnick and J.Donovon, OS, McGraw Hill.
        \n\n\n\n\n

    </string>
    
    
    
    
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name214">
        <b>CSE-214 Digital Logic Design</b>
        \n\n
        
        Introductory concept, number systems and codes, Boolean algebra, De Morgan\’s theorems, logic gates and their truth 
        tables, combinational logic circuits, karnaugh map method, digital arithmetic, operations and circuits, decoder, 
        encoder, multiplexer, and demultiplexer, Flip flop and related devices, race around problems, Asynchronous and 
        synchronous counters and their applications, MSI logic circuits, interfacing with analog world: D/A converter 
        circuitry, A/D converter circuitry.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Reference Books:</b>
        \n\n
        
        1. Ronald J. Tocci &amp; Neal S. Widmer, Digital Systems Principal and Application.
        \n\n
        
        2. R P Jain, Modern Digital Electronics.
        \n\n
        
        3. William I. Fletcher, An Engineering Approach to Digital Design.
        \n\n
        
        4. M. Morris Mano, Digital Logic and Computer Design.
        \n\n\n\n\n
    
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name215">
        <b>CSE-215 Digital Logic Design Practical</b>
        \n\n
        
        Laboratory works based on CSE-214.
        \n\n
        
        Minimize and Implementation of Boolean Functions Using Logic Gates, Design Half Adder and Full Adder, Design Half 
        Subtractor and Full Subtractor, Verify the Truth Table of S-R, T, D Flip-Flop, Verify the Truth Table of J-K, 
        Prepare Different Type Shift Resister and Check Its Operation, Design Synchronous Counter, 
        Design Asynchronous Counter, Design Ripple Counter, Design Johnson and Ring counter, Verify the Operation of Encoder 
        and Decoder, Verify the Operation of Multiplexer, De-Multiplexer, Verify the Operation of D/A and A/D Converter.
        \n\n\n\n\n 
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name216">
        <b>CSE-216 Mathematics for CSE</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Theory of Matrices:</b> Types of matrices (Creditary, hermitian, symmetric etc.); Determinant of a square matrix; 
        Equivalence, Adjoint and inverse of a square matrix; Linear equations; The characteristic roots and the characteristic 
        equation of a matrix; Linear transformation. Similarity transformations.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Vector Algebra:</b> Scalars and vectors, equality of vectors; Addition and subtraction of vectors; Multiplication 
        of vectors by scalars; scalar and vector product of two vectors and their geometrical interpretations; triple products 
        and multiple products; liner dependence and independence of vectors.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Vector calculus:</b> Differentiations and integration of vectors together with elementary applications; 
        Definition of line, surface and volume integrals; Gradient, divergence and curl of point functions, various formulae, 
        Gauss\’s theorem, Stoke\’s theorem, Green\’s theorem.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Fourier Analysis:</b> Real and Complex form of Fourier series; Finite transform; Fourier Integral; Fourier transforms 
        and their uses in solving boundary value problems of wave equations.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Laplace Transform:</b> Definition; Laplace transforms of some elementary functions; sufficient conditions for 
        existence of Laplace transforms; Inverse Laplace transforms; Laplace transforms of derivatives. The unit step function; 
        Periodic function; Some special theorems on Laplace transforms; Partial fraction; Solutions of differential equations 
        by Laplace transforms; Evaluation of improper integrals.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Reference Books:</b>
        \n\n
        
        
        1.	Md. Abdur Rahman, Mathematical Methods.
        \n\n
        
        2.	Matrices, A.R. Vasishtha.
        \n\n
          
        3.	Khosh Mohammad, Vector analysis.
        \n\n\n\n\n
      
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name217">
        <b>CSE-217 Electronic Devices and Circuits</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Semiconductor Diodes:</b> Semiconductor Materials, Energy levels, Entrinsic Materials- n-Type and p-Type, 
        Semiconductor Diode, Ideal Diode, Diode Equivalent Circuit, Transition and Diffusion Capacitance.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Diode Application:</b> Sinusoidal Inputs: Half Wave Rectification. Full Wave Rectification,  Clippers, Clampers, 
        Zener Diode, LED.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Bipolar Junction Transistor (BJT):</b> Transistor Construction, Transistor Operation, Common-Base Configuration, 
        Transistor Amplifying Action, Common Emitter Configuration, Common Collector Configuration, Limits of  Operation.
        \n\n
        
        <b>DC Biasing – BJTs:</b> Operating Point, Fixed Biased Circuit, Voltage - Divider Bias. DC Bias with Voltage Feedback, 
        Miscellaneous Bias Configuration, Bias Stabilization.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Field Effect Transistor (FET):</b> Construction And Characteristics of JEFT Transfer Characteristics, Depletion 
        Type MOSFET, Enhancement Type MOSFET.
        \n\n
        
        <b>FET Biasing:</b> Fixed – Biased Configuration, Self - Bias Configuration, Voltage – Divider Biasing.
        \n\n
        
        <b>BJT Transistor Modeling:</b> Amplification in the Ac Domain, The Hybrid Equivalent Model, Graphical Determination of 
        h-parameters.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Operational Amplifiers:</b> Differential and Common-Mode Operation, Op-amp Basics. Practical Op-amp Circuit, Op-amp 
        Specifications-DC Offset Parameters, Op-amp Specifications-Frequency Parameters, Op-amp Unit Specifications.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Op-amp Applications:</b> Voltage Summing, Voltage Buffer, Instrumentations Circuit, Active filters.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Feedback and Oscillator Circuits:</b> Feedback Concepts, feedback Connection Type, Practical Feedback Circuit, 
        Feedback Amplifier – Phase and Frequency Consideration, Oscillator Operation, Phase-Shift Oscillator, Wien – Bridge 
        Oscillator, Crystal Oscillator.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Other semi-conductor devices:</b> Thermistors, Tunnel diode, LED &amp; GUNN diode, Photodetectors.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Integrated Circuits:</b> Integrated-circuit technology, Basic monolithic integrated circuits, Epitaxial Growth, 
        Masking and Etching, Diffusion of Impurities, Transistors for monolithic circuits, Monolithic diodes, Integrated 
        resistors, integrated capacitors and inductors.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Reference Books:</b>                                           
        \n\n
        
        
        1.	Robert Boylestad and Louis Nashelsky, Electronic Device And Circuit Theory, Sixth Edition.
        \n\n
        
        2.	 Albert Paul Malvino, Electronic And Circuits
        \n\n
        
        3.	Abraham Bell, Electronic Devices And Circuit.
        \n\n\n\n\n

    </string>
    
    
    
    
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name218">
        <b>CSE-218 Electronic Devices and Circuits Practical</b>
        \n\n
        
        Laboratory works based on CSE-217.
        \n\n
        
        I-V Characteristics of diode, Input and Output Characteristics of BJT: Common-Base Configuration(CB), Common-Emitter 
        Configuration (CE), Common-Collector Configuration (CC), I-V characteristic of Zener diode.
        \n\n\n\n\n
         
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name219">
        <b>CSE-219 Basic Accounting</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Introduction: </b> Definition of Accounting, its role and functions, various images of Accounting, users of 
        Accounting information, history of Accounting, generally accepted accounting principles, distinction between 
        Bookkeeping and Accounting, relationship of Accounting with other disciplines, ethical issues, the accounting 
        profession.
        \n\n
        
        <b>The Recording Process: </b> Business transactions, steps in the recording process, the accounting equation, the 
        account, the rules of debit and credit, the journal and the ledger, subsidiary ledgers and special journals, 
        the trial balance.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Accounting for Merchandising Operations: </b> Merchandising  operations, merchandising transactions, recording of 
        merchandising purchases and sales under perpetual and periodic inventory systems.
        \n\n
        
        <b>The Adjustment Process: </b> Accounting period, accrual vs. cash basis of Accounting, revenues (income) and expenses, 
        types of adjusting entries, preparing and posting of closing entries, preparing the adjusted trial balance, preparation 
        of classified income statement and the balance sheet.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Worksheet: </b> Meaning, objects, nature, rules for the preparation of worksheet and preparation of worksheet – 
        8-column and 10-column.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Preparation of Financial Statements: </b> Single and multiple-step income statements, Owner\’s equity statement , 
        Classified balance sheet, Cash flow statement.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Rectification of Errors: </b> Meaning; Types of Errors; Rectification of errors before preparation of trial balance; 
        after preparation of trial balance; after preparation of financial statements and errors detected in the next 
        accounting year.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Control of Cash: </b> Internal control; controlling cash; the bank checking account; petty cash funds; bank 
        reconciliation statement.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Accounting Information System: </b> Basic concepts, principles of Accounting information systems, developing an 
        Accounting system, mechanized accounting systems.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Reference Books: </b>
        \n\n
        
        
        1. Harman, Edwards and Maher, Accounting A business perspective, Latest edition.
        \n\n
         
     	2. Md. Hafiz Uddin, Basic Accounting (English version), Latest edition, The Angel Publications.
     	\n\n\n\n\n
        
    </string>
</resources>