<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<resources>
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name111">
        <b>CSE-111 Introduction to Computer System</b>
        \n\n

        <b>Introduction:</b> \n Data &amp; Information, History, Basic organization of computer, Computer generations, Types of 
        computer: Main frame, Mini and Micro computer; Different types of micro computer, Simplest &amp; Expanded Computer 
        System, Number systems: Binary, Hexadecimal and Octal numbers; A Modern Overview of Computers, Some Modern 
        Computing Ideas, Types of computer buses.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Hardware &amp; Software:</b> \n Hardware, classification of hardware, Types of software, Systems software: Operating 
        system, Editors, Assemblers, Compilers, Interpreters, System Utilities, Application packages.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Input Device Techniques:</b> \n Keyboard, Touch Screen, Light pen, Mouse, Pen Input Method, Graphics Tablet, Joysticks, 
        Barcodes. OCR System ,Scanner. Mark Sense Reader, Magnetic Ink character recognition,  Digital Camera, Speech Input.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Output Device Techniques:</b> \n Monitor, Printer, Graphics output devices.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Storage Techniques:</b> \n Primary Storage device and techniques, Secondary storage device and techniques.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Operating System:</b> \n Basic  concept, types of operating system : batch, multi tasking,  multiprocessing , time 
        sharing &amp; real time operating system.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Modern Communication Systems:</b> \n Computer Networks, types of computer network, network topology , 
        International Network Standards.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Programming Concept:</b> \n Problem analysis, Algorithm build-up, Flowcharts, High Level Language Features, 
        Function and Procedure.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Reference Books:</b>
        \n\n
        
        
        1.	Understanding Computer Science for Advance Level(4th Edition). -Ray Bradley.
        \n\n
        
        2.	Computer Fundamentals (4th Edition). -Pradeep K. Sinha.
        \n\n
        
        3.	Computers and Information Systems(5th Edition), -Sarah E. Hutchinsonb and Stacey C.Sawyer.
        \n\n
        
        4.	Computer Fundamental ,M. Lutfar Rahman and M. Alamgir Hossain.
        \n\n\n\n\n

    </string>
    
    
    
    
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name112">
        <b>CSE-112 Programming Language</b>
        \n\n
        
        Overview of C; Constants, variables and data types; Operator &amp; Expression; Managing Input &amp; Output 
        Operators; Decision making and branching; Decision making and looping; Arrays; Handling of character strings; 
        User-defined functions; Structure and union; Pointers; File management.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Reference Books:</b>
        \n\n
        
        
        1.	E. Balagurusamy, “Programming in ANSI C”
        \n\n
        
        2.	 Yamath Kanathkar, “Let US C”
        \n\n
        
        3.	 Yamath Kanathkar, “Pointer in C“
        \n\n
        
        4.	 Herbert Schildt, “Turbo C”
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name113">
        <b>CSE -113 Programming Language Practical</b>
        \n\n
        
        Overview of C; Constants, variables and data types; Operator &amp; Expression; Managing Input &amp; Output 
        Operators; Decision making and branching; Decision making and looping; Arrays; Handling of character strings; 
        User-defined functions; Structure and union; Pointers; File management.
        \n\n\n\n\n
     
    </string>
    
    
    
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name114">
        <b>CSE-114 Physics (Electricity and magnetism)</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Charge, Electric field &amp; Gauss\’s Law:</b> \n Simple phenomena in electrostatics; Electrostatic induction and 
        charge density; Coulomb\’s law; Electric field &amp; field strength; Point charge in an electric field; dipole in an 
        electric field; Electric flux; Gauss\’s law and some applications; Electric potential; Potential due to a point charge; 
        Equipotential surfaces; Potential energy; Potential gradient; Capacitance and its calculation; Parallel plate capacitor 
        with dielectric; Dielectric &amp; Gauss\’s law; Electric vectors; Energy stored in an electric field.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Electric current, Simple circuits and Electrical Measurements:</b> \n Current and Ohm\’s law; E.M.F. and potential 
        difference; Whetstone bridge; Simple RC and RL circuits, The potentiometer; Moving coil galvanometer; Ammeter; 
        Voltmeter; Multimeter; Wattmeter &amp; Energy meter; Measurements of Voltage, Current, Resistance, Inductance, 
        Capacitance, Power and Energy.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Magnetic Field &amp; force on Current:</b> \n Coulomb\’s law; Magnetic field and field strength; Magnetic force on 
        current; Directions of current and field; Maxwell\’s screw rule; Fleming\’s left hand rule; Magnetic field near 
        long wire; Magnetic field for solenoid; Fleming\’s right hand rule.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Magnetic properties of matter:</b> \n Poles and dipoles; Coulomb\’s law for magnets &amp; Gauss\’s theorem of 
        magnetism; Dia-magnetism, Para-magnetism and Ferro-magnetism. Magnetomotive force and field intensity; concept of 
        self and mutual inductance; The coefficient of magnetic coupling; Rise of current and decay of current in 
        inductive circuit; Energy in magnetic field; Inductance in series and parallel; Hysteresis and eddy current losses.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Reference Books:</b>
        \n\n
        
        
        1.	David Halliday and Robert Resin, Physics Part-II
        \n\n
        
        2.	Boylested, Introductory Circuit Analysis.
        \n\n
        
        3.	B. L. Theraja, A Text book of Electrical Technology.
        \n\n\n\n\n
      
    </string>
    
    
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name115">
        <b>CSE-115 Differential Calculus and Co-Ordinate Geometry</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Differential calculus:</b> \n Limits, continuity and differentiability; successive differentiation of various types of 
        functions; leibniz\’s theorem; Rolle\’s Theorem; Mean value Theorem in finite and infinite forms; Lagrange\’s form of 
        remainders; Cauchys form of remainders; Expansion of functions; Evaluation indeterminate forms by L\’Hospitals rule; 
        Partial differentiation; Euler\’s Theorem; Tangent and Normal, Subtangent and subnormal in Cartesian and polar 
        co-ordinates; Maximum and minimum values of functions of single variable; Points of inflexion; curvature, radios of 
        curvature, center of curvature Asymptotes, curve tracing.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Co-ordinate Geometry:</b> \n Transformation of co-ordinates axes and it uses; Equation of conics and its reduction to 
        standard forms; Pair of straight lines; Homogeneous equations of second degree; Angle between a pair of straight lines; 
        Pair of lines joining the origin to the point of intersection of two given curves, circles; system of circles; 
        orthogonal circles; radical axis, radical center, properties of radical axes; Coaxial circles; and limiting points; 
        Equations of parabola, ellipse and hyperbola in Cartesian and polar co-ordinates; Tangents and normals, pair of 
        tangents; Chord of contact; Chord in terms of its middle points; Pole and polar parametric co-ordinates; diameters; 
        Conjugate diameters and their properties; Director circles and asymptotes.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Reference books:</b>
        \n\n
        
        
        1.	Dr. Abdul Matin, Differential Calculus.
        \n\n
        
        2.	Abu Yusuf, Differential Calculus Integral Calculus.
        \n\n
        
        3.	B.C Das &amp; B. N. Mukherjee, Differential calculus.
        \n\n
        
        4.	Rahman and Bhattacharja,A textbook of Co-ordinate Geometry and Vector analysis.
        \n\n
        
        5.	Prof. Md. Anwar Hossain,Business Mathematics.
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name116">
        <b>GED-116 English</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>The works should concentrated at the higher levels on technical and IT usage to include:</b>
        \n
        
        Accuracy and conciseness in technical English structure, format, etc for technical reports and theses comparing and 
        contrasting other aspects of short reports (such as for assignments) and long dissertations (such as for projects).
        \n\n
        
        <b>1.READING AND COMPREHENSION:</b> 
        \n
        thematic structures, vocabulary, cohesive and rhetorical devices, grammatical items, intention/ attitude of the writer, 
        précis (i) comprehension; (ii) paragraph; (iii) précis; (iv) essay; (v) amplification; (vi) dialogue-writing.
        \n\n
        
        <b>2.	STRUCTURES:</b>
        \n
        The sentence: 
        \n
        
        i) Normal group- a) determiners, b) Adverb, C) adjective, d) Noun-adjective, c) Headword, f) Prepositional phrase 
        g) infinitive phrase h) participle phrase i) appositive.
        \n\n
        
        ii) Verbal Group: a) the tenses b) the modal auxiliaries c) phrasal verbs.
        \n\n
        
        iii) Verb Modifiers: a) Adverbials of time  b) Adverbials of place  c) Adverbials of manner d) adverbials of duration, 
        completing sentences, correction of sentences, transformation of sentences, combination of sentences, 
        framing of which questions.
        \n\n
        
        <b>NOTIONS AND FUNCTIONS:</b>
        \n
        
        i) Emotional attitudes e.g. liking 
        \n
        
        ii) Moral attitudes: apology, regret, etc
        \n
        
        iii) Suasion (utterance, designed to influence the behavior of other)
        \n
        
        iv) Intellectual attitudes, e.g. agreement, disagreement, permission, obligation, etc.
        \n
        
        v) Socializing e.g. greeting, farewell, etc.
        \n\n
        
        <b>3. LETTERS:</b>
        \n
        
        Application---request---Enquiries---Quotations---Complaints---Tender---to Newspapers---Formal and Informal---
        Advertisements, etc.
        \n\n
        
        <b>4. TRANSLATION:</b>
        \n
        English to Bangla and Bangla to English.
        \n\n
        
        <b>5. TECHNICAL WRITING:</b>
        \n
        Writing Projects, Reports and theses.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Reference Books:</b>
        \n\n
        
        
        1.	Chowdhury &amp; Hossain, Advanced Learner Functional English.
        \n\n
        
        2.	Boeckner, Keith and Brown, Charies P, Oxford English for computing.
        \n\n
        
        3.	Wren and Martin, High School English Grammar &amp; composition.
        \n\n
        
        4.	Thomson &amp; Martin, A practical English Grammar.
        \n\n\n\n\n

        
        
    </string>
</resources>