<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>


<resources>
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name221">
        <b>CSE-221 Algorithm Design</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Introduction to algorithm: </b> \n Analysis of algorithm, design of algorithm, mathematical foundation of algorithm, 
        asymptotic notations, summations, recurrences, sets etc.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Divide and Conquer: </b> \n General method, Binary Search, Finding the Maximum and Minimum, Quick Sort, Selection.
        \n\n
        
        <b>The Greedy method: </b> \n General method, Knapsack problem, Minimum cost spanning trees, Single Source Shortest path.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Dynamic programming: </b> \n General method, Multistage Graphs, All pair\’s shortest paths, Single Source Shortest 
        path, Knapsack problem, Optimal Binary search Tree, Traveling salesperson.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Basic Traversal &amp; Search technique: </b> \n Techniques for Binary trees, Techniques for Graphs.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Backtracking: </b> \n General method, The 8-Queens problem, Sum of subsets, Graph Coloring.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Branch and Bound: </b> \n The method, 0/1 Knapsack problem, Traveling salesperson.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Reference books: </b>
        \n\n
        
        
        1. Fundamentals of Computer Algorithm, Sartaj Sahni
        \n\n
         
        2. How to Solve it by Computer, R.G.Dromey.
        \n\n
        
        3. Data Structure &amp; Programming Design, Robert L.Kruse.
        \n\n\n\n\n
       
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name222">
        <b>CSE-222 Algorithm Design Practical</b>
        \n\n
        
        Laboratory works based on CSE-221
        \n\n
        
        <b>Divide and conquer: </b> \n Binary Search, finding the maximum and minimum.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Performance measurement using time Function: </b> \n quick sort and marge sort, marge sort and Bubble sort, Quick sort 
        and Heap sort.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Greedy Method: </b> \n Knapsack problem, Minimum cost spanning tree, Prim\’s algorithm, Single source shortest path.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Dynamic Programming: </b> \n All pair shortest path, 0/1 kanpsack problem, the traveling salesperson problem. 
        \n\n
        
        <b>Backtracking: </b> \n The 8 Queens Problem, Graph coloring problem.
        \n\n\n
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name223">
        <b>CSE-223 Database Management System</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Introduction: </b> \n Database system concept, Purpose of Database system; View of data: Data abstraction; Data models: 
        Relational model, Network model, Hierarchical model; Database languages: DDL, DML; Conventional file processing; 
        Transaction management; Storage management; Database Administrator; Database users; Overall system structure.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Database model: </b> \n Entity-Relationship model; Attributes; Mapping Cardinalities; Existence Dependencies; Weak 
        entity set &amp; Strong entity set; Relational model and its language (Relational algebra and SQL).
        \n\n
        
        <b>Database design: </b> \n Decomposition; Normalization; Object-oriented Databases; Centralized systems; Distributed 
        Databases; Data Fragmentation; Parallel Databases.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Integrity Constraints: </b> \n Domain constraints, Referential constraints, Functional Dependencies.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Indexing: </b> \n Basic concept; Ordered index; Primary index; Dense index and Sparse index; Multilevel index; Secondary 
        index.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Reference Book: </b>
        \n\n
        
        1. Database System Concepts (4th Edition) -Abraham Silberschatz   Henry F.Korth   S.Sudarshan
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name224">
        <b>CSE-224 Database Management System Practical</b>
        \n\n
        
        Laboratory works based on CSE-223.
        \n\n
        
        Design and Create database, Insert/Delete records in each table, Design MASTER FORM with menus, Do the  different 
        queries, Report design. Different PL/SQL problems.
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name225">
        <b>CSE-225 Computer Organization and Architecture</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Introduction: </b> \n Organisation and Architecture, Instruction sets- formats, cycle, timing etc; Addressing modes; 
        Types of Instruction; RISC characteristics; CISC characteristics.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Computer System: </b> \n System Buses, Components, Functions, Bus Interconnection.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Computer Arithmetic: </b> \n Different types of data representation; Addition and Subtraction; Multiplication 
        Algorithms; Division Algorithms.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Memory Organization: </b> \n Main memory, Auxiliary memory, Associative memory, Cache memory, Virtual memory, Memory 
        management requirements and hardware.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Input-Output Organization: </b> \n Input-Output Interfaces; Data transfer, Interrupts; Direct Memory Access (DMA); 
        Input-Output channel.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Central Processing Unit(CPU): </b> \n ALU, CPU structure and Functions.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Control Unit: </b> \n Control Unit operation, Micro-operation, Control of processor, Hardwired Implementation.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Fundamentals of parallel processing: </b> \n  Parallel processing; Pipelining; Vector processing; Multiprocessors; Array 
        processor, Bit-slice processor Interconnection structures.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Reference Books:</b>
        \n\n
        
        
        1. William Stallings, Computer Organisation and Architecture.
        \n\n
        
        2. V. Hamcher, Z.Vranesic and S.Zaky, Computer Organisation.
        \n\n
        
        3. J.P. Hayes, Computer Architecture and Organisation.
        \n\n
        
        4. Dr. M. Rafiquzzaman, Fundamentals of Computer System Architecture.
        \n\n\n\n\n
      
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name226">
        <b>CSE-226 Data Communications</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Introduction: </b> \n Data Communication networks standards, communication architecture and protocol.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Data Transmission: </b> \n Analog and digital data, Spectrum and Bandwidth, Transmission impairments, Channel capacity, 
        Transmission media, coaxial cable, twisted pair, fiber optics, wireless transmission, electromagnetic spectrum, radio, 
        microwave, infra red, cellular and satellite.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Data Encoding: </b> \n Digital data and digital signaling, NRZL, NRZI, Bipolar AMI, Manchester and differential 
        Manchester encoding, Digital data and analog signaling,  ASK, FSK, PSK &amp; QPSK and their performance, Analog data 
        and digital signaling, PCM.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Data Communication Techniques: </b> \n Asynchronous and Synchronous transmission, CRC Method, RS232( or EIA 232D), 
        V2.4 interface standard.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Data Link Control: </b> \n Flow control; Error detection- parity and CRC, Error Control(Stop and wait, Go back N ARQ, 
        Selective Reject ARQ), HDLC, Other data link control protocols.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Multiplexing: </b> \n Frequency Division Multiplexing, Synchronous Time Division Multiplexing, Statistical Time 
        Division Multiplexing.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Circuit Switching &amp; Packet Switching: </b> \n Space Division and Time Division switching, Switching network; 
        Circuit switching network; Circuit switching concepts,  Packet switching principles, Virtual Circuit, Datagram.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Reference Books: </b>  
        \n\n
        
        
        1.	Behrouz A. Forouzan, Data Communication and Networking.
        \n\n
        
        2.	W Stallings, Data and Computer Communication.
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name227">
        <b>GED-227 Economics</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Introduction: </b> \n Definition, micro economics and macro economics. Positive Vs. normative economics. The basic 
        problems of economic organization. Production possibility frontier.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Supply and demand: </b> \n Concepts of supply and demand and their determinants, market equilibrium and shifts of 
        market equilibrium, concepts and measurements of various elasticitis of demand and supply.
        \n\n
        
        <b>The theory of consumer behaviour: </b> \n Utility-total and marginal utility, cardinal &amp; ordinal utility, law of 
        diminishing marginal utility.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Theory of production: </b> \n Production function, fixed Vs, variable factors of production, short run and long run, 
        total average and marginal product, the law of diminishing returns, returns to scale, technological change.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Theory of cost and revenues: </b> \n Short and long run cost functions, implicit and opportunity cost, fixed and 
        variable costs, total average and marginal costs, envelope curves, marginal product and the least cost rule, profit 
        maximizing conditions.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Market: </b> \n Perfect competition and monopoly, short &amp; long run equilibrium of firm and industry, 
        profit maximization, shut down condition, resource allocation and economic efficiency.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Macro economic overview: </b> \n Fundamental concepts of macroeconomic, aggregate demand and aggregate supply.
        \n\n
        
        <b>National income accounting: </b> \n circular flow of income, different concepts of national income- GNP, GDP, NNP, NI 
        at factor price, market price and constant price, personal income, disposable income, real and nominal GDP, Net 
        economic welfare (NEW); The CPI &amp; the GDP Deflator, the methods and problems of computing national income.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Consumption and saving function: </b> \n concepts of MPC, APC, MPS, APS- Short run and long run  view-Kuznet\’s puzzle.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Investment Function: </b> \n Determinants of investment, concepts of MEC, MEI, Present value Theorem.
        \n\n
        
        <b>The Classical and Keynesian theory: </b> \n Determination of income and employment, Inflationary and deflationary gaps 
        and measures to bridge the gap, theory of multiplier and accelerator.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Reference Books: </b>
        \n\n
         
        
        1.	Samuelson &amp; Nordhaus, W, : Economics.
        \n\n
        
        2.	Leftwitch: the price System &amp; Resurce Allocation.
        \n\n
        
        3.	Bilsa: microeconomic theory.
        \n\n
        
        4.	Koutsoyiannis: Moderm Micro-economics.
        \n\n
        
        5.	Dornburg &amp; Mc Dougall: Macro-economics.
        \n\n
        
        6.	Swenburg &amp; Mc Dougall: Macro-economics.
        \n\n
        
        7.	Domwnick Salvatory: Micro-economics.
        \n\n
        
        8.	Eugene Diulio: Macro-economics.
        \n\n\n\n\n
         
        
    </string>
    
</resources>