<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<resources>
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name421">
        <b>CSE-421 Web Engineering</b>
        \n\n
        
        Introduction to Web application technology, basic concepts, Client Server architecture, Web browser and Web servers, 
        WWW, structure of a website, popular websites and their speciality, basic concepts static and dynamic web sectors, 
        different web problems like Hoaxes, Spyware, Viruses and Pop-ups etc.
        \n\n
        
        Brief history of Mark-up languages, HTML and introduction to HTML, basic HTML tags, adding links to different pages, 
        inserting images, back ground sounds, GIF, Animations, form and form components, Contact/Feed back Forms (Text box, 
        Text fields, pull-down menu, submit/reset Button, redirection between Web pages.
        \n\n
         
        CSS, basic concepts of CSS, CSS handlers, creating custom text styles using CSS, using/calling CSS functions in forms, 
        changing links.
        \n\n
         
        Introduction to Java scripts, Using Basic Java Scripts functions like writeline, time,date etc. Using Simple scripts on 
        different mouse events, Changing page Title,Using java Scripts to design multi-state  image links, pull- down menus, 
        embedding dynamic elements with  Java Scripts, advanced custom tags.
        \n\n
        
        Basic Concepts of Java applet , building simple applets with images, text and links, supported platform and browsers, 
        common problems and trouble shooting. Basic concepts of DHTML, How it uses HTML, Java Scripts and CSS components. 
        Texts, links and Image array.
        \n\n
        
        PHP, Supported platforms, basic programming concepts and its dynamism, Simple PHP scripts to write/read inputs in 
        forms and using in Dynamic forms. Integrating PHP and My-SQL, Using PHP Forms to manipulate data in the database, 
        Data Validation, Session, security, Web application development.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Reference Book: </b>
        \n\n
        
            
        1.	Chris Lea, Wankyu Choi,Allan Kent,Ganesh Prasad,Chris Ullman. Beginning Php 4 (Programmer to Programmer).
        \n\n
        
        2.	 Surid Sharkar, CSS/Java Script.
        \n\n
        
        3.  Web Design Complete Reference by Thomas A. Powell
        \n\n
        
        4.  Creating Web Pages with HTML Simplified by Sherry Willard Kinkoph
        \n\n
        
        5.  Web Design in a Nutshell (O’RELLY)- Jennifer Niederst 
        \n\n\n\n\n

    </string>
    
    
    
    
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name422">
        <b>CSE-422 Web Engineering Practical</b>
        \n\n
        
        Laboratory works based on CSE-421
        \n\n
        
        
        1. Designing a simple HTML Document to show text (Introduction to &lt;HTML&gt;,&lt;Body&gt;, &lt;Head&gt;, &lt;Title&gt;,
        &lt;Meta Content&gt;,Using
        Different HTML tags to format Body contents.
        \n\n
        
        2.Text alignment in table, Introduction to Form elements(textbox, checkbox, combo box etc) and designing simple 
        Feedback/Contact forms.
        \n\n
        
        3.Using Java Scripts to to create web pages containing custom Welcome message(Date-time).
        \n\n
        
        4.Using text Links to navigate between different pages, inserting  Images  and back ground sounds and using Images as 
        Link.
        \n\n
        
        5.Using page frames and mousover links and implementing them in a HTML document.
        \n\n
        
        6.Using CSS to apply formatting text, forms, tables and link styles.
        \n\n
        
        10.Using different control statements in Java Scripts to execute simple mathematical expressions(if-else, Switch-case, 
        for, while, do-while).
        \n\n
        
        11.Installing Apache, PHP 4/5 and integrating into windows platform, creating PHP documents with simple tags, 
        installing My-SQL and connection between PHP and My-SQL.
        \n\n
        
        12.Inserting data into My-SQL database using PHP forms.
        \n\n
        
        	
        Project: Design and develop a Complete Dynamic website with HTML, PHP and My-SQL having forms and also a 
        flexible navigation menu which has links to all available section on the site.
        \n\n\n\n\n
       
    </string>
    
        
    
        
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name423">
        <b>CSE-423 Computer and Network Security</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Cryptography and cryptographic algorithms: </b> Traditional cryptographic algorithms: traditional cryptography, 
        cryptanalysis, Private-key (symmetric-key) and public-key (asymmetric-key) cryptographic algorithms, DES and block 
        cipher modes, advanced encryption standard, RSA and other public key cryptosystems, key management, Diffie-Hellman key 
        exchange, Elliptic curve cryptography, cryptography hash functions, secure hash algorithm, message authentication 
        codes, Digital signatures and digital signature standard.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Cryptography and network security: </b> Data-origin authentication and data integrity, Key distribution, management, 
        Kerberos and X.509 authentication service, certificate authotity and public key infrastructure, Email security, PGP and 
        S/MIME, IP Security, authentication header and ESP, Security associations, Key management, eb security considerations, 
        secure socket layer and transport layer security, secure electronic transactions (SET).
        \n\n
        
        <b>Cryptography for antivirus software and password management: </b> generic decryption, digital immune system and UNIX 
        password scheme.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Reference Book: </b>
        \n\n
        
        
        1.	Cryptography and Network Security, William Stallings.
        \n\n
         
        2.	Hand book of Applied Cryptography, by A. Menezes, P.van Oorschot, and S. Vanstone, CRC press, 1996 
        ( www.cacr.math.uwaterloo.ca/hac)
        \n\n\n\n\n 
	
    </string>    
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name424">
        <b>CSE-42X Elective Course </b>
        \n\n
        
        This is an elective course the student should choose one of the elective course in consultation with head of the 
        department. 
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name425">
        <b>CSE- 499 Project Work (Continued from 7th Sem.)</b>
        \n\n
        
        12 hours in a week, 6.00 Cr.
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name426">
        <b>CSE-424 Image Processing</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Introduction to image processing: </b> Representation of image, A basic image processing system, Relationship to 
        human visual system, Example of fields that use digital image processing.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Digital Image Fundamentals: </b> Image formation in the eye, Light and electromagnetic spectrum, Image sensing and 
        acquisition, Image sampling, Image quantization, Some basic relationships between pixels Neighbors of a pixel, Adjacency, 
        connectivity, region, Boundaries, Distance measures.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Image enhancement: </b> Some basic gray level transformations, Histogram processing, Histogram equalization, Histogram 
        matching, Image negatives, log transformation, Power law transformation, Basics of spatial filtering, Smoothing spatial 
        filters, Homomorphic filtering, Correspondence between the spatial and frequency domain filtering.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Image Restoration: </b> A model of the image degradation/ Restoration process, Noise models, Restoration in the 
        presence of noise only spatial filtering.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Color Image processing: </b>Color fundamentals, Color models, the RGB color model The CMY, CMYK color Model, HIS 
        color Model, Basics of full-color transformation, Color transformations, formulation.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Image Compression: </b>Image compression fundamentals, Coding redundancy, Inter pixel redundancy.
        \n
        
        Psychovisual redundancy, Image compression models, The source encoder and decoder, The channel encoder and decoder.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Image Segmentation: </b> Edge detection, line detection, point detection, Boundary Detection, Thresholding, 
        Region based segmentation.
        \n\n\n 
        
        <b>Reference book: </b>
        \n\n
        
        
        1.	Rafael C. Gonzalez, Richard E. Woods. Digital Image Processing.
        \n\n
        
        2.	Anil K. Jain. Fundamentals of Digital Image Processing.
        \n\n
        
        3.	M A Sid-Ahmed. Image processing theory, Algorithms and architectures.
        \n\n\n\n\n 
        
         
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name427">
        <b>CSE-425 VLSI Design</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>VLSI Design: </b> Design and analysis techniques for VLSI circuits; Design of reliable VLSI circuits; Noise 
        consideration; Design and operation of large fan out and fan in circuits, clocking methodologies; Techniques for data 
        path and data control design. Simulation techniques; parallel processing, Special purpose architectures in VLSI layout 
        partitioning and placement routing and wiring in VLSI; Reliability aspects of VLSI design, Graph based VLSI Design, 
        Multilevel VLSI circuit, Multiple Valued VLSI circuit.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Reference Books: </b>
        \n\n
        
        	 
        1.	Basic VLSI Design system and Circuits, Douglas A. Pucknell, KAMRAN Eshraghiam, Pentic, Hall International Inc. 
        Second Edition.
        \n\n
         
        2.	Modern VLSI Design by Wayne Wolf.
        \n\n\n\n\n
     
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name428">
        <b>CSE-426 Simulation and Modeling</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Concept of system: </b> System components, continuous and discrete systems.
        \n\n
        
        <b>System modeling: </b> Types of models, static and dynamic models, physical and mathematical models, continuous and 
        discrete models. Principles used in system modeling. Study if system model;  system design, system model analysis and 
        postulation.
        \n\n
        
        <b>System Dynamics: </b> Need for simulation, types of simulation, techniques of simulation. Comparison of simulated 
        and analytical methods. Continuous system simulation. Differential equation model.
        \n
        
        Exponential growth models and decay models, generalization of growth models. System dynamics diagrams. Multi-sigment 
        models, representation of time delay. Probability concepts in simulation; Stochastic variable, discrete and and 
        continuous probability functions,. Generations of random numbers. Generating discrete distributions. Non-uniform 
        continuously distributed random numbers, Rejection method.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Discrete System Simulation: </b> Discrete event simulation, activity simulation, representation of time, generation 
        of arrival patterns, entities, resources, queues. Measures of queues and mathematical solution of queuing problems.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Discrete simulation languages: </b> General Purpose simulation, System language (GPSS) and  SIMSCRIPT.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Reference Books: </b>
        \n\n
        
        
		1.System Simulation by Geoffery Grodon, Prentice Hall
		\n\n
		
		2.Discrete-event System Simulation by Banks J and Carson JS, Prentice Hall.
		\n\n
		
		3.Simulation Modeling with Pascal, Prentice Hall.
		\n\n
		
		4. System Simulation with digital computer. Narsing deo.
		\n\n\n\n\n

    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name429">
        <b>CSE-427 E-Commerce</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Introduction: </b> An overview,traditional and electronic business trasanctions, types of e-commerce, benefits of 
        e-commerce.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Security and e-commerce: </b> Review of private key and public key enery operations, Comparasion of encryption 
        method, Digital signatures and certificates, overview of literate security systems.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Handling money on the net: </b> Transactions on the internet,requirements for payment systems,types and tools for 
        electyronics payment, electronic data interchange and components of EDI system.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Consumer and Business Markets: </b> Consumer markets and one to one marketing,value chains and the market place, 
        Online communities and new marketing opportunies, websities and ordering online, Online catalogs , tying database, to 
        online catalogs, Electronic consumer support,tracking online problems, security software modules.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Virtual: </b>Virtual factory, virtual coordination and implementation,access to shared data and applications, 
        entrusting access to intermediary.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Business Process Engineering: </b> Approaches, models and methodologies, management of changes.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Legal Issues: </b> Risk associated with proper documents and electronic documents, authentication of electronic 
        documents, laws for e-commerce, EDI interchange agreements legal issues for internet commerce.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Reference Books: </b>
        \n\n
        
        
        1.E-Commerce,KK Bajaj and D. Nag.
        \n\n
        
        2.E-Commerce, D.Kosiur.
        \n\n
        
        3.Electronic Commerce , P. Loshin, P. Murphy.
        \n\n
        
        4.Frontiers of Electronic Commerce, R. Kalakota.	
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
    </string>
</resources>