<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name411">
        <b>CSE-411 Computer Network</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Introduction: </b> Basic computer network concept; Network structure; Network software; Reference model; Example 
        networks; OSI Model, TCP/IP Model, X.25 Networks.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Frame Relay: </b> Introduction to frame relay, advantages and disadvantages, role of frame relay, frame relay 
        operations, virtual circuits, DLCIs inside the network, frame relay layers; physical layer , data link layer.
        \n\n
        
        <b>ATM Network: </b> Packet networks, mixed network traffic, cell networks, asynchronous TDM,virtual connection, 
        identifiers, cell, connection establishment and release, Application Adoptions Layer(AAL),ATM layers, Physical layer, 
        ATM WANs, ATM LANs.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Medium Access sub-layer: </b> Multiple Access Protocols: ALOHA; CSMA/CD Protocol; Collision-Free protocols;CDMA Limited 
        contention protocol; Wavelength division multiple access protocols; Wireless LAN protocols; IEEE standard 802 for 
        LANs and MANs; Bridges; High-speed LANs;Wireless LANs,Mobile telephony and Satellite Networks.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Network Layer: </b> Network layer design issues; Routing algorithms; Congestion control Algorithms; Inter networking; 
        Network layer in the internet; IPv4 and introduction to IPv6.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Transport Layer: </b> The transport service; Elements of transport protocols; The internet transport protocols; The 
        ATM AAL layer protocols.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Optical Fiber Network: </b> SONET and SDH.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Application Layer: </b> Network security; DNS-Domain Name system; SNMP: Simple Network Management protocol; 
        Electronic Mail; The World Wide Web; Multimedia.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Reference Books: </b>
        \n\n
        
        
        1.	Tannenbaum ,Computer Networks.
        \n\n
        
        2.	W. Stallings, Data &amp; Computer Communication.
        \n\n
        
        3.	Behrouz &amp; Forouzen, Data Communication &amp; Networking.
	    \n\n\n\n\n
	            
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name412">
        <b>CSE-412 Computer Network Practical</b>
        \n\n
        
        Laboratory works based on CSE-411
        \n\n
        
        Overall Concept about network, Configure TCP/IP, Different protocol and net card, DHCP server/client configuration. 
        Introduction to DNS, DNS server configuration, use of DNS testing utility, Caching only DNS server configuration, 
        canonical name implementation, Introduction to electronic mail system, configuration, use of DNS testing utility, 
        Caching only DNS server configuration, Canonical name implementation, introduction to electronic mail system, configure 
        to ISP online mail, configure SMTP, POP, testing and debugging, email account splitting, virtual hosting, IMP and POP 
        setup, WINS configuration, apache web server configuration, apache core active and apache module, web based mail 
        configuration, apache core active and apache module, web based mail configuration using open web mail, IP based virtual 
        web hosting, name based virtual web hosting, testing and debugging and log file analysis, squid  proxy server 
        configuration, understanding of different squid tag FTP configuration.
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name413">
        <b>CSE-413 Artificial Intelligence and Neural Network</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Introduction: </b> What is AI, Intelligent agents.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Problem Solving by Searching: </b> Blind search, Informed search, Depth first, breadth first, depth limited, 
        iterative deepening, bi-directional, best first, heuristics search, A* search, Hill climbing search, Simulated 
        annealing search, Genetic Algorithm.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Knowledge: </b> Knowledge representation, First-order logic, PL, FOPL, WFFs, Fuzzy Logic. 
        \n\n
        
        <b>Neural Network: </b> ANN, Perceptron, Learning, Supervised, Unsupervised, Reinforcement learning, Back Propagation.
        \n\n\n
        
        
        <b>Reference Books: </b>
        \n\n
        
        
        1.	Stuart Russel &amp; Peter Norvig,  Artificial Intelligence: A Modern Approach.
        \n\n
        
        2.	Stamations V. Katalopoulos, Understanding Neural Networks and Fuzzy Logic.
        \n\n
        
        3.	Barr and Feigenbaum, Handbook of Artificial Intelligence Vol. I , William Kaufmann
        \n\n
        
        4.	Iven Bratko, Programming for Artificial Intelligence.
        \n\n\n\n\n
	
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name414">
        <b>CSE-414 Parallel and Distributed Processing</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Parallel Processing: </b> Overview- Importance, architecture, hardware and software issues. Architecture for 
        parallels processing- classifications, comparative study of different architectures. Issues in parallel processing, 
        Parallel Algorithm – Pointer Jumping, Work-efficient, Sorting Networks, Graph Problems- Connected Components, Shortest 
        Paths Spanning Trees.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Distributed processing : </b> Overview- Definition, impact of distributed processing on organizations, pitfalls in 
        distributed processing. Forms of distributed processing- Function distribution, hierarchical distributed systems, 
        horizontal distributed system.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Strategy: </b> strategies for distributed data processing, control of complicity, problem of incompatibility, 
        centralization Vs decentralization, cost an benefit analysis.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Design of distributed data: </b> Distributed data- Distributed data, location of data, multiple copies data, conflict 
        analysis, database management, distributed database and applications.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Fault Tolerance: </b> Forward and Backward Error Recovery, Voting Protocol, Redundancy Approaches, Operation based 
        and State Based Approach, Commit Protocols.
	    \n\n\n
	    
	    <b>Reference Books: </b>
        \n\n
        
        
        1.	Advanced Computer Architecture- Hwang Kai
        \n\n
        
        2.	Distributed Operating System- P.K. Sinha
        \n\n
        
        3.	Distributed Operating System- Tanenbaum
        \n\n
        
        4.	Algorithm- Coreman
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name415">
        <b>CSE-415 Peripheral and Interfacing</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Interfacing techniques: </b> Interfacing for Memory; Communication system; System overhead (DMA and Programmed data 
        transfer); I/O ports and Control; Parallel and Serial Interfacing devices; Timing considerations; Noise considerations; 
        Application of PPI, PIC, DMAC, PCI etc.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Digital Interfacing: </b> Programmable parallel ports and handshake input/output (IC 8255), Interfacing a 
        Microprocessor to keyboards, X-lat, Display-Alphanumeric and multiplexed LED (Interfacing with IC 7447), Relay, Stepper 
        motor, Incremental Encoder, Optical motor shaft encoder.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Modern data-entry devices: </b> Scanners overview; Bar code reader; Optical mark reader (OMR); Optical Character 
        Reader (OCR); Tape Reader; Digitizer: Reading technique, Capacitive Electrostatic scanning digitizer.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Display devices: </b> CRT; Basic CRT operations; Timing and frequencies; CRT controller ICs; LCD technologies; 
        Passive and active matrix; LCD reliability; Electroluminescent display.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Printers: </b> Impact printers; Serial and line printing; Laser printing; Ink-Jet printing; Color printing; Plotters.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Storage devices: </b> Floppy disk; Floppy disk controller (IC 8272) ; Magnetic hard disk and controller; Compact 
        disk, magnetic tape storage.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Data Communication and Network: </b> Introduction to asynchronous serial data communication, RS-232 C serial data 
        standard, USART(IC 8251A) word format, Null Modem configuration, The GPIB, HPIB, IEEE 488 Bus.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Reference Books: </b>
        \n\n
        
        
       	1. Microprocessor and Interfacing by Andrew Hall
       	\n\n
       	
    	2. Computer Peripherals (Part B) by Barry Wilkinson
    	\n\n\n\n\n
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name416">
        <b>CSE-416 Peripheral and Interfacing Practical</b>
        \n\n
        
        Laboratory works based on CSE-415
        \n\n
        
        Understand SDK 86 board, write and execute a program in an SDK 86.
        \n
        
        Understand RS-232 standard, Connections and Cabling.
        \n
         
        Communicate between two Computers using parallel ports (Printer Port).
        \n
        
        Observe and manipulate Null modem Configuration.
        \n
        
        Communicate between two Computers using serial ports.
        \n
        
        Drive a single 7 segment LED display with 7447.
        \n
        
        Understand the basic characteristics of IC 8255.
        \n\n\n\n\n

    </string>
    
    
    
    
    <string name="cse_subject_code_and_name417"> 
        <b>CSE-417 Digital Signal Processing</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Introduction to Digital Signal Processing (DSP): </b> Introduction; Digital Signal Processing; Sampling and 
        Analog-to-Digital Conversion; Discrete Time Signals; Ambiguity in Digital signals; Discrete Time Systems; Application 
        areas for DSP; Keys of DSP operations: Convolution, Correlation, Digital Filtering, Discrete Transformation, 
        Modulation; System Design: Methodology  &amp; Implementation Methodology.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Discrete Fourier transform: </b> Fourier series, one dimensional Fourier transforms, discrete Fourier Transform 
        (DFT) and its properties, Fast Fourier Transform (FFT) and its algorithm, Inverse discrete Fourier transformation.
        \n\n
        
        <b>The Z-Transform: </b> Introduction to z-Transform; General Results of z-transform; Inverse z-Transform: Partial 
        Fraction Expansion, Power Series Expansion, Contour Integration; Comparison of inverse z-transform method; Properties 
        of z-transform; Complex Convolution Theorem and Parseval\'s Relation.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Implementation of Discrete-Time Systems: </b> Introduction; Block Diagram and Signal Flow Graph Representation of 
        Digital Networks; Matrix Representation of Digital Networks; Basic Structures of IIR Systems: Direct Form, Cascade 
        forms, Parallel Form; Transposed Forms; Basic Structures of FIR Systems; Finite Precision Effects.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Design of Digital Filters: </b> Introduction to Digital Filters; Types of Digital Filters: FIR and IIR; Choosing between 
        FIR and IIR Filters: Digital Filter Design Steps; Design of FIR Filters: Design of FIR Filters by Windowing, Design of 
        Optimum Equiripple Linear-Phase FIR Filters, Design of IIR Filters: Classical Continuous-Time Low-Pass Filter 
        Approximations, Conversion of Transfer Functions from Continuous to Discrete Time, Frequency Transformations of Low pass 
        Filters, Adaptive digital filters: concepts of adaptive filtering, basic wiener filter theory, the basic LMS adaptive 
        algorithm, recursive least square algorithm.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Reference books: </b>
        \n\n
        
        
        1.	Emmanuel C. Ifeachor, Barrie W. jervis.  Digital Signal Processing.
        \n\n
        
        2.	John G. Proakis, Dimitris G. Manolakis,  Digital Signal Processing – Principles, Algorithms, and applications.
        \n\n
          
        3.	Alan V. Oppenheim, Ronald W. Schafer, John R. Buck, Dicrete-Time signal Processing.
        \n\n\n\n\n

    </string>
    
    
   
</resources>