<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<resources>
    <string name="ece_subject_code_and_name221">
        <b>ECE-211: Fundamentals of Communications</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Noise:</b> Shot noise, White noise, Gain in decibels, Signal to noise ratio.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Radio Communication systems:</b> Amplitude modulation (AM), AM broadcast technical standards, 
        Double sideband suppressed carrier (DSBSC), Single sideband suppressed carrier (SSB), Vestigial sideband (VSB), 
        Phase modulation (PM) and frequency modulation (FM), Envelop detector, Product modulator, AM transmitter, 
        Superheterodyne receiver, FM transmitters and recivers.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Pulse and digital signaling:</b> Pulse code modulation (PCM), Delta modulation (DM), 
        Adaptive delta modulation (ADM), Differential PCM (DPCM), Adaptive DPCM (ADPCM), 
        Time division multiplexing (TDM), Frequency division multiplexing (FDM).
        \n\n              
        
        <b>Telephony:</b> Background and concept, The simple telephone connection, Conventional analog switching in 
        telephone networks, Analog telephone versus digital telephone systems, Basic switching functions, Introductory 
        switching concepts, Numbering concept for telephony, Digital switching – space division and time division.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Mobile Telephony:</b> Mobile radio systems, How a cellular telephone call is made, The cellular system design 
        fundamentals – Frequency reuse, channel assignment strategies, Handoff strategies, Interference and system capacity, 
        Trunking and grade of service, Cell splitting, Multipath propagation and fading, Doppler shift, 
        Cellular system standards – AMPS, GSM, CDMA (IS-95). 
        \n\n
        
        <b>Recommended books:</b>
        \n\n
        
        
        •	Communication Systems by Simon Haykin.
        \n\n
        
        •	Modern Communication Systems Principle and Applications by Loen W. Couch.
        \n\n
        •	Telecommunication System Engineering by R.L. Freeman.
        \n\n
        
        •	Cellular Mobile Systems Engineering, Saleh Faruque.
        \n\n
        
        •	Wireless Communication Principles and Practice by T.S. Rappaport.
        \n\n
        
        •	Fundamentals of Communication by M. Lutfar Rahman (Editor).
        \n\n\n
                
    </string>
    
    
    
    <string name="ece_subject_code_and_name222">
        <b>ECE-212: Electrical Instrumentation &amp; Measurements</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Introduction:</b> Significance and methods of measurements, Direct and indirect methods and standard
        types of instruments.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Analog Voltmeters and Ammeters:</b> Different types of analog voltmeters, Accuracy and error of analog voltmeters.
        Different types of ammeters, Accuracy and errors of analog ammeters.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Digital Voltmeters:</b> Staircase ramp type, Successive approximation type, Integrating type,
        Delta pulse modulation type. 
        \n\n
        
        <b>Digital Multimeters:</b> DC voltage attenuator, Current to voltage converter, AC/DC converter, Resistance to voltage converter,
        HF/LF converter, Automation in Multimeters, Automatic polarity indication and auto ranging digital instrumentations.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Oscilloscope and Signal Generator:</b> Single beam and dual beam types, Sampling and storage types, 
        Sweep frequency generations, Function generators.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Analyzers:</b> Wave analyzer, Harmonic generators, Frequency synthesizer and spectrum analyzers, 
        Analog and digital frequency meters, Recorders and displays.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Data Acquisition:</b> Data loggers, Data acquisition and control, PC-based instrumentation.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Recommended books:</b>
        \n\n
        
        
        •	Instrumentation, Measurements and Feedback by B.E. Jones.
        \n\n
        
        •	Electronics Instrumentation and Measurement Techniques by W.D. Cooper.
        \n\n
        
        •	Instrumentation Technology by B.B. Jones and Butterworth.
        \n\n
        
        •	Industrial Instrumentation Fundamentals by A.E. Fribance.
        \n\n\n     
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    <string name="ece_subject_code_and_name223">
        <b>ECE-213: Digital Electronics – II</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Decoding and Encoding:</b> Decoders, BCD to 7 segment decoder, BCD to decimal decoder, Encoders, Switch encoder.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Multiplexing and Demultiplexing:</b> Multiplexer, Demultiplexer, MUX and DEMUX applications, Comparator, 
        Parity generator and checker.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Converters:</b> Digital to Analog Converter(DAC), Weighted register DAC, R-2R ladder, DAC specifications, 
        Analog to digital converters (ADC), Digital ramp ADC, Successive approximation ADC, Flash ADC, 
        Continuous conversion type ADC, Examples of ADC and DAC ICs, Principle of digital instruments, Digital multimeters, 
        Phasemeters, Frequency meters. 
        \n\n
        
        <b>Semiconductor Memories:</b> Memory organization and operation, Expansion of work size and work capacity, 
        Classification and characterization of memory, Organization of RAM and ROM, Advancements of semiconductor memories, 
        PLA, PLD, PAL.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Recommended books:</b>
        \n\n
        
        
        •	Principles of Digital Electronics by T.J. Tocci.
        \n\n
        
        •	Modern Digital Electronics by R.P. Jain.
        \n\n
        
        •	Digital Electronics by Morris Mano.
        \n\n
        
        •	Digital Systems by M. Lutfar Rahman.
        \n\n\n
        
       
    </string>
    
    
    
    <string name="ece_subject_code_and_name224">
        
        <b>ECE-214: Signals and Systems</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Signals:</b> Continuous-time and discrete-time signals, Even and odd signals, Periodic and non-Periodic signals, 
        Deterministic and random signals, Energy and Power signal, Unit impulse and unit impulse functions; 
        Some elementary D-T signals: Unit Sample Sequence, Step signal, Ramp &amp; Exponential signal.
        Simple manipulation of D-T signals. Sampling and aliasing.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Systems:</b> Digital System, D-T system, Block diagram representation of D-T systems. 
        Different types of systems: Relax &amp; Non-Relax system, Static and Dynamic system, Time Invariant and Time Variant System,
        Linear and Non-Linear system, Causal and Non-Causal system, Stable &amp; Unstable system.
        Time Domain Representations for Linear Time Invariant Systems. Convolution theorem, Convolution sum; 
        Correlation - Auto correlation and Cross correlation, Properties.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Fourier Representations of Signals:</b> Discrete time periodic signals - the discrete time Fourier series 
        Continuous time periodic signals - the Fourier series Discrete time non-periodic signals - 
        the discrete time Fourier transform Continuous time non-periodic signals - 
        the Fourier transform Properties of Fourier representations.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Laplace Transform:</b> Region of convergence, Inverse Laplace transform, Analysis of LTI systems using 
        Laplace transform.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Books:</b>   
        \n\n
        
        
        •	Communications Systems by Simon Haykin.
        \n\n
        
        •	Digital Signal Processing by Proakis and Manolakis.
        \n\n
        
        •	Signals and Systems, A.V. Oppenheim, A.S. Willsky and I.T. Young, Prentice Hall, 1983.
        \n\n
        
        •	Signals and Systems - Continuous and Discrete, R.F. Ziemer, W.H. Tranter and D.R. Fannin, 
        4th edition, Prentice Hall, 1998.
        \n\n
        
        •	Introduction to Signals and Systems, Douglas K. Lindner, Mc-Graw Hill International Edition: c1999.
        \n\n
        
        • 	Signals and Systems, Simon Haykin, Barry van Veen, John Wiley and Sons (Asia) Private Limited, c1998.
        \n\n
        
        •	Signals and Linear Systems, Robert A. Gabel, Richard A. Roberts, John Wiley and Sons (SEA) Private Limited, c1995.
        \n\n
        
        •	Principles of Communication: Systems, Modulation and Noise, 5th Edition by R. E. Ziemer.
        \n\n\n
        
        
        
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    <string name="ece_subject_code_and_name225">
        <b>ECE-215: Computer Architecture</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Overview of Computer Organization and architecture:</b> Organization and Structure, Structure and Functions, 
        Simple machine code sequence to illustrate action, system buses, interconnection structures 
        (Bus structure and bus types), Interrupts and instruction cycle.
        
        <b>Storage and Input/Output Systems:</b> Overview of memory system, memory chip organization and error correction, 
        cache memory, memory storage devices. Overview of I/O, programmed and interrupt-driven I/Os, 
        direct memory access (DMA).
        \n\n
        
        <b>Computer Arithmetic:</b> Integer representation and arithmetic, floating-point representation (IEEE), 
        floating-point arithmetic. Arithmetic and Logic Unit (ALU), Bit Sliced ALU.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Instruction Set and Register:</b> Computer function (fetch and execute cycles), interrupts, Machine instruction 
        characteristics, types of operands and operations, instruction functions, addressing modes, instruction formats, 
        instruction pipelining. 
        \n\n
        
        <b>Control Unit:</b> Micro-operations, hardwired control unit, control unit operation, micro-instruction 
        sequencing and execution, micro-programmed control unit.
        \n\n
        
        <b>High performance computer systems:</b> Techniques to achieve high performance, RISC, CISC, 
        introduction to superscalar processor, parallel processor, array processor. 
        \n\n
           
        <b>Recommended Books:</b>
        \n\n
        
        
        •	Computer Organization and Architecture, 6th edition, by William Stallings.
        \n\n
        
        •	Computer Architecture: A Quantitative Approach by John Hennessey.
        \n\n
        
        •	Computer Organization and Architecture: Designing for Performance (7th Edition) by William Stallings 
        (Hardcover - Jul 11, 2005)
        \n\n
        
        •	The Essentials of Computer Organization And Architecture by Linda Null and Julia Lobur 
        (Hardcover - Feb 15, 2006)
        \n\n
        
        •	Computer Organization by Carl Hamacher, Zvonko Vranesic, and Safwat Zaky (Hardcover - Aug 2, 2001)
        \n\n
        
        •	Schaum\'s Outline of Computer Architecture by Nick Carter (Paperback - Dec 26,2001)
        \n\n\n
        
               
    </string>
    
    
    
    <string name="ece_subject_code_and_name226">
        <b>ECE-216: Digital Electronics – II Lab</b>
        \n\n
        Based on course ECE-213 Digital Electronics – II.
        \n\n\n
        
    </string>

    
    <string name="ece_subject_code_and_name227">
        <b>ECE-217: Fundamentals of Communications Lab</b>
        \n\n
        
        Based on course ECE-211 Fundamentals of Communications.
        \n\n\n
                
    </string>
    
    
    <string name="ece_subject_code_and_name228">
        <b>ECE-219: Viva-Voce</b>
        \n\n
        
        Viva-voce is based on all the courses covered in the 4th semester.
	    \n\n\n
        
        
    </string>
    
</resources>