<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<resources>
    <string name="ece_subject_code_and_name311">
        <b>ECE-301: Electromagnetic Fields and Waves</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Static electric field:</b> Postulates of electrostatics, Coulomb\’s law for discrete and continuously
        distributed charges, Gauss\’s law and its applications, electric potential due to charge distribution,
        conductors and dielectrics in static electric field, flux density – boundary conditions; capacitance – 
        electrostatic energy and forces, energy in terms of field equations, capacitance calculations of different 
        geometries; boundary value problems – Poisson\’s and Laplace\’s equations in different co-ordinate systems,
        steady electric current, Ohm\’s law, continuity equation, Joule\’s law, resistance calculation.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Static magnetic field:</b> Postulates of magneto statics, Biot-Savart\’s law, Ampere\’s law and applications,
        vector magnetic potential, magnetic dipole, magnetization, magnetic field intensity and relative permeability, 
        boundary conditions for magnetic fields, magnetic energy, magnetic forces, torque and inductance for different 
        geometries.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Time varying fields and Maxwell\’s equations:</b> Faraday\’s law of electromagnetic induction, Maxwell\’s
        equations – differential and integral form, boundary conditions, potential functions, time harmonic fields 
        and Poynting theorem.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Plane electromagnetic waves:</b> Propagation and reflection of electromagnetic waves in unbounded media, 
        plane waves in loss-less media – Doppler effect, transverse electromagnetic waves, polarization of plane waves, 
        plane waves in lossy media, loss-less dielectrics, good conductors, group velocity, instantaneous and average 
        power densities, normal and oblique incidence of plane waves at plane boundaries for different polarizations.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Books:</b>
        \n\n
        
        
        •	Fundamentals of Electromagnetics with Engineering Applications, 2005, S.M. Wentworth.
        \n\n
        
        •	Fields and Waves in Communication Electronics, Simon Ramo, J.R. Whinnery, T.V. Duzer, 3rd Edition.
        \n\n
         
        •	Fields and Waves in Communication Electronics, 3rd Ed., 1989, S. Ramo, J.R. Whinnery and T. VanDuzer, Wiley.
        \n\n
        
        •	Elements of Electromagnetics, 3rd Ed., 2001, M.N.O. Sadiku, Oxford University Press.
        \n\n
        
        •	Electricity and Magnetism, K.K. Tewari.S. Chand &amp; Company Ltd.
        \n\n
         
        •	Electromagnetics, J.A. Edminister, TATA McGraw Hill Edition.
        \n\n
         
        •	Field and Wave Electromagnetics, David K. Cheng, Addison Wesley Publishing Co., 1992, 2nd Edition.
        \n\n\n 
                     
        
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    <string name="ece_subject_code_and_name312">
        <b>ECE-302: Numerical Analysis</b>
        \n\n
        
        Solution of equation in one variable (Fixed-point iteration Method, Newton Raphson Method, Error Analysis), 
        Interpolation polynomial for equal and unequal interval, Solving Systems of Linear Equations (Direct Method, 
        Gaussian elimination with backward substitution, using matrix operation), Numerical Solution of Ordinary 
        differential Equation (Euler Method, Runge-Kutta Method, Finite Difference Method), Numerical Differentiation 
        and Integration (Richardson\’s extrapolation method, Adaptive quadrature, Trapezoidal and Simpson\’s rule),
        Illustrative programming projects and use of computer to implement the projects.
        
        \n\n
        
        <b>Recommended books:</b> 
        \n\n
        
        
        •	Nymerical Analysis : Richard L Burden, J. Douglas Faires, 7th edition.
        \n\n
        
        •	Numerical Analysis, Vipin and Vasishtha.
        \n\n
        
        •	Numerical Analysis : J.H. Mathews, Numerical Mehods for Computer Science , Engineering and Mathematics, 
        Prentice-Hall, 1987
        \n\n\n	
        
               
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="ece_subject_code_and_name313">
        <b>ECE-303: Microprocessors &amp; Assembly Language</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Microprocessors:</b> Evaluation of Microprocessors, register and accumulator based microprocessor, 
        programmable logic device, memory organization, I/O techniques, 8086 microprocessor: internal architecture, 
        addressing modes, pin configuration and function, memory bank, interrupt interface, maximum/minimum mode interface, 
        read/write cycle.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Advanced Microprocessors:</b> Overview, internal architecture, memory management of 80186, 80286, 80386, and 
        80486 microprocessor. Overview of Pentium processor, co-processor, Alpha processor, and pipeline processor.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Assembly Language:</b> Types of assembler, assembly programming basics, instruction formats, 
        assembly instruction types: Data transfer instruction, Arithmetic and Logic instruction, 
        shift and rotate instruction, Transfer control and conditional processing, String processing, 
        Input/Output, Interrupts, Procedures and macro.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Books:</b>
        \n\n
        
        
        •	Microprocessor and microprocessor based system design by M. Rafiquzzaman.
        \n\n
        
        •	The 8088 and 8086 microprocessors by W. A. Triebel.
        \n\n
         
        •	Introduction to Microprocessors by John Crisp.
        \n\n
        
        •	INTEL Microprocessors 8086/8088, 80186/80188, 80286, 80386, 80486, Pentium, Prentium ProProcessor, 
        Pentium II, III, 4 by Barry B. Brey.
        \n\n
        
        •	The Art of Assembly Language by Randall Hyde.
        \n\n\n
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    <string name="ece_subject_code_and_name314">
        <b>ECE-304: Data Communications</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Introduction:</b> A data communication Model, Data Communication tasks, Data Communication 
        networks standards, Introduction to OSI and TCP/IP models.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Data Transmission:</b> Spectrum and bandwidth, Transmission impairments, 
        Channel capacity and data rate, transmission media- coaxial cable. twisted pair, fiber optics, 
        wireless transmission, electromagnetic spectrum, microwaves, radio waves, infrared and satellite communication.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Data Encoding:</b> Digital data and digital signaling, NRZL, NRZI. Bipolar AMI, Manchester and 
        differential Manchester encoding. Digital data and Analog signaling, ASK, FSK, PSK, QPSK, 
        QAM and their performance. Analog data and digital signaling – PCM, DM.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Data Transmission techniques:</b> Asynchronous and synchronous data transmission technique, 
        EIA 232 &amp; V.24 interface standard.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Data Link Control:</b> Flow control, Error Detection - Parity and CRC, Error correction and Hamming code, 
        Error Control (Stop and Wait, Go back N ARQ. Selective Reject ARQ), High-level Data Link Control (HDLC).
        \n\n
        
        <b>Multiplexing:</b> Frequency Division Multiplexing, Synchronous Time-Division Multiplexing, 
        Statistical Time- division Multiplexing, wavelength division multiplexing.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Data Communication Networking:</b> Circuit switching, Space division and TDM switching, 
        Packet switching, Virtual circuit and datagram.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Recommended books:</b>
        \n\n
        
        
        •	Data and Computer Communications, W. Stallings, Macmillan, 6th Edition.
        \n\n
         
        •	Computer Networks, A. S. Tanenbaum, Prentice Hall, 1996.
        \n\n
         
        •	Data Communications and Networking, 4/e, McGraw-Hill, Behrouz A. Forouzan.
        \n\n\n 
        
      
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    <string name="ece_subject_code_and_name315">
        <b>ECE-305: Electronic Materials</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Structural properties:</b> Crystalline, amorphous, polymer, binding force, elastic properties, 
        dislocations, defects, etc. Thermal and electrical properties: specific heat, thermal expansion, thermal conductivity.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Dielectric properties of solids:</b> Basic relationship and parameters, model of dielectric polarization, 
        ferroelectricity and piezo-electricity.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Optical properties of solids:</b> Classical theory, free carrier effects, lattice absorption, electrical absorption.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Magnetic properties of solids:</b> Atomic magnetic moments, dia and paramagnetism, ferromagnetism, anti ferromagnetism, 
        magnetic resonance.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Superconductivity:</b> Theory of superconductivity, superconductors and some applications.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Nano-Technology:</b> Carbon as a nano material, structure of carbon, carbon nanotube, quantum dots and nanowires.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Books:</b>
        \n\n
        
        
        •	Electronic Processes in Materials by Azaroff and Brophy.
        \n\n
        
        •	Semiconductor and Electronic Devices by Streetman.
        \n\n
        
        •	Handbook of Nano-structured  Materials and Nano Technology b H S Nawla.
        \n\n\n
             
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    <string name="ece_subject_code_and_name316">
        <b>ECE-306: Data Communications Lab</b>
        \n\n
        
        Based on course ECE-304 Data Communications. 
        \n\n\n
              
    </string>
    
    
    
    <string name="ece_subject_code_and_name317">
        <b>ECE-307: Microprocessors &amp; Assembly Language  Lab</b>
        \n\n
        
        Based on course ECE-303 Microprocessor and Assembly Language.
        \n\n\n
        
    </string>
    
</resources>