<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<resources>
    
    
    <string name="ece_subject_code_and_name121">
        <b>ECE-111: Physics – II (Modern Physics, Heat and Thermodynamics)</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Properties of Matter:</b> Atoms, Molecules and forces between them, Bonds – ionic, covalent, metallic,
        Hydrogen bond and Van Der Walls force, Crystals and their types, Defects and deformations.
        \n\n
                
        <b>Atomic Physics:</b> Wave particle duality, Photoelectric effect, Quantum theory of light, X-rays and X-ray diffraction, 
        Compton Effect, De Broglie waves, Phase and group velocities, Particle diffraction, Uncertainty principle. 
        \n\n
        
        <b>Atomic Structure:</b> Rutherford model of atom, Electron orbits, Atomic spectra, Bohr atom, 
        Energy levels and spectra, Atomic excitation.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Quantum Mechanics:</b> Wave function &amp; wave equation, Time dependent Schrödinger\’s equation,
        Particle in a box, Reflection and transmission by a barrier.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Heat and thermodynamics:</b> Temperature and thermometry, Thermal expansions and calorimetry, Heat transfer, 
        First law and second law of thermodynamics with simple applications, Properties of thermodynamic substances.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Books:</b>
        \n\n
        
       
        •	Concepts of Modern Physics by Arthur Beiser.
        \n\n
        		
        •	Fundamentals of Classical Thermodynamics, Richard E. Sonntag, 
        Claus Borgnakke and Gordon V. Van Wylen., 6th ed., John Wiley &amp; Sons, 1998.
        \n\n
        
        •	Engineering Thermodynamics by S.L. Somasundaram.
        \n\n
        
        •	Fundamentals of Engineering Thermodynamics, Michael J. Moran and Howard N. Shapiro, John Wiley &amp; Sons.
        \n\n\n

    </string>

    
    
    
     <string name="ece_subject_code_and_name122">
        <b>ECE-112: Math – III:Differential Equations and Complex Variables</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Ordinary Differential Equation:</b> Degree and order of ordinary differential equations, 
        Formation of differential equations, Solution of first order differential equations by various methods, 
        Solution of first order but higher degree ordinary differential equations, 
        Solution of general linear equations of second and higher orders with constant coefficients, 
        Solution of homogeneous linear equations and its applications.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Complex Variables:</b> Complex number system, General functions of a complex variable, 
        Limits and continuity of a function of complex variable and related theorems, 
        Complex differentiation and the Cauchy-Riemann Equations, Mapping by elementary functions, 
        Line integral of a complex function, Cauchy\’s Integral Theorem, Cauchy\’s Integral Formula,
        Liouville\’s Theorem, Laurent\’s Theorem. Singular points, Residue, Cauchy\’s Residue theorem.
        Evaluation of residues, Contour integration, conformal mapping.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Books:</b>
        \n\n
        
        
        •	Ordinary Differential Equation by B.D. Sharma.
        \n\n
        
        •	Complex Variables by Schaum\’s Outlines Series.
        \n\n
        
        •	Functions of a complex variable by Dewan Abdul Quddus.
        \n\n
        
        •	Functions of a complex variable by Kedar Nath Ram Nath.
        \n\n
        
        •	Laplace Transform by Schaums Outline Series.
        \n\n\n
        
      
    </string>
    

     
    <string name ="ece_subject_code_and_name123">
        <b>ECE-113: Electrical Circuits – I</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Electric current and Ohm\’s law:</b> Modern electron theory of electricity,
        Effect of temperature of resistance, EMF and potential difference, Ohm\’s law,
        Electric power and energy, Heating effect of current, Concept of alternating current (AC), 
        AC waveforms, Average and effective values of AC signals.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Laws of DC Circuit:</b> Kirchhoff\’s voltage and current laws, Series and parallel networks;
        Network analysis - methods of branch and loop currents, Mesh analysis, nodal analysis, Bridge networks, 
        Delta-Way conversion; Thevenin\’s and Norton\’s theorems, Maximum power transfer theorem, Millman\’s theorem,
        Reciprocity theorem.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Capacitive and Inductive Circuits:</b> Capacitance and dielectrics, Capacitors in series and parallel, 
        Energy storage, Transients in RC circuits, Initial values; Magnetic field, Flux density, Permeability, 
        reluctance, Ohm\’s law for magnetic field, Magnetizing force, Inductance, Induced voltage, RL transients,
        Initial values, Inductors in series and parallel, RLC circuits with DC source.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Books:</b>
        \n\n
        
        •	Introductory circuit Analysis by Robert L. Boylestad, 10th edition.
        \n\n
        
        •	Introduction to Electric Circuits 5th edition by Richard C. Dorf.
        \n\n
        
        •	Electric Circuits Fundamentals, 5th edition by Thomas L. Floyd.
        \n\n
         
        •	Electrical Circuit Analysis, Hayt and Kemmerly, published by McGraw-Hill.
        \n\n
        
        •	A text Book of Electrical Technologies by B.L. Theraja.
        \n\n\n

    </string> 
    

    
    
    <string name="ece_subject_code_and_name124">
        
        <b>ECE-114: Electronic Circuits – I</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Semiconductor Diode:</b> Introduction to semiconductors, p-type and n-type semiconductors; 
        p-n junction diode characteristics, diode load line, Diode applications: half and full wave rectifiers, 
        clipping and clamping circuits, regulated power supply using Zener diode, LED and photo diodes.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Bipolar Junction Transistor (BJT):</b> Construction and operation, amplifying action, 
        Transistor circuit configurations (CE, CB, CC), BJT biasing, relations between alpha and beta, 
        leakage current in a transistor, Thermal runaway of a transistor, I-V characteristics, 
        DC load line and Q point, transistor biasing factor, effect on bias variations, 
        stability factor for CB and CE configuration, different methods of transistor biasing, AC load line.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Field Effect Transistors (FET):</b> JFET construction, operation and characteristics, biasing of FET, 
        MOSFET construction, operation and characteristics, depletion and enhancement type MOSFETs, 
        biasing and application of depletion and enhancement MOSFETs.
        \n\n
        
        <b>BJT small signal amplifier circuit analysis:</b> BJT Amplifiers CE, CB, CC configurations, 
        DC analysis of transistor circuits, Collector feedback configuration, h-parameter model of transistor. 
        Relationship between CC, CB, CE parameters, expressions for voltage gain, current gain, 
        input resistance and output resistance. Effects of coupling and bypass capacitor. Hybrid Pi equivalent circuit, 
        gain bandwidth product, Frequency response, Frequency compensation, Low frequency compensation, 
        High frequency compensation, Cascade amplifier.
        \n\n
        
        <b>FET small signal amplifier analysis:</b> Amplifier with source resistance, Small signal model, 
        AC small signal operation, Loading effect, Source follower (common drain) circuit, Common gate circuit, 
        Design of FET amplifier circuits (CS, CD and CG).
        \n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Books:</b>
        \n\n
        
        
        •	Electronic Devices by Floyd – 5th edition.
        \n\n
        
        •	Micro-electronics by Jacob Millman and Arvin Grabel.
        \n\n
        
        •	Electronics Devices and Circuits Theory by Robert L. Boylestad, Louis Nashelsky.
        \n\n
        
        •	OpAmp Applications Handbook, (Analog Devices Inc., edited by Walt Jang).
        \n\n
        
        •	Schaum\'s Outline of Electronic Devices and Circuits, Second Edition, by Jim Cathey.
        \n\n\n

                
    </string>

    
    
    <string name="ece_subject_code_and_name125">
        
        <b>ECE-115: Digital Electronics – I</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Number Systems and Codes:</b> Decimal, binary, Octal and hexadecimal number systems and conversion, 
        BCD, Alphanumeric, Grey, Excess-3, ASCII codes.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Digital Logic:</b> Boolean algebra, De Morgan\’s theorem, Logic gates and their truth tables,
        Canonical form of logic expressions.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Combinational Logic Circuits:</b> Sum of Products form (SOP), Product of Sum form (POS), Max term, 
        Min term, Algebraic simplification, designing combinational logic circuits, Simplification using K-map, 
        K-map and don\’t care term.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Flip-Flops and Related Devices:</b> Sequential circuits, NAND gate latch, NOR gate latch, 
        Clock signal and clocked flip-flops, Asynchronous inputs of flip-flops, flip-flop timing considerations, 
        Race-around condition, master-slave flip-flop, Flip-flop applications, Design of synchronous and asynchronous counters, 
        Ring counter, Johnson counter, Different types of registers, Application of counter.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Arithmetic Circuits:</b> Half adder, Parallel binary adder, Parallel binary adder with register, 
        Parallel adder ICs, 2\’s complement system and circuit, BCD adder, Subtract circuit, Multiplier circuit.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Integrated Circuit Logic Families:</b> TTL logic family, Standard TTL and other TTL series characteristics, 
        TTL open collector output, Tristate TTL, ECL family and its characteristics, MOS, PMOS, NMOS, and CMOS families.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Recommended books:</b>
        \n\n
        
        
        •	Principles of Digital Electronics by T.J. Tocci.
        \n\n
        
        •	Modern Digital Electronics by R.P. Jain.
        \n\n
        
        •	Digital electronics by by Morris Mano.
        \n\n
        
        •	Digital Systems by M. Lutfar Rahman.
        \n\n

    </string>
    
     
    <string name="ece_subject_code_and_name126">
        
        <b>ECE-206: Electrical Circuits – I Lab</b>
        \n\n
        
        Based on course ECE-113
        \n\n\n
        
    </string>  
    
    
    <string name="ece_subject_code_and_name127">
        
        <b>ECE-206: Electronic Circuits – I Lab</b>
        \n\n
        
        Based on course ECE-114 and ECE-115
        \n\n\n
        
    </string>
</resources>