<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    
    
    <string name="subject_code_and_name111">
        <b>ECE-101: English</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Reading and Comprehension:</b> Thematic structure, vocabulary, cohesive and rhetorical devices, 
        grammatical items, intention/attitude of the writer, précis (i) comprehension (ii) paragraph (iii) précis 
        (iv) essay (v) amplification (vi) dialogue-writing.
        \n\n
        
         <b>Structures: The sentence:</b>
         \n
        Normal group – a) determiners b) adverb c) adjective d) non-adjective e) headword f) prepositional phrase 
        g) infinitive phrase h) participle phrase i) appositive.
        \n
        Verbal group – a) the tenses b) the modal auxiliaries c) phrasal verbs.
        \n
        Verb Modifiers – a) adverbials of time b) adverbials of place c) adverbials of manner 
        d) adverbials of duration, Completing sentences, correction of sentences, transformation of sentences, 
        framing of which questions.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Notions and Functions:</b> i) emotion attitudes ii) moral attitudes iii) suasion iv) intellectual attitudes 
        v) socializing.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Letters:</b> Application, Request, Enquiries, Quotations, Tender to newspaper, Formal and informal, 
        Advertisements, etc.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Translations:</b> English to Bengali  and Bengali  to English.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Technical Writing:</b> Projects, reports, and thesis.
        \n\n
        
        
        <b>Recommended books:</b>
        \n\n
        
        
        •	Advanced Learners functional English by Chowdhury &amp; Hossain.
        \n\n
              
        •	Oxford English for Computing by Boeckner, Keith, and Brown.
        \n\n
        
        •	High School English Grammar and Composition by Waren &amp; Martin.
        \n\n\n


    </string>

    
    
    
    <string name="subject_code_and_name112">
        
        <b>ECE-102: Physics-I (Electricity, Magnetism, &amp; Optics)</b>
        \n\n
        
        
        <b>Electrostatics:</b> Electronic charge, Conservation &amp; quantization of charge, Coulomb\’s law,
        Electric field and field strength, Lines of force, Point charge and dipole in an electric field, 
        Electric flux &amp; Gauss\’s law, Applications of Gauss\’s law, Electric potential and field strength,
        Potential due to a point charge, Group of point charges, Potential due to continuous charge distribution, 
        Electric potential energy.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Capacitance and Dielectrics:</b> Capacitance, calculation of capacitance, 
        Parallel plate capacitor with and without dielectric, Dielectric – an atomic view, Gauss\’s law for capacitor,
        The three electric vectors, Energy storage in an electric field.
        \n\n
        
        
        <b>Magnetism and Electromagnetism:</b> The magnetic field, Definition of B, permeability of a medium, 
        Magnetic force on a current, Torque on a current loop, Circulating charges, Ampere\’s law, Lines of magnetic induction,
        Force between two parallel current carrying conductors, B for a solenoid, Biot-Savart law, 
        Faraday\’s law of electromagnetic induction, Lenz\’s law, Time varying magnetic field,
        Inductance and calculation of inductance; Magnetic properties of matter - paramagnetism, diamagnetism, 
        ferromagnetism, Intensity of magnetization, Magnetization curve, Hysteresis, the three magnetic vectors, 
        Gauss\’s law for magnetism, Magnetic induction and susceptibility, Magnetic circuit, Ampere turns,
        Comparison between magnetic and electric circuits.
        \n\n
        
        
        <b>Optics:</b> Optical interference, Young\’s experiment, Coherence, Intensity in Young\’s experiment,
        Thin Film interference, Newton\’s rings, Michelson\’s interferometer, Diffraction, Diffraction grating,
        Polarization, Double refraction, Optical activity.
        \n\n
        
        
        
        <b>Recommended Books:</b>
        \n\n
        
        •	Physics Part-II by David Halliday &amp; Robert Resnick.
        \n\n
        
        •	Fundamentals of Physics by Halliday &amp; Robert Resnick.
        \n\n\n


    </string>
    
    
    
    
    <string name="subject_code_and_name113">
        
        <b>ECE-103: Math-I: Differential &amp; Integral Calculus</b>
        \n\n
        
        
        <b>Differential Calculus:</b> Limits, Continuity and differentiability; 
        Successive differentiation of various types of functions; Leibnitz\`s theorem; Rolle\`s  theorem;
        Mean value theorem in finite and infinite forms; Lagrange\`s form of remainders; Cauchy\`s form of remainder;
        Evaluation of indeterminate forms by L\` Hospitals rule; Partial differentiation;
        Euler\`s Theorem; Maximum and minimum values of functions of single variable.
        \n\n
        
        
        <b>Integral Calculus:</b> Definitions of integration; Integration by the method of substitutions; 
        Integration by parts; Standard integrals; Integration by the method of successive reduction; 
        Definite integrals and its properties and use in summing series; Beta function and Gamma function.
        \n\n
        
        
        <b>Recommended Books:</b>
        \n\n
        
        •	Integral Calculus by Anton.
        \n\n
        
        •	Integral Calculus by Abdul Matin.
        \n\n
        
        •	Integral Calculus by  Khose Mohammad.
        \n\n
        
        •	Integral Calculus by B.C. Das and B. N. Mukharjhee.
        \n\n
        
        •	Differential Calculus by B.C. Das and B. N. Mukharjhee.
        \n\n
        
        •	Ordinary Differential Equation by B.D. Sharma
        \n\n\n
        
    </string>    
    
    
    
    <string name="subject_code_and_name114">
        
        <b>ECE-104: Math-II: Linear Algebra</b>
        \n\n
        
        Vectors in Rn, Different operations on vectors, Dot product and cross product, Norm and distance in Rn, 
        Cauchy Schwartz theorem, Minkowski\’s inequality.
        \n
        
        Linear equations and system of linear equations, Solution of linear equations.
        \n
        
        Matrix, Different operations on matrix, Transpose matrix, square matrix, Inverse matrix, symmetric matrix.
        \n
        
        Vector space and subspace.
        \n
        
        Linear dependence and independence on vector space, Basis and dimensions, Rank of matrix, Coordinates.
        \n
        
        Linear mapping, Different types of mapping, Kernel and image of linear mappings, Singular and non-singular mappings, 
        Isomorphism, Matrix Representation.
        \n
        
        Eigen values and Eigen vectors.
        \n\n
        
        
        <b>Recommended Books:</b>
        \n\n
        •	Linear Algebra, Schaums Outline Series.
        \n\n
        
        •	Linear Algebra by Abdur Rahman.
        \n\n
    
     </string>    

    
    
    
    <string name="subject_code_and_name115">
        
    <b>ECE-105: Fundamentals of Computer &amp; Programming</b>
    \n\n
    
    
    <b>Introduction:</b> 
    \n
    
    Data and Information, History of Computer, Computer Generations, Types of Computer: Mainframe, 
    Mini and Microcomputer, Different types of Micro Computer, Expanded Computer System, Number Systems: Binary, 
    Decimal, Octal and Hexadecimal numbers, Classification of Hardware and Software, Input and Output Devices, 
    Primary and Secondary Storage Devices.
    \n\n

    <b>Programming in C:</b>
    \n
    <b>Introduction:</b> A Simple C program, Preparing and Running a C Program.
    \n\n
    
    <b>C Fundamentals:</b> Character Set, Identifiers, Keywords, Data Types, Constants, Variables, Declarations, 
    Expressions, Statements, Symbolic Constants.
    \n\n
    
    <b>Operators and Expressions:</b>  Operators, Types of Operators, Library Functions, Data input and output, 
    preparing and running a complete C program.
    \n\n
    
    <b>Control Structures:</b>  Branching: if, if.else, nested if, ladder if, switch, break, Looping: while, do-while, 
    for, Nested control structures.
    \n\n
    
    <b>Functions:</b>  Definition and Declaration, Accessing, Processing, Function Prototypes, Passing arguments, 
    Function Calling and Returning Values.
    \n\n
    
    <b>Arrays:</b> Definition and declaration, Types of arrays, processing an Array, Passing arrays to functions.
    \n\n
    
    <b>Pointers:</b>  Definitions and declarations, Passing pointer to functions, Dynamic Memory Allocations, 
    Operations on Pointers, Arrays of Pointers.
    \n\n
    
    <b>Structures and Unions:</b> Definition, Processing, User Defined Data Types, Structure and Pointers, 
    Passing Structures to Functions, Unions.
    \n\n
    
    <b>Data Files:</b> Definition and Declaration, Types of data files, Creating, Opening, closing and processing files.
    \n\n
    
    <b>Recommended Books:</b>
    \n\n
    •	Computer Fundamentals by M. Lutfar Rahman and M. Alamgir Hossain.
    \n\n
    
    •	Programming in C (3rd Edition) (Developer\'s Library) by Stephen Kochan.
    \n\n
    
    •	The C Programming Language (2nd Edition) by Brian W. Kernighan, Dennis Ritchie, and Dennis M. Ritchie.
    \n\n
    
    •	Absolute Beginner\'s Guide to C (2nd Edition) by Greg Perry.
    \n\n
    
    •	C Programming for the Absolute Beginner (For the Absolute Beginner Series) by Michael Vine.
    \n\n
    
    •	C Programming: A Modern Approach, Second Edition by K. N. King.
    \n\n
    
    •	C by Example (Cambridge Computer Science Texts) by Noel Kalicharan.
    \n\n\n
   </string>
   
    
    
    
    <string name="subject_code_and_name116">
        <b>ECE-106: Physics – 1 Lab</b>
        \n\n
            Based on ECE-102 Physics – 1.
            \n\n
        
    </string>
    
    
    <string name="subject_code_and_name117">
        <b>ECE-107: Fundamentals of Computer &amp; Programming Lab</b>
        \n\n

        Based on ECE-107 Fundamentals of Computer &amp; Programming.
        \n\n\n
    </string>

</resources>