<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<resources>
    
    <string name="ece_subject_code_and_name211">
        
        <b>ECE-201: Statistics &amp; Probability:</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Statistics:</b> \n Frequency distribution of data: Population and sample, Collection and representation of 
        statistical data. Tabulation of data. Class intervals. Frequency distribution, discrete, continuous and 
        cumulative distributions. Histograms and frequency polygons. Graphical representation of data.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Statistical Measures:</b> \n Measures of central tendency – arithmetic mean, median, mode, geometric mean, 
        weighted average, harmonic mean. Measures of dispersion – range, standard deviation, variance, coefficient of 
        variation, moments, skewness, kurtosis. Correlation theory: Linear correlation, Measures of correlation and 
        its significance. Regression and curve fitting: Linear and non-linear regression, Methods of least squares. 
        Curve fitting.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Probability:</b> \n Definition of probability and related concepts. Laws of probability, 
        Conditional probability and Baye\’s theorem, Discrete and continuous random variables, Probabiloty mass functions,
        probability density function, Joint Distribution, Marginal and conditional distribution, 
        Independence of Random Variables, Mathematical expectations. Probability distributions: Binomial, Poisson and Normal 
        distributions and their properties.  
        \n\n
        
        <b>Covariance, correlation and regression: </b> \n simple correlation, measures of correlation and its significance, 
        regression and curve fitting, Linear and non-linear regression. Methods of Least squares and curve fitting, 
        Rank correlation.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Fundamentals of time series:</b> \n Introduction to time series.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Books:</b>
        \n\n
        
        
        •	An Introduction to Statistics by S.P Gupta and M.P Gupta.
        \n\n
        
        •	Theory and Problem of Statistics by Schaum\’s Outlines Series.
        \n\n
        
        •	Basic Statistics by Abdul Jalil and Rezina Ferdouse.
        \n\n
        
        •	Understanding Statistics by Graham Upton and Ian Cook.
        \n\n
        
        •	An Introduction to Statistics and Probability by Dr. Nurul Islam.
        \n\n\n\n\n

        
    </string>
    
    
    
    <string name="ece_subject_code_and_name212">
        
        <b>ECE-202: Math-IV: Engineering Mathematics</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Fourier Analysis: </b> \n Real and complex form of Fourier series; Finite transform; Fourier Integral; 
        Fourier transforms and their uses in solving boundary value problems of wave equations.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Laplace Transforms:</b> \n Definition; Laplace transforms of some elementary functions; Sufficient conditions 
        for existence of Laplace transforms; Inverse Laplace transforms; Laplace transforms of derivatives. 
        The unit step function. 
        \n
        
       Periodic function. Some special theorems on Laplace transforms; Solutions of differential equations by Laplace 
       transforms.
       \n\n
       
       <b>Vector Algebra and Vector Calculus: </b> \n Additions, subtractions, dot and cross products, triple product 
       and their geometrical interpretation and application, differentiation and integration of vectors, 
       line surface and volume integrals, gradient, divergence, curl and their physical significance, 
       divergence theorem and Gauss\’s theorem and their applications.
       \n\n\n
       
       <b>Recommended Books:</b>
       \n\n
       
       
       •	Mathematical Methods by Abdur Rahman.
       \n\n
       
       •	Fourier Transform by Schaums Outline.
       \n\n
       
       •	Laplace Transform by Schaums Outline.
       \n\n
       
       •	Physical Mathematics by B.D. Gupta.
       \n\n\n\n\n 
        
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    <string name="ece_subject_code_and_name213">
        
        <b>ECE-203: Electrical Circuits – II</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>AC Fundamentals: </b> \n Basic principles of AC generators, Equations of alternating voltage and current, 
        Attributes of a sinusoidal signal, Phase relations, Average value, RMS value, Form factor, Vector diagrams, 
        Addition of two AC equations; Response of basic R, L, and C elements to sinusoidal voltage and current, 
        Frequency response of basic elements, Average power and power factor, complex Numbers, Rectangular form, 
        Polar form, conversion between forms, Phasors.
        \n\n 
        
        <b>Series and Parallel AC circuits:</b> \n Impedance and Phasor diagrams, AC through series RL circuits, 
        Frequency response of series RL circuits, AC through series RC circuits, Admittance and susceptance, 
        AC power, Power factor, Power triangle, Series R-L-C circuits and resonance; Parallel AC circuit with R, L, 
        and C, Resonance in parallel RLC circuit, quality factor.
        \n\n
        
        <b>AC Network Analysis in Frequency domain: </b> \n Mesh circuit method, Node voltage method, Equivalent Y and Δ connections.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Polyphase Circuits: </b> \n Three-phase generator, Y connected generator with Y connected load, Y-Δ systems, 
        Δ connected generator, Systems with unbalanced loads.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Filters and Two Port Networks: </b> \n One port and two port networks, High pass, low pass, band pass networks and 
        filters, Hay power frequencies.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Complex Frequency: </b> \n Network analysis in the S domain, Network response in the S plane, 
        natural response and forced response.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Fourier Methods: </b> \n Trigonometric and exponential Fourier series, Waveform symmetry, Line spectrum, 
        Effective values and power, Application in circuit analysis.
        \n\n
        
        <b>The Laplace Transform: </b> \n Selected Laplace transforms, Initial value and final value theorems, 
        Partial fraction expansions, etc.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Books:</b>
        \n\n
        
        
        •	Introductory Circuit Analysis by Robert Boylested.
        \n\n
        
        •	A Textbook of Electrical Technology by B.L. Theraja.
        \n\n
        
        •	Schaums Outline Series on Theory and Problem of Electric Circuits by Joseph A. Edminister.
        \n\n\n\n\n

        
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    <string name="ece_subject_code_and_name214">
        
        <b>ECE-204: Electronic Circuits – II</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Feedback Amplifier: </b> \n Principle of feedback amplifier, Positive and negative feedback, 
        Advantages of negative feedback - gain stability, Decreased distortion, increased bandwidth, 
        Forms of negative feedback, Practical negative feedback circuits.
        \n\n
               
        <b>Power Amplifiers:</b> \n Classification of large signal amplifiers - class A, AB, B and C, Harmonic distortion, 
        efficiency and figure of merit of class A, AB, B; transformer - coupled amplifiers, 
        push pull amplifiers, Complementary symmetry amplifiers, Tuned amplifiers - Single tuned circuits using 
        BJTs and FETs, Impedance transformations and transformer coupling, Narrow band tuned amplifiers, Cascade 
        tuned amplifiers, Synchronous and stagger tuning, Neutralization.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Oscillators:</b> \n Sinusoidal oscillators, the Barkhausen criterion, Practical considerations, 
        Analysis and design of RC phase shift oscillators, Hartley and Colpitts oscillators. 
        Amplitude stabilizations, Crystal oscillators, Frequency stability, Stability criterion.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Operational Amplifiers:</b> \n Difference amplifier; CMMR; Ideal operational amplifier; Inverting amplifier; 
        Non-inverting amplifier; General-purpose IC operational amplifier; Integrator; Differentiator, adder, Voltage follower, 
        Reference voltage source, V to I and I to V converter, Current amplifiers, Charge amplifiers, Differential amplifier, 
        Instrumentation amplifier, Log and antilog amplifiers, Function generators, Precision rectifiers, Comparators, 
        Window comparators, Schmitt trigger, Miller Sweep, Bootstrap sweep, Analog multiplier, Analog divider, Square rooters.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Books:</b>
        \n\n
        
        
        •	Electronics Devices and Circuits Theory by Robert L. Boylestad, Louis Nashelsky.
        \n\n
        
        •	Op-Amp and Linear Integrated Circuits by  R.L. Gayakawad.
        \n\n
        
        •	Op-Amp and Linear Integrated Circuits by  R.F. Caoughlin.
        \n\n
        
        •	Schaum\'s Outline of Electronic Devices and Circuits, Second Edition, by Jim Cathey.
        \n\n
        
        •	Pulse and Digital Electronics by G.K. Mithal.
        \n\n
        
        •	Pulse and Digital Switching Waveforms by Millman and Taub.
        \n\n\n\n\n
         
        
    </string>
 
    
    
    
    <string name="ece_subject_code_and_name215">
        
        <b>ECE-205: Object Oriented Programming</b>
        \n\n
        
        Principles of object oriented programming, Beginning with C++, Tokens, Expressions and Control Structure, 
        Functions in C++, Classes and Objects, Constructors and Destructors, Operator overloading and type conversion, 
        Inheritance, Extending Classes, Pointers, virtual functions and Polymorphism, Managing console I/O operations, 
        Working with files.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommended books:</b>
        \n\n
        
        
        •	Object-Oriented Programming with C++ by E. Balagurusamy.
        \n\n
        
        •	Teach Yourself C++ by Herbert Schildt.
        \n\n
        
        •	Turbo C++ The Complete Reference by Herbert Schildt.
        \n\n
        
        •	Turbo C++ by Robert Lafore.
        \n\n\n\n\n
           
    </string>

    
    
    <string name="ece_subject_code_and_name216">
        
        <b>ECE-206: Electrical Circuits – II Lab</b>
        \n\n
        
        Based on course ECE-203 Electrical Circuits – II. 
        \n\n\n\n\n 
    
    </string>

    
    
    <string name="ece_subject_code_and_name217">
        
        <b>ECE-207: Object Oriented Programming Lab</b>
        \n\n
        
        Based on course ECE-205 Object Oriented Programming.
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
    </string>
    
    
    <string name="ece_subject_code_and_name218">
        <b>ECE-208: Electronic Circuits – II Lab</b>
        \n\n
        
        Based on course ECE-204 Electronic Circuits – II.
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
    </string>
    
    
    
</resources>