<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<resources>
    <string name="subject_code_and_name411">
        <b>ECE-401: Microwave Engineering</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Introduction:</b> VHF, UHF and microwave frequency ranges. 
        \n\n
        
        <b>Microwave transmission lines:</b> Transmission line equation and solution, 
        Reflection and transmission coefficient, Standing wave and standing wave ratio, 
        Smith chart, impedance transformation and matching.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Waveguides and components:</b> Rectangular waveguide, Circular waveguide, Waveguide components, 
        cavities and resonators, Directional couplers, Circulators and isolators.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Microstrip Lines:</b> Wave propagation and micro strip lines, dielectric constants, characteristic impedance, 
        attenuation factors.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Microwave Devices:</b> Microwave transistor, Varactor diode, IMPATT diode, Gunn diode, Schottky barrier diode, 
        Backward diode, Point contact diode, Klystron, Reflex Klystron, TWT and magnetron. 
        \n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Books:</b>
        \n\n
        
        
        •	Electronic Communication Systems by Kennedy, McGraw-Hill.
        \n\n
         
        •	Fields and Waves in Communication Technology, S. Ramo, J.R. Whinnery, Th. van Duzer, John Wiley &amp; Sons, Inc.
        \n\n
         
        •	Foundations for Microwave Engineers, R. E. Collin, IEEE (John Wiley &amp; Sons).
        \n\n
        
        •	Microwave Transistors, Amplifiers, Analysis and Design by Guillermo Gonzalez, Prentice Hall.
        \n\n
        
        •	Microwave Engineering by David M Pozar by John Wiley.
        \n\n
        
        •	Microwave Devices and Circuits by Leo, Prentice Hall.
        \n\n
         
        •	Foundations for Microwave Engineering by R E Collins, McGraw-Hill.
        \n\n\n
        
    </string>
  
    
    
    
    <string name="subject_code_and_name412">
        <b>ECE-402: Wireless Communication Systems</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Digital Modulation Technique:</b> Modern communication systems, BPSK, DPSK, QPSK, OQPSK, MSK, GMSK, MFSK, 
        Spread spectrum modulation techniques, DS-SS, FH-SS, Multipath channels, intelligent cells, micro and nano cells.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Satellite Communication:</b> Introduction, Orbits, Station Peeping. Satellite altitude, Transmission path, 
        Path loss, Noise consideration, Satellite system, Saturation flux density, Effective isotropic radiated power, 
        Multiple access methods, Earth station antenna, satellite link, design, frequency plan, Satellite communication 
        for Internet, VSAT Network, GNSS-GPS and Galileo Systems, GIS, Multiple Access Techniques.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Mobile Communication:</b> Mobile-Multimedia traffic, Flow control, Bandwidth allocation, Channels, lst, 
        2nd and 3rd generation wireless networks. Cellular mobile system engineering. 
        \n\n
        
        <b>Free-space propagation:</b> Propagation model. Multipath propagation, Propagation environment, Marine environment.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Microcells:</b> Two Ray Model, Freznel Zone, RF cove¬rage, Indoor coverage, Outdoor coverage, 
        computer aided Techniques, Single coverage plot, composite coverage plot, RF survey, Cellular traffic, 
        Trunking efficiencies. 
        \n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Books:</b>
        \n\n
        
        
        •	Introduction to Wireless Systems, Shankar P.M, Wiley, 2002.
        \n\n
        
        •	Fundamentals of Wireless Communication, Tse D. and Viswanath P., Cambridge, 2005.
        \n\n
        
        •	Wireless Communications and Networking, Stallings W., Prentice Hall 1st Edition, 2001.
        \n\n
        
        •	Satellite Communication Systems: Systems, Techniques, and Technology, Maral G. and Bousquet M., Wiley 4th 
        Edition, 2002, ISBN 0-471-49654-5.
        \n\n
        
        •	Mobile Satellite Communication Networks, Sheriff R.E. and Fun Hun Y., Wiley, 2001.
        \n\n\n

        
        
    </string>
    
</resources>