<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<resources>
    <string name="ece_subject_code_and_name421">
        <b>ECE-411: Information Theory and Coding</b>
        \n\n
        
      <b>Block and Convolutional Codes for High Spectral Efficiency:</b> \n Trellis Coded Modulation (TCM), Coding with Diversity. 
      Turbo Codes.
      \n\n
      
      <b>Iterative Decoding:</b> \n MAP Algorithms. ARQ schemes. General concepts of coding theory. Noise and error correcting codes. 
      Linear codes including the Hamming, Golary, the Reed-Muller codes, Finite and Number Fields. Algebraic Function fields, 
      algebraic curves and their applications, Cyclic codes (including the BCH, Reed-Solomon, Justesen, Goppa, and Quadratic 
      Residue codes). Decoding techniques for some of these codes. Application to information processing.
      \n\n
       
      <b>Information measures:</b> \n Entropy, relative entropy, and mutual information, Asymptotic equipartition theory, Entropy rates, 
      source coding and data compression, unannei capacity, Differential entropy and Gaussian channel, Rate-distortion theory.
      \n\n\n
      
      <b>Recommended Books:</b>
      \n\n
      
      
      •	Information and Coding Theory (Springer Undergraduate Mathematics Series) by Gareth A. Jones, J.Mary Jones.
      \n\n
      
      •	Theory of Information &amp; Coding by Robert McEliece.
      \n\n
      
      •	Fundamentals of Information Theory and Coding Design (Discrete Mathematics and Its Applications) by Roberto Togneri, 
      Christopher J. S. Desilva.
      \n\n
      
     
      •	Digital Communication by Simon Haykins.
      \n\n
      
      •	Information Theory by Thomas &amp; Cover.
      \n\n
       
      •	The Theory of Information and Coding: Student Edition (Encyclopedia of Mathematics and its Applications) by R. J. 
      McEliece (Hardcover - Aug 2, 2004)
      \n\n\n\n\n
          
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    <string name="ece_subject_code_and_name422">
        <b>ECE-412: Biomedical Instruments</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Human Anatomy &amp; Physiology:</b> \n Anatomy &amp; Physiology of major systems of the body - generation &amp; 
        propagation of Bioelectric potentials.Transducers, Leads &amp; Electrodes: Transducers for biological applications 
        types, properties, characteristics &amp; selection.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Leads &amp; Electrodes:</b> \n Types, materials, properties, characteristics. Method of application and 
        selection - equivalent circuits of leads &amp; electrodes. Fundamentals of biomaterials: Compatability studies of 
        metals, ceramic plastics used in the inplantable devices.
        \n\n
        
        <b>EEG :</b> \n Working principles, lead system &amp; clinical applications.
        \n\n
        
        <b>EMG :</b> \n Working principles, &amp; clinical applications. Evoked potential systems, Audiometry.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Theraputic instruments:</b> \n Diathermy, defibrilletor, cardiac pacemakers, stimulators. Power source for 
        implantable devices.Laser Applications in machine. 
        \n\n
        
        <b>X-Rays:</b> \n Production &amp; use in machine, basics of radiography, diagnostic &amp; therapeutic - X-Ray film 
        construction and processing, interaction with body. Fundamentals of Radiation Therapy.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Blood pressure:</b> \n Diastolic &amp; Systolic measurement by invasive and non invasive methods - Ultra sound, 
        Spygmomanometer Automated methods - direct methods.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Blood flow:</b> \n Electro-magnetic, Ultrasound, Blood cell counters. Applications of Ultra sound-basic physics 
        of Ultra sound generation, Echo cardiography, Modes of Scan, Doppler measurements, Biological effects - colour doppler.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommended books:</b>
        \n\n
        
        
        •	Principles of Applied Biomedical Instrumentation, Geddes &amp; Baker.
        \n\n
         
        •	Biomedical Instrumentation and Measurements, Cromwel.
        \n\n
         
        •	Hand book of Bio -medical Instrumentation, R.S. Kandpur.
        \n\n
         
        •	Fundamental Physics of Radiography, Massey &amp; Meridith.
        \n\n
         
        •	Medical Physics , Christanson.
        \n\n
         
        •	Hand book of Analytical Equipment, R.S. Kandpur.
        \n\n\n\n\n
	
    
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    <string name="ece_subject_code_and_name423">
        <b>ECE-413: Network Security</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Cryptography and Cryptography Algorithms:</b> \n Traditional cryptography, Cryptanalysis, Private-key (Symmetric-key) 
        and Public-key (asymmetric-key) cryptographic algorithms, DES and Block cipher modes, Advanced Encryption Standard 
        (AES), RSA and other public key cryptosystems, Key Management, Diffie-Hellman key exchange, Elliptic curve cryptography. 
        Cryptographic hash functions, Secure Hash Algorithms, Message authentication codes, Digital signatures and digital 
        signature standard.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Cryptography and Network Security:</b> \n Data origin authentication and Data integrity, Key distribution, 
        Key management, Kerberos and X.509 authentication service, Certificate authority (CA) and public key infrastructure 
        (PKI), E-mail security, PGP and S/MIME, IP security (IPSec), Authentication header and ESP, Security associations, 
        key management, Oakley key determination protocol and ISAKMP, Web security considerations, secure socket layer (SSL) 
        and transport layer security (TLS), Secure electronic transactions (SET).
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommended books:</b>  
        \n\n
        
        
        •	Hand Book of Applied Cryptography - Menezes, Van Oorschot and Vanstone, CRC Press.
        \n\n
        
        •	Cryptography and Network Security, Principles and Practice - William Stallings, Printece Hall.
        \n\n
        
        •	Applied Cryptography - Bruce Schneier.
        \n\n
        
        •	Network Security - Kaufman, Perlman and Speciner.
        \n\n\n\n\n
	
        
        <b>Optional Courses</b>
        \n\n\n
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="ece_subject_code_and_name431">
        <b>ECE-420: Neural networks</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Preliminaries:</b> \n Neural computations, Classifiers, Approximators, Simple memory and restoration patterns, 
        Optimizing networks, Clustering and feature detecting networks, Development of artificial neural systems, 
        Future trends.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Fundamental concepts and models of artificial neural systems:</b> \n Biological neuron and their artificial models, 
        Models of artificial neural networks, McCulloch\’s Pitts neural model, Feed forward and feedback network, Neural 
        processing, Learning and adaptation, Neural network learning rules, Associative memory, BAM, MAM, FAM, Hopfield 
        networks, Self organizing networks, ART networks, Back propagation network.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Applications of neural algorithm and systems:</b> \n Character recognition, Control networks, Robot kinematics, 
        Expert systems.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommended books:</b>
        \n\n
        
        
        •	Introduction to Artificial Neural Systems by Jacek M. Zurada.
        \n\n
        
        •	Artificial Intelligence by E Rich, McGraw-Hill.
        \n\n
         
        •	Neural Networks, A Comprehensive Foundation, 2nd edition, by Simon Haykin, Prentice-Hall, 1999.
        \n\n
         
        •	Neural Networks: Algorithm, Applications, and Programming Techniques, J. Freeman and D. Skapura, 
        Addison-Wesley, 1992. 
        \n\n
         
        •	Adaptive Pattern Recognition and Neural Networks, Y-H Pao,  Addison-Wesley, 1989.
        \n\n\n\n\n
      
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    <string name="ece_subject_code_and_name432">
        <b>ECE-421: Digital Image Processing</b>
        \n\n
        
        <b>Fundamentals of Digital Image Processing:</b> \n Formation of an image, Imaging in the ultraviolet band, 
        Imaging in the visible band, Imaging in the microwave band, imaging in the radio band, 
        X-ray imaging, gamma ray imaging,  Components of an image processing system, Steps in DIP.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Digital Image:</b> \n Elements of visual perception – structure of the human eye, image formation in the eye.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Image Sensing and Acquisition:</b> \n Image sensor, Sensor strip, Sensor arrays, Image formation model.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Image Sampling and Quantization:</b> \n representing digital image, Basic relationship between pixels, 
        Image operation on pixel basis.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Image Enhancement in the Spatial Domain:</b> \n Gray level transformations, Histogram processing, 
        Enhancement using arithmetic logic operations, spatial filtering, Smoothing and sharpening spatial filters.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Image Enhance in the Frequency Domain:</b> \n Fourier transform, 1D and 2D FT, Properties of 2D FT, DFT, FFT; 
        Smoothing frequency domain filters, Sharpening frequency domain filters, Homomorphic filtering.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Image Restoration:</b> \n Model of image restoration process, Restoration in the presence of noise, 
        Estimation of the degradation function.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Color Image Processing:</b> \n Color models, Color Image processing, Color transformation, Color Image compression.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Wavelet and Multiresolution Processing:</b> \n Wavelet transforms.
        \n\n
        
        <b>Image Compression:</b> \n Image compression models.      
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Books:</b>
        \n\n
        
        
        •	Digital Image Processing by rafael C. Gonzalez and Richard E. Woods.
        \n\n
         
        •	Fundamentals of Digital Image Processing, Anil K. Jain, Prentice Hall, 1989.
        \n\n
         
        •	Digital Image Processing, Gonzalez and Woods, 2nd edition, Prentice Hall, 2001.
        \n\n
         
        •	Digital Image Processing, William K. Pratt, 3rd Edition, John Wiley, 2001.
        \n\n
        
        •	Digital Image Processing, Kenneth R. Castleman, Prentice Hall, 1996.
        \n\n\n\n\n
      
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="ece_subject_code_and_name433">
        <b>ECE-422: Multimedia Communication</b>
        \n\n
        
        Fundamentals, Introduction of international standards, Image coding: DCT/subband/VQ, Image coding: JPEG, Video 
        coding: ITU-T H.261, H.263, H.263 Version 2, Video coding: ISO MPEG-1, MPEG-2 , MPEG audio coding, ITU-T speech 
        coding: G.72x, MPEG-4 Video, Systems: ITU-T H.320, H.323, H.324, etc., Systems: MPEG-1, MPEG-2, MPEG-4 Systems, 
        Multipoint data conferencing: T.120, Networking issues: error resilience, network characteristics, Quality of 
        Service (QoS), Error resilience in video codecs: H.26x and MPEG, Multimedia over IP: Multicast, RTP/RTCP, 
        packetization, streaming, Multimedia over ATM, Multimedia over wireless/mobile networks.
        \n\n
        
        This course introduces technologies for multimedia communications. We will address how to efficiently represent 
        multimedia data, including video, image, and audio, and how to deliver them over a variety of networks. In the coding 
        aspect, state-of-the-art compression technologies will be presented. Emphasis will be given to a number of standards, 
        including H.26x, MPEG, and JPEG. In the networking aspect, special considerations for sending multimedia over ATM, 
        wireless, and IP networks, such as error resilience and quality of service, will be discussed. The H.32x series, 
        standards for audiovisual communication systems in various network environments, will be described. Current research 
        results in multimedia communications will be reviewed through student seminars in the last weeks of the course.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Books:</b>
        \n\n
        
        
        •	Multimedia Communication Systems: Techniques, Standards, and Networks by K. R. Rao.
        \n\n
        
        •	Introduction to Multimedia Systems (Communications, Networking, and Multimedia) by Sugata Mitra, Gaurav Bhatnagar.
        \n\n\n\n\n
     
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="ece_subject_code_and_name434">
        <b>ECE-423: High Speed Telecommunication</b>
        \n\n
        
        Networking terminology, Evolution of Internet, Networking basics and Internet protocol stack, TCP performance analysis, 
        TCP sequence number plots; Wireless networks – Wireless internet protocol and performance, Wireless TCP issues, 
        Multichannel MAC issues, Vegas and Multicast rate control, Video server broadcasting, IEEE 802.11 and 802.16; 
        ATM networks: ATM terminology, Cell networking, ATM signaling, ATM adaptation layer, ATM switching, ATM traffic 
        management; Network traffic management and modeling, Connection and admission control; High-speed LAN, Performance 
        modeling and estimation – Probability and stochastic process, queuing analysis, self similar traffic; Congestion and 
        traffic management, Internet routing, Quality of Service (QoS).
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommended books:</b>
        \n\n
        
        
        •	High-Speed Networks and Internets by William Stallings.
        \n\n
        
        •	Computer Networks and Systems – Queuing Theory and Performance Evaluation by Thomas G. Robertazzi.
        \n\n
        
        •	Principles of Wireless Networks by Kaveh Pahlavan and Prashant Krishnamurthy.
        \n\n\n\n\n
      
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    
    <string name="ece_subject_code_and_name435">
        <b>ECE-424: Radar and Navigation</b>
        \n\n
        
        Fundamentals, Basic principle, Radar development, Applications of radar, Power, Frequencies used in Radar, 
        Factors governing radar performance, Radar equation and range, Factors influencing maximum range, 
        Effect of noise, Types of Radar, CW &amp; FM radar; Doppler effect; MTI &amp; Pulse radar; Modulators, Multiple access 
        techniques, Receivers, Duplexers, Radar antenna, Tracking radar and radar systems.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommended Books:</b>    
        \n\n
        
        
        •	Microwave and Radar Engineering by M. Kulkarni
        \n\n
        
        •	Microwave Principle by J Reich
        \n\n
        
        •	Microwave Devices and Circuits by Y. Liao
        \n\n
           
        •	Introduction to Radar System by M. I. Skolnik.
        \n\n
        
        •	Microwave Engineering by David M. Pozar.
        \n\n\n\n\n
      
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    <string name="ece_subject_code_and_name436">
        <b>ECE-425: Radio and Television Engineering</b>
        \n\n
        
        Introduction to radio frequencies; Radio frequency amplifiers; Amplitude modulation and demodulation, 
        Angle modulation and demodulation, Frequency conversion and Mixing; Radio transmitter and receiver, 
        Superheterodyne receiver; Antennas.
        \n\n
        
        Television fundamentals; Analysis and synthesis of TV pictures, Composite video signal, TV picture tube; TV 
        cameras – types, construction and operating principle; Color signal; TV receivers; TV measurements; Colorimetry.
        \n\n
        
        Television transmission systems – PAL, SECAM and NTSC systems, TV signal transmission and distribution systems.
        \n\n
        
        Introduction to satellite TV receiver system – elements of the system and construction, creation and operation of the 
        system.
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
        
    </string>
    
    
    
    
    <string name="ece_subject_code_and_name437">
        <b>ECE-426: IC and VLSI Technology</b>
        \n\n
        
        IC processing, Wafer production and clean room principles, Silicon processing, Lithography, Oxidation, Doping 
        techniques, Thin film deposition, Etching, Back-end technology, Layer processes used in IC fabrication, 
        Designing a fabrication process to specifically meet physical and electrical specifications for the final chip, 
        Integrating the fabrication steps, IC packaging, Yields in IC processing, Microsystem products, Microfabrication 
        process, nanotechnology.
        \n\n
        
        CMOS VLSI design process and focuses on design at the circuit and physical levels, Terminologies and trends in 
        VLSI design. MOS transistor theory, CMOS processing technology, resistance and capacitance estimation, 
        CMOS design styles, NMOS and CMOS inverters, dc, transient and tranfer characteristics. Designing and testing 
        basic logic gates and other VLSi building blocks such as adders, multipliers, counters, barrel shifters, etc. 
        using computer aided design tools and hardware in the laboratory.
        \n\n\n
        
        <b>Recommended books:</b>
        \n\n
        
        
        •	Silicon VLSI Technology: Fundamentals, Practice, and Modeling by James D. Plummer, Michael D. Deal, Peter B. 
        Griffin.
        \n\n
        
        •	Solid State Electronic Devices, Fifth Edition, Ben Streetman, Sanyay Banerjee, Prentice Hall, 2000.
        \n\n
         
        •	Silicon VLSI Technology, James D. Plummer, Michael D. Deal, Peter B. Griffin, Prentice Hall, 2000.
        \n\n
         
        •	Principles of CMOS VLSI Design, Neil H. E. Weste and Kamran Eshraghian, Addison Wesley.
        \n\n
        
        •	Analysis and Design of Digital Integrated Circuits, Third Edition, David A. Hodges, Horace G. Jackson, and Resve 
        A. Saleh, McGraw-Hill, 2004.
        \n\n\n\n\n
        

    </string>
    
    
    
    <string name="ece_subject_code_and_name438">
        <b>ECE-439: Project Report and Project Defense</b>
        \n\n
        
        The project work must be started in the 7th semester of the 4th year and it must be completed by the end of 8th 
        semester. The project work must be carried out under the supervision of a teacher. Group projects may be allowed but a 
        group must not consist of more than two students. A project report will be submitted after the completion of the 
        project work. A panel of examiners appointed by the National University will conduct the project defense and also 
        evaluate the project report. The evaluation of project work carrying 200 marks is as follows:
        \n\n
        
        a. Project Report	100 marks.
        \n
        
        b. Project Defense	100 marks.
        \n\n\n\n\n
        
        
    </string>
</resources>